♪ Just one touch tell me who you are ♪
♪ here beneath the skies of Astar ♪
♪ Spoken with no sound ♪
♪ foreign lands abound ♪
♪ wandering skies ♪
♪ for the voice that I lost... ♪
♪ though soon your land I view ♪
♪ above ♪
♪ (Just one touch from me) ♪
♪ Fly true, touch and breakthrough ♪
♪ brave new worlds tale ♪
♪ my voice unveiled. ♪
♪ Set sail... But unto the skies ♪
♪ and we will leave the world behind. ♪
♪ Sometimes our minds change ♪
♪ sometimes it feels strange ♪
♪ when you're alone above. ♪
♪ Land that is fleeting... ♪
♪ (Just one touch from me) ♪
♪ Fly true, touch and breakthrough ♪
♪ brave new worlds tale ♪
♪ my voice unveiled. ♪
♪ Set sail... But unto the skies ♪
♪ and we will leave the world behind. ♪
♪ One touch last forever ♪
♪ Fly true, touch and breakthrough ♪
♪ brave new worlds tale ♪
♪ my voice unveiled. ♪
♪ Set sail... But unto the skies ♪
♪ Let's leave, let's leave, ♪
♪ let's leave the world behind ♪
♪ Just one touch tell me who you are ♪
♪ Here beneath the skies of Astar ♪