[Birds chirping]
[Roar in a distance]
♪ Light so Bright, Light so Pure ♪
♪ Keepers of the Light, Answer me True ♪
♪ Light so Bright, so Pure, Light so True ♪
♪ I give myself to you ♪
Keep on moving, girl.
One step after another.
There must be a way out of this thicket.
Hello? Is there somebody out there?
Oh shit! No! No! No!..
No!
Oh no, not the fire!
Please! Gods of the Holy Mountain!
Don't let it end this way!
No! No!
[Screams]
Get off! Get off!
[More screams and whacks]
Aaaaah!
[Snapjaw howls]
[Dramatic music]
Help! Help! Somebody!
- Who's there?! What in the light's name
is going on?
I'm over here! Help me! Please!
Hey you filthy beast!
Get the hell out of here
or I'll burn your eyes out with my light!
Yes, I'm talking to you!
RAAAARGH!
No! Get off! Get away!
Go back to where you came from! Get out!
And you! Stupid rats! Get out! Get out!
That'll teach 'em!
Hey… are you okay?
[Sobbing]
Phew. That was a close call.
Even a child knows
that a simple torch won't keep
the night's creatures away!
What on earth were you doing out here
without a proper light?
They tried to kill me! But I ran away!
Don't worry. You're safe now.
My light will keep us safe.
No, you don't understand!
Look, I know how getting lost in the woods
alone can mess with your head.
My village is not far
away. Can you walk?
I'm sure everything will be better
once you've had a warm meal.
No! I can't come with you!
Tomorrow is the festival of lights!
What are you going to tell the Keepers
when they see me?
The festival of lights is a celebration of love!
What objections could the Keepers
possibly have against giving shelter
to someone who is lost?
More than you can possibly imagine.
No, I can't come with you.
You saved my life, you deserve better
than the trouble I'll cause you.
I've got to go. Farewell… and thank you…
[Howling in the distance]
Don't be silly, look at yourself.
I'm not letting you die out here.
Festival night should be
the best night of the year, not your worst.
You'll be safe at my house, I promise.
My name is Riversong. What's your name?
Frostwind.
Pleased to meet you, Frostwind.
Here, take my hand.
There's a warm fire waiting for us.
Thank you. Really. Thank you.
You're welcome. This way.
[Applause]
It was the year 385
after the Awakening.
The village of Ferndale lay cozily nestled
in the valley of the Serpent River
where the winds sweeping
down from the Holy Mountain
tingled with the scent of pine trees
and the streets were filled
with the sounds of playing children
and oxen carts on cobblestone.
As with every other village,
each household
needed to have its own holy light.
These were nothing like ordinary lanterns.
They were gifts from the gods.
They shone bright as fire, yet without
flame, and nothing could extinguish them.
But the most important thing was that,
while even the strongest walls and gates
could not keep the dark creatures away
that came from the forest in the night
the holy light could.
A home without a light would not
have been a safe place to live
and leaving the village without one
at night would have been plain suicide.
Over the course of months, however, even
a holy light would eventually begin to dim.
And so, once every year
at the time of the summer solstice
farmers, millers, blacksmiths, bakers,
carpenters, spinsters, weavers, cobblers
everyone in the village
who could afford to do so
would lay down their work for a day
and celebrate The Festival of Lights.
Families would gather in their homes
and selebrate each other’s
company with lots of mulled
wine, mince pie, and
other festive specialties.
Parents would give their children
homemade presents
and in the evening the village priests
would walk from door to door
giving everyone their blessing,
and renew the lights in every house.
For the villagers, this was
the happiest day of the year
as the return of light to their home
reminded them
that the gods and their earthly servants
would always be there
to love and protect them.
For they were the Keepers of the Light.
[Music: "Keepers of the Light" by Fox Amoore]
♪ In a world forsaken by time ♪
♪ Is a light that always shall shine ♪
♪ It flows from out of your breath ♪
♪ Putting all the darkness to death ♪
♪ A torch in the dark is my own will ♪
♪ To light this place and let the white fill ♪
♪ Come forth now, oh so bright ♪
♪ Come with me and show your might ♪
♪ So the keepers can see ♪
♪ The keepers can feel me rise ♪
♪ Then shine ♪
♪ Keepers of the light ♪
♪ Shine! ♪
♪ Oh, keepers of the light ♪
♪ Shine your will so bright ♪
♪ Keepers of the light ♪
The keepers are coming,
the keepers are coming!
Quick, make sure you're home when
they come, or you won't get your presents!
Do you know what you are going to get?
I want a rocking horse!
I'm going to get my own hunting knife!
How do you know?
I just know. And I also know
what you are going to get!
Oh tell me!
No! I know you're a telltale!
I'm not, I won't, I swear!
Not even mum! Come on!
And what's in it for me?
Snowbell! Sunchaser! Get your little
fuzzy behinds over here right now!
I'm coming, mommy!
Wait for me!
Mom? Mom… where are you…?
MOM?
What… what the hell? Where am I?
Hello? HELLO?
Ah, you're awake!
I was beginning to worry about you.
Riversong?
Yes, it's me!
Welcome to my humble home!
Here, I made you some tea.
Thank you, but... How long was I asleep?
Umm... Pretty much the whole day.
Which is good.
How are you holding up?
Everything still hurts.
Yeah, I'm not surprised.
What were you doing out there?
I was running away.
From what? Or... whom?
The Keepers at Coldlake.
I was preparing dinner with my mom
when they suddenly burst into our house,
armed to their teeth, telling us
we're all arrested.
My mother punched the first one
right in the face
yelling at me to run for my life.
They struck her down with their swords.
I managed to slip past them,
and ran as fast as I could.
I don't know what happened to my mother.
I think she's...
dead.
They're after you because you have
the dark plague, right?
How do you know?
You hid it well. The scarf covering
the patch of missing fur
on your neck, the plague-smell masked with
lilacs and jasmine - all well done, but
the signs are obvious if you know
what to look for.
Wow! You knew it all along?
And you still saved me
and took me to your home? Why?
If they find out you are hiding a plague bearer...
I am a healer. It's what I do.
I swore an oath to help people in need.
If the Keepers want me to leave you to die,
they will have to kill me first.
Be careful what you wish for.
Don't worry. Brother Strongarm spends
most of his time getting high on incense
and Brother Greystone is an old geezer
who can barely remember his own birthday.
They couldn't hurt a fly. We're going to
wrap you up in a blanket
put some powder on your nose,
and tell them I'm treating you for a cold.
Thank you.
Don't think anything of it. Those cruel
things that happened to you and your mother…
Helping ease the pain
is the least I can do.
Where was your father when
all this happened?
Let's just say, he lives far, far away…
And he won't be back any time soon.
I'm sorry. What happened?
He had to leave us
when I was still a little girl
and the only thing he left behind was…
The pendant!
I was wearing a pendant! Where is it?
Relax, relax, it's right here.
On the table.
I took it off of you, so you
wouldn't strangle yourself.
Ahh, thank you!
It's the only thing left to
remind me of him.
He told me to hold on to it in bad times.
Did he tell you what the symbol
in the front means?
No. Why?
Because I've seen it before,
at a friend's place.
He's sort of an expert on strange things,
and I'm dying to ask him
what he might know about it.
You'll have to tell me full story
sometime. But not now, of course.
The Keepers are coming!
It's time to get you dressed up.
Dear community, citizens, and friends.
We have once again come together
to celebrate the beginning of a new year
and praise the gods of the holy mountain.
[Everyone] "As it was, and always will be!"
Once more we shall accept
the trial laid upon us
and never falter in our fight against
the evil that hides in the darkness
and those who have been infested by it!
[Everyone] "As it was, and always will be!"
Once more we shall open our doors
and our hearts
and let new light be brought into our homes
so it may always shine upon us.
[Everyone] "As it was, and always will be!"
This year, a very special blessing
and honor has been bestowed upon us.
Brother Greystone and I are getting
old and frail
and walking from home to home is a burden
that becomes harder and harder for us.
To that end, Great Overseer Ironwill
from the bishopric of Coldlake
has decided to favor our humble parish
with his presence.
He will lead this year's renewal ceremony
for which we thank him
from the bottom of our hearts.
Now let the ceremonies begin!
Wait!
Ironwill?
From Coldlake?
No! He knows me! He knows everyone!
Damn! That was not part of my plan.
If he sees me, we're both done for!
Don't panic. We're going to improvise.
We just have to convince them that
you have a terrible case of…
the flu. Yes. The flu.
Sneeze and cough a lot!
That will keep them from
taking a close look at you.
What if it doesn't work?
Then you run.
There's a window in the back of the house.
But it will work, I'm sure.
Pull your hat down, here they come.
We are coming to bring the light.
It's a great honor to welcome you to
my home, Great Overseer Ironwill.
Our light is right here.
A very nice home you have.
What is your profession, if I may ask?
I'm a healer.
Oh, interesting.
We don't have any of those in Coldlake.
Not any more. The last one we had
was convicted of witchcraft,
and we had to burn him at the stake
not a pretty sight.
Um... Yeah.
I errr...
Should I worry maybe?
But I guess not.
Don't worry, it's just Riversong.
Collecting herbs and mixing ointments
is his passion
and he has never done anything
against the will of the great gods.
And? Who's that?
Oh, just a patient. Don't get too close
it's very contagious!
You don't want to spread the flu
all over the village, would you?
Of course not. Brother Strongarm
finish quickly so we can get out of here.
Yes, hmmm..
I hereby christen this home with
the divine light of the holy mountain
May it protect you and your home
from all evil.
As it was, and always will be.
Thank you, keepers of the light,
for giving me your gift.
I shall always be grateful to you
and the great gods.
Eeeew! Hurry up, Strongarm!
I may blindly trust the great gods,
but I'd rather not tempt them.
Yes. Umm... Have a good evening,
Riversong!
And my best wishes for your patient.
Ah, thank you. And my best wishes
for you as well.
Wait a minute.
*sniff*
What's that?
Lilacs and Jasmine?
Yeah... Umm...
What kind of flu medicine is that?
That - that's just my new herbal tea.
Keeps away the cold… And it's great
if you have sweaty paws.
Like me, huh. See?
That's not part of any flu medicine
that I ever heard about.
And I could swear I've smelled this before…
Who's the patient of yours again?
Um, no one in particular.
Just a friend from the village.
She's not with her family?
-On festival night?
-Well...
I want to see her!
No, no-no-no-no, that's not a good idea!
That's very bad idea actually!
What if you catch the flu?
That's up to the gods!
Now get out of my way.
I think I remember where
I caught that scent before.
Frostwind!
NO!
RUN!
AAAAAAAARGH!
Guard! She's out the window! Go get her!
This man has been concealing a person
carrying the dark plague!
Dark plague is one of the biggest threats
to our civilization!
It's the law of the great gods
of the holy mountain
that those who carry it must be eliminated
and those who help the infected
shall be tried with no mercy!
As it was, and always will be.
Great Overseer, she escaped
into the darkness.
Shall we lock down the gates?
I don't think that will stop her.
The walls of this lousy place have cracks
the size of pigrats
and finding her outside in the dark
is hopeless.
She was lucky to survive the night once
she won't be so lucky a second time.
Let the night take her.
[GROAN]
I want him on a trial by tomorrow
and I want everyone in the village to see
what happens to witchers who bring
the dark plague into our midst.
You will see where this gets you.
The liege lord is an old friend
of my family.
He knows I'm not a witcher.
He would never sentence me…
Never!
We'll see… witcher.
We'll see.
[applause]
Come on, Rob…
Don't - don't give up.
There's always hope.
You're almost - almost there.
Father above, we pray and plead
for your most blessed
Holy mercy.
We know, as fallen humans,
we do not deserve it
yet we still have..
..reverent spirit by which we can live
a more obedient life..
..through your word..
..we pray this...
..in the name of your blessed son,
Jesus Christ..
..Amen
Wait. What?
What's that?
Some... Some sort of military base?
It's... not... not on the map
but… there's - there's signs of life
all over the place!
Hello! Hello?
Is - is anybody there?
This is Robert Henson, I'm the last
survivor of my - of my group!
Can you - can you hear me? Please!
I - I need your help!
Answer me, please!
I'm - I'm a friend!
If there's anybody in there, please,
open the airlock!
I know you're in there!
I can see your lights are on!
Please! I'll do anything for you, anything!
I swear! Please let me in!
Go away. This is the new age.
Your kind no longer rules this place.
My… my kind?
What do you mean? I'm a survivor!
Just like you!
We're all of the same kind… aren't we?
I said, go away. This is our final warning.
But I have nowhere to go.
And I haven't had anything to drink
for days.
I need water, or I'm going to die!
Come on! Let me in, you bastards!
LET ME IN! PLEASE!
The door! It opens! Thank you!
Whoever you are, thank you!
Who are you? WHAT ARE YOU?
NO! GET AWAY FROM ME!
NOOOO! AAAAAAAARRGHT!
One more time: This is the new age.
Your kind no longer rules this place.
Good morning gentlemen.
It's my honor and my privilege to announce
that his serene highness
Liege Lord Eldercrown of the one…
or the other…
Oh what the hell am I even doing here?
My head is killing me!
Chippy? Chippytooth? Is that you?
Yes, I'm afraid so.
You know, some idiot got himself caught
with a plague bearer
and that smug bastard from Coldlake thought
'Hey, let's just cancel everybody's
holidays and have a lovely trial
while everyone's still hung over!'
Yeah. Well, sorry for being that idiot,
I guess.
Oh, you will be sorry, believe me.
You picked a bad day for pulling
that kind of shenanigans.
Eldercrown would have given you a slap on
the wrist and sent you home without dessert
but Ironwill?
That guy is dead serious.
Damn!
Ooh, that headache is killing me.
How long did you stay up last night?
Too long.
We sent the kids to bed at eleven, then
Nightstar and his wife came over, and
we ended up killing at least, I think,
half a dozen bottles…
When you get home, you should
get some dandelion, mugwort and gentian
and let it simmer on the stove for a while.
It won't make up for the sleep you lost,
but it will at least help clear your head.
Thanks. The old witcher,
always on duty, right?
Healer, Chippy. Healer.
Whatever you call it, you're not making
my job any easier.
I mean, we've known each other
for how long?
And now I'm the one who has to send you
up to the scaffold in the keepers' name.
The verdict hasn't been spoken yet.
And you don't have to do this, you know…
I am a soldier of the guard.
If I refuse to obey the Lord's orders,
I will be the next one
watching his own trial from that cage.
And unlike you, I have a wife and kids.
There is nothing I can do for you, River.
I'm sorry.
It's all right, Chippy.
Oh, here we go.
GENTLEMEN, PLEASE…
Gentlemen, please stand for the high court:
Brother Strongarm, chronicler of Ferndale.
His serene highness Lord Eldercrown
of Ferndale.
And Great Overseer Ironwill of Coldlake.
Are you freaking crazy?
Out… out… out with you! Out! Out!
Out!
And stay outside!
The High Court of Ferndale
is now in session.
Thank you. Will everybody please be seated.
I am calling the case of the People of
Ferndale against Healer Riversong.
Witcher Riversong!
Excuse me, Overseer, but would you mind
if we go with the protocol?
Certainly.
Then please make your opening statement.
Your Honor. The accused has been charged
with the crime of performing witchcraft,
desecration of the holy sacrament
of the festival of light, and giving
shelter to a bearer of the dark plague.
Only the gods of the holy mountain
know where the plague bearer is now.
Instead of turning her in,
witcher Riversong decided
to shelter and foster her
releasing her evil darkness
upon the entire town of Ferndale!
I saw it with my own eyes,
and Brother Strongarm can testify
that the accused is guilty as charged!
Brother Strongarm, is Overseer Ironwill
correct?
Yes, my Lord, I too,
saw it with my own eyes.
I did not want to believe it,
but it is the truth.
The divine laws know only one punishment
for this crime.
Hey! Hey, wait a minute!
Am I not allowed to defend myself?
- What kind of trial is this?
- Silence, Witcher!
Overseer Ironwill, Riversong is correct.
We ought to hear his side of the case
as well.
All right, let the witcher talk.
I'm a healer, not a witcher!
My desire is to help, not to destroy!
I never had any bad intentions,
that's completely absurd!
I was on my way home from collecting herbs
when I found her.
She was getting attacked by a snapjaw
and a dozen pigrats
and she didn't have a light with her.
She could no longer defend herself.
I had to help, or she would have died!
But you knew she had the plague
and that the plague can not be cured.
Of course, my Lord.
But I also know that the whole scare about
how contagious the plague is
is nothing but a myth!
I've seen more sick people than any of you
and I've seen my share of
contagious diseases
and the dark plague is not one of them.
And even if it can not be cured
many people don't even show symptoms
for many years
and why shouldn't they be allowed to live
a decent life until then?
If it is not infectious,
then why is it so common?
I … I don't know. But look at me.
If it were so bad, shouldn't I
have it by now?
Witchcraft!
Overseer, please.
Why are we even listening to this nonsense?
The law is the law.
Aiding the plague-infected is a crime
against life itself
and must be punished as such!
-Bullshit!
-Riversong!
Show some respect, you're in a court
of law!
A fine law you have that commands you
to kill your own people.
All right, gentlemen,
this is leading nowhere.
Riversong has been a valuable member of
our community for many years.
He was always there to help the sick -
be they nobles, clerics or beggars.
I see no ill will in what he did.
The death penalty would be excessive.
By virtue of the powers bestowed upon me
as the Liege Lord of Ferndale
I hereby decide to let mercy prevail and-
Mercy?
Are the gods of the holy mountain
not merciful enough for you?
What?
Are you implying that the eternal gods
whose mercy is endless
do not look kindly enough upon us
that you put yourself above their laws?
With all due respect, Overseer Ironwill
I appreciate your spiritual guidance,
but I am the legitimate ruler of this town
and I am the one who speaks justice,
and not you.
You are of course right.
So I take it that next year,
you would rather not have us
come to your town for the festival.
And that you would rather like to see the
dark creatures haunt the streets at night
feeding on the innocent
the children
when the lights begin to dim.
I'm sure keeping your town safe will not
pose a challenge
to a magnificent ruler like you,
my serene Lord Eldercrown.
I… I'm sorry, Overseer Ironwill.
I concur.
This crime calls for a bold example
of justice
so that others shall not follow
the witcher's evil path.
I hereby condemn you, Riversong of Ferndale
to be hanged at dusk.
This is an outrage!
A just decision, my Lord.
Shut up and get out of my town hall.
OUT!
Witcher. As I said.
I am so disappointed in you, son!
One day, you will pay for this! I promise!
YOU WILL PAY FOR THIS!
And - and what now, my Lord?
Now we do what needs to be done.
My Lord, may I request to be relieved
of my duties for today?
River and I have known each other
for years.
Please don't make me do this.
Do I look like I am enjoying this?
But still I am doing my duty
And I expect you to do the same.
Is there anything I can get you
for your hangover?
You know, I was planning to see the healer
but I guess that has been taken care of…
Oh, don't push it.
I'll let my servant bring you some water.
And now please excuse me.
River?
Just leave me alone, alright?
Okay.
It's me, Frostwind.
Up here. The window.
Frostwind! I thought you ran away!
How long have you been up there?
Long enough to see your trial.
We need to get you out of there.
I could smash the glass, but if the rat
wakes up before I get to him
we're both done for.
I have a better idea. Step away from
the window.
Chippytooth! Hey!
Hey, you! Chippy! Wake up! HEY!
Who… what… where? Oh!
Oh, it's you...
Chippy! What the hell are you doing?
You need to stay awake,
or the Lord's going to skin you
and use your hide as a throw rug!
I know, I know. If only I wasn't
so damn tired…
Yeah, it's really stuffy in here.
You should open a window and let some
fresh air in, I'm sure that'll help.
Yeah, that makes sense. Let's try that.
Fresh air! I feel so much better now!
That hurt!
And holy crap, this guy smells
like a brewery!
I...
I can't believe you came back for me!
Thank you!
I owed you. But let's not
start celebrating yet…
We still need to figure out
where to go from here.
Do you remember the friend
I told you about yesterday?
The strange one?
Yeah! He lives in a shed
near Serpent River.
People fear him because he somehow
manages to survive in the woods
without a holy light.
He doesn't give a damn about the Keepers
and their power.
He's our only option for a night
outside the village, unless
unless you want to room with the
pigrats again.
No, thank you, I've had my fill of
snappy-bitey forest critters for this week.
All right! Then let's get the hell out
of here. Follow me.
[applause]
Frosty! Hey, Frostwind.
Wake up, little one!
But I don't want to wake up.
It's still dark outside.
I know, but daddy needs to tell
you something very important.
What is it? Did something happen?
Yes. Yes, my dear. Daddy has to leave.
And I'm afraid I won't
be back for a long time.
You mean, like, for a week?
No.
-A month?
-No.
-A year?
More than a year?
Why? Is it because of me?
I always kept my secret, I
never told anyone, I swear!
Not at all.
It's because I've been doing a good job.
The high overseer has asked me to
become a head researcher at the stronghold.
Inside the holy mountain? Wow!
That's awesome! I
want to know all about it!
You have to write me a letter every day!
I wish I could. But I can't.
The keepers would read them.
And then bad things would happen.
How bad?
Do you remember our little
secret? It's not a game any more.
I know I never told you this, but…
If anyone finds out who you
really are, the Keepers will kill you.
And mother. And possibly me, too.
No! What?
No! Please don't leave!
You must stay here and
protect us, pleaaasse don't go!
Don't be afraid little one.
You're a strong girl
and I know you can keep a secret.
And maybe I won't be able to write you,
but mother is still
one of the best tailors in town.
I can still send you clothes to repair,
and who knows, maybe I'll forget …
things .. in my pockets.
Like… Like sweets?
Yes. How did you know?
But don't eat them all. Not at once.
I want you to eat one every week.
Not more, not less.
Exactly one. And no other sweets.
Just those I send you. Do you understand?
Yes. But why?
Because… well… because…
sweets are bad for your teeth.
Okay.
And there's another thing. I want to
give you something before I leave. Here.
Wow! Thank you dad, this is beautiful!
I want you to wear
this pendant all the time.
Whatever happens, never take it off.
Not even when I'm taking a bath?
Not even then. Cherish it like life itself
because one day, it might save yours.
How so?
You will have to trust me on that.
One day, you will understand all this.
But for now, the less you know, the better.
I promise, I will be watching
over you from the holy mountain.
And I have a dream that one day
all this won't be necessary any more.
Who knows. Maybe that dream will come true
and we'll see each other again.
Now come here, and give daddy
a hug. It's time to say goodbye.
I love you, dad. Please don't go.
I love you too. But I have - I have to go.
Farewell my little one.
Farewell.
I see daylight! Finally! I'll race you!
HEY! Be careful!
Damn… just a few years ago
I used to outrun the fastest
boys of town. Now look at me.
I think you're doing pretty well!
Fiddlesticks! I'm getting worse
every day and you know it.
Well, you still keep on going.
You have a strong will to live!
It's really just a strong desire to
get out of dark, gloomy caves fast.
Don't you belittle my caves!
It's a treasure house of
useful herbs and mushrooms!
So, your mysterious
friend… is he a healer, too?
Yes and no. He...
is more of a… substance researcher.
Like, cave mushrooms?
Yeah, you gotta be careful with those.
Too much of them, and they willl cause
a total loss of all basic motor functions.
The mind recoils in horror, unable
to communicate with the body.
You can actually watch yourself
behaving in terrible, terrible ways
but you can't control it. Nasty stuff!
Wait! *sniff* *sniff*
Do you smell that too?
Smoke! Smoke! By the gods!
Oh no! The cabin! Burned to the ground!
Is this where he used to live?
Yeah! Poor Bottlebrush!
Bottlebrush?
Yeah! This was his
house, and now it's all gone!
His name is… Bottlebrush?
Yeah, for the mountain's sake, it is.
Well, that explains why he's hiding.
Yes, and now he's possibly
dead, what a great opportunity
to make some more fun of him!
I'm sorry.
I want to know what happened.
Maybe we can find something in the ashes.
Whoever did this was very
thorough. There's almost nothing left.
Yes. And I smell... I smell oil.
It's all over the place.
This wasn't an accident. Have you found…
have you found a body?
No, nothing.
Then let's cross our claws
that he managed to get away.
I guess that means our stay for
the night has been canceled, huh?
Yeah. We're stuck. Dear gods.
Oh, look what I found!
What... What is it?
It's a strange drawing showing
some strange… creature.
[laughter, applause]
Oh! Yeah, that's typical for old Brushie.
The strange creature is called a "human".
Brushie's home used
to be full of stuff like that.
A human! My mom used to
tell me fairy tales about them.
When I was little, I really
believed they existed!
Somewhere in the woods, hunting us kids
Brushie was totally obsessed with humans.
He spent his whole life digging through
old ruins, looking for artifacts.
The Keepers have declared the ruins a
holy site, but that never concerned him.
He ended up with quite a
collection - tools, statues, art
lots of mysterious things.
He reminds me a lot of my father.
I was too young to really
understand what he was doing, but
I think he was also
searching for something.
He would often disappear
into the forest for hours
and return with boxes
full of strange things …
How did he manage to
get around the keepers?
He… he is one of them.
WHAT?
Yes. I am the daughter of
Silverstreak the Dressmaker
and Brother Fireheart of Pinecrest,
former High Overseer of Coldlake.
A bastard. Half Keeper, half mundane.
Wow!
Your mother broke a Keeper's bloodline?
She could as well have
set the temple on fire.
Of course they never told anyone about it.
Officially I'm an orphan.
As long as father was
still living in Coldlake
he would come to our house,
pretending to do business with my mom.
When he was ordered back
to the holy mountain one day
he promised to do everything
he could to protect us
but we knew we'd most
likely never see him again.
Oh! I think - I think I've found something.
Frostwind, show me your
pendant again, please.
Here! Why?
Because I knew I had seen it before!
This... This little sign
used to hang above the door.
Maybe it's like a secret guild symbol
and your father wanted you to seek out others
who wear this sign if you're in trouble?
Maybe… maybe not…
Hmmmrmmmm! Hrrrm! Hmmm
mmm mm mmm mm hrmmpfhmphmph!
Eh...
Who are you? What do you want?
Hmmmrmmmm! Hrrrm! Hmmm
mmm mm mmm mm hrmmpfhmphmph!
Eh, sorry, but eh… I don't understand you…
Hrmrmrmtmmtmtmmtmtmmm!
Awww! Isn't he adorable?
Look at that little cape
and a little itsy-bitsy knife!
Maybe he's lost, and wants
to find his way back to his mommy?
I don't think so.
You've something that
we want. Give it to me.
Hmmhmmhmmhmmhmm hmmhmm hmm!
I know that's what you said
and if you weren't too stupid
to wear your scarf properly
maybe they could understand you, too!
Hrrrrrmph!
So...
Now, milady, show me your necklace.
Here… take it...
You are carrying the sign.
But that alone is not enough.
You said your father, Brother
Fireheart of Pinecrest, gave this to you.
Prove it.
"Light so Bright, Light so Pure."
Now you.
Oh, it's a code!
No, that's not a code.
It's a song that mother taught me.
"Light so Bright, Light so Pure.
Keepers of the Light, Answer me True!"
Thank you, but I think I've heard enough.
Bottlebrush! You're alive!
Of course I am.
Please welcome our friends: Frostwind
of Coldlake, and Riversong of Ferndale.
May I introduce myself?
I am Longleaf of Camp Freedom.
I'm sorry I had to scare you like
that, but we had to make sure that you are
well, who you say you are.
Damn the gods, I thought
this thing would suffocate me!
Hi, I'm Bitternut! Nice to meet you!
Brushie, old chap, what on
earth happened to your house?
Burned down by the Keepers.
They've been very active lately,
combing through the woods
sending new overseers to all the villages,
burning witches at the stake.
Yeah
But I got a warning from our
scouts and got away in time.
Your scouts?
Your father didn't tell you
what the symbol means, right?
It's the tree of knowledge.
The secret sign of the Rebel Underground.
The Keepers' reign is a tyranny,
and someone needs to stop them.
That someone… is us!
Your father has been one
of our biggest supporters.
All in secrecy, of course.
That makes you, my
lady, a very welcome guest.
Brushie, you never told me!
You didn't have to know.
But it's getting dark and I'm sure you both
need a good meal and a warm place to sleep.
Please come on, follow me, I will lead
you the way to Camp Freedom.
Is that like, your secret base?
Much more than that, my dear. Much more.
Once there, I promise you
two will have a lot of catching up to do.
Let's go!
This way!
I don't believe all this.
I don't believe all this!
[applause]
Welcome to Camp Freedom!
Huh
Wow!
This is a lot bigger than I expected!
And look at all these
lights! What magic is that?
Electricity! Science, not magic!
You will learn all about it, I promise.
But first, let me introduce you.
HEAR HEAR! We have a
very special guest today!
Please all welcome Frostwind of Coldlake,
daughter of Brother Fireheart, our savior!
[everyone cheering]
[everyone] -Long live Fireheart! Long live Fireheart!
-Hi everybody
Nice to meet you!
Why are they all cheering?
Without your father, we'd
all still be sitting in the dark
begging some priest for pieces of radioactive
rock to protect us from the pigrats.
Uh wait… isn't Fireheart a keeper himself?
Yes, and he's been secretly
supplying us with everything we need
right from inside the Keepers' stronghold.
And more than that.
He enlightened us with the
ancient knowledge of our creators.
All this because he fell in love with a
commoner who opened his eyes to the truth.
You know him? Where is he now?
Oh yes, I've met him many times.
He still works inside the holy mountain
helping maintain and
operate the ancient machinery.
Attention, everybody, please stand back
and don't touch any metal parts!
Activate in 3…
2…
1…
-Wow!
-Yes!
IT'S ALIVE! IT'S ALIIIIIVEEEEE!
MUHAHAHAHA!
What?
What is that thing?!
Sparky… of all the useful
artifacts still in storage
you choose to repair the
fucking soda machine? Seriously?
Oh, forgive me! I only
got four transformers
the rod charging stations, the
three extra field generators and
the electric fence back online today.
Can't I do something
just for fun after hours?
Here, that'll help you pull
that stick out of your ass.
Are you kidding me? This
stuff is at least 500 years old.
Well, according to the label
it has no natural ingredients
and twice the half-life of plutonium.
What could possibly go wrong? Cheers!
[laughter, applause]
Ah! The crowning achievement
of human civilization!
COME ON EVERYBODY, THE
DRINKS ARE ON THE HOUSE TONIGHT!
[everyone cheering]
[upbeat music starts playing]
[everyone] Awwwwwwwww!
God damn! Come on you rusty piece of junk!
[everyone cheering again]
But...
WHAT THE HELL IS GOING ON HERE?
*gasp* It's Stormrunner!
What? Who?
Who?
The leader of the rebellion!
Just do as everyone else does!
Do you think this is a game? Do I
have to remind you why we are all here?
People are suffering and dying every day
because they are denied the
knowledge of their true heritage
by some 'god' inside the holy mountain!
We will end the Keepers' reign!
Teach the people the ancient knowledge
of our creators that they have been denied
and bring enlightenment to the world!
[everyone] Yeeeah!
I have great news, everyone!
Brother Fireheart has gained
control of the stronghold's power grid.
An electrical fire is going to cause
a complete outage of the north wing
shutting down all locks,
defenses and security systems.
This is our chance to
march into their sanctuary
take control of their 'god machine'.
Team Alpha will leave in three hours.
That means every trained fighter.
Only a skeleton crew will stay at the base.
This is our day, brothers and sisters!
[everyone] Yeeeah!
Well... Looks like this is it!
The stronghold is a day away
so by about this time tomorrow
the dark ages will finally be over.
And what are we going…
What's wrong with her?
Ah, she's got the dark plague,
and she's getting weaker and weaker.
The dark plague you say! At
her age? Now that's unusual.
Yes. It looks like she only
caught it a few weeks ago.
Something doesn't make sense here.
You don't 'catch' the dark plague.
It's a genetic predisposition.
A… genetic… what?
It means, that you're either
born with it, or you are not.
I have no explanation.
All I know is that she didn't show
any symptoms until a few days ago.
I need to tell you something.
That pendant she's wearing
the tree of knowledge, do you
know why her father gave it to her?
I have no idea.
The amulet was Fireheart's failsafe.
He didn't want to reveal
Frostwind's identity to anyone.
So he gave her the
pendant and a secret phrase
so she could identify herself in
case he could no longer care for her.
Even I didn't know who she was
until you two showed up at my house.
Fireheart must really love his daughter…
He does. But this is also terrifying
This was supposed to be the
last resort if everything else fails.
Something isn't right here.
I'll make sure to keep that in mind, but...
anyway, we need to get her
to a place where she can rest.
Could you please take
care of her for a moment?
I have an idea.
Frosty? Hey, Frosty! Wake up, come on!
Do you hear me?
River? What happened?
Here, I've got something to drink for you.
Easy, Frosty, Easy. Come
on, we need to get to
get you and... you can
get some rest, okay?
Do you think you can walk?
Here, I'll help you.
You can use that tent by the oak tree.
Okay, great.
-Boss?
-Hm?
I know you… what's wrong?
I don't know...
Something … I can't put my paw on it.
Something isn't right.
But Team Alpha is on its way now
and there's nothing we can do -
except wait, and hope.
[applause]
Frosty?
Yes?
It's freezing, isn't it?
Yes. It's a starry night.
Beautiful. But cold.
Would you... Would you mind if I
come over to your side?
-Oh! Well…
-Only if you want! Only if you want.
No, no, it's fine.
I feel lonely, too.
Come over here kittycat,
this blanket has space for two.
On my way!
Feeling better now?
Much better… mrrrr… you're so cuddly…
[purring]
Oh my god! You can purr! That is so cute!
Oh… uhm… Yes I can. But
I'm trying not to. It's so… So childish.
No, it's not. It's just cute.
But men aren't supposed to be cute.
Under my blanket, you
can be as cute as you want.
Alright then!
[purring intensifies]
What is it this time?
I can't stop thinking about all
the things that happened today
and how it all fits together.
For example, Fireheart
gave you the amulet
and the song to identify yourself,
and get help when you need it.
But why so complicated?
It was pure luck we
ended up here so quickly.
If you father works at the stronghold
I would expect him to know what
happened in Coldlake yesterday.
Why didn't he send one
of the rebels to get you out?
Because that would have blown his cover?
Possible.
But I feel like there's a whole different
side to this story that we're missing out on.
Is there - is there anything else
your father gave to you?
Not really.
The only contact we had
was when he sent batches of
worn out robes for my mother to fix.
He was too afraid to send written notes
so sometimes he put things
into one of the robes' pockets
as if they had been forgotten to
let us know everything is alright.
Coins, little gemstones, a
little extra support for mom.
Oh, and he also used to send me
sweets so I don't have to be so sad.
But he stopped sending those a while ago.
I guess he thought I was getting too old.
How about that song
your father taught you…
"Light so Bright, Light so True"
Did he ever tell you what it means?
No, only that is was part of our secret
and that bad things would happen
if I sung it to anyone but myself.
Do you think that bad things
will happen if you sing it to me?
Because I'd really like to hear it…
No, I don't think so. It goes like this:
♪ Light so Bright, Light so Pure ♪
♪ Keepers of Light, Answer me True! ♪
♪ Light so Bright, so Pure, Light so True ♪
♪ I give myself to you ♪
Beautiful.
And mysterious.
Just like you.
Oh, thank you, River.
Do you think we're safe here?
With you around, every place feels safe.
[purring intensifies further]
Please keep doing that…
please keep doing it all night long…
[relaxed music]
[panting, then giggling]
[more giggling]
What? What is it?
What?
I...
I er I think I bit my tongue.
What?!
I... Yeah
I - I tried so hard to be quiet
that I bit my...
[giggling]
Shhhh!
Quiet!
What if they hear us?
Oi!
Are you finally done fucking yet?
[laughter, applause]
Some people want to sleep, you know!
Ah, screw it
I'll go for a walk until
you two are through!
Oh dear, so much for our good reputation.
Do you think that guy has a boner now?
Well, he sure did pitch a tent.
Frosty, Frosty…
I would have never thought
that you're such a naughty girl!
You know…
in times like these,
it's hard to stay sane.
I needed this… I needed you!
Me too.
I haven't felt this
complete in a long time.
I'm so glad I met you.
Are you sure?
I mean
even with all the trouble I've caused?
You remind me of someone.
You know, that's one of
the worst things to say
-right after you...
-No-no-no!
No-no-no!
It's not what... It's not
what you think, it's...
Have you ever wondered why a guy of my age
is living in such a big house, all alone?
Well... Something bad happened, right?
I grew up going to the keepers' temple
listening to the priests' sermons.
I learned how the gods blessed the
animals living on the holy mountain
and gave them a mind of
their own, the ability to speak.
Made the keepers our shepherds.
I wanted to show the gods my
gratitude for as long as I lived.
Until one day.
What happened?
I had a wife I loved dearly.
But something happened to her.
The light in the house, it...
it began to blind her.
Even when the shutters were closed.
Even when her eyes were closed.
It got worse every day.
She just wanted to run
away and hide from it, like...
Like a snapjaw.
Or a pigrat.
I didn't... Didn't know what to do.
So I brought her to the temple.
The keepers were our shepherds, right?
They kept her there,
and sent me home. And...
When I came back next day
she was gone.
They...
They told me that the gods had decided
she was possessed by darkness.
By the gods! Are you saying they…
-I mean…
-I...
I never found out what -
what they did to her. But
What I do know is that that
was the day I stopped believing.
And I swore that I would never let
something like that happen again.
And then you decided to let
me ruin what's left of your life?
No, Frostwind. It's...
It's exactly the opposite.
Ever since I lost my wife,
I have been dead inside.
You made me feel alive again.
And look where you've taken us!
We're in a place full of
things that would have been
magic to us only yesterday.
Right now, I couldn't be happier!
I love you, Frostwind, and I want
to stay with you until all eternity!
I love you too, River! But
you know I'm going to die!
No. No, you are not.
I swear, on my life, that I
will find a way for you to live.
[BRZZZZT]
Wait! What was that just now?
I don't know.
[BRZZZZT]
Is that one of the machines?
Whatever it is, I don't
like the sound of it…
[BRZZZZT]
Okay, that's it, I'm
going to check it out.
Be careful!
Don't worry. I'll be back in a minute.
Hello?
Are you still awake?
Did you also hear that noise?
You know, it went like …
[BRZZZZT]
-AAAAAH!
Yes, that's exactly how it sounds.
[diabolical laughter]
-No!..
Oh hello.
How rude of me to interrupt
your tender moment.
If I had known that you're
Fireheart's little bastard
I would have taken so
much better care of you.
What do you want, Ironwill?
Nothing.
Just you.
I'm afraid this is
going to hurt quite a bit.
Scream if you want, there
is nobody left to hear it.
[BRZZZZT]
-AAAAAH!
Ah... Brother Strongarm?
Are we ready to leave?
Yes, Overseer. They are all knocked out.
Excellent.
I've got what I was looking for.
Set this place ablaze and follow quickly.
We must get to the
mountain before the rebels.
Hey, wait a minute, what about me?
I let you inside the camp and I
showed you where her tent is.
What about my reward?
Oh, of course!
You shall get your reward!
Brother Strongarm, would you be so kind?
Most certainly.
[BRZZZZT]
-AAH!
Now set this place on fire.
I will.
And you are coming with me.
[BRZZZZT]
[fire cracking]
[dramatic music]
[panting]
Oh shit!
Holy fucking shit
-Do you believe me now?
-What have they done?
-Yeah, yeah!
-I told you it was a trap.
Yeah, but... Why
Bitternut of all people?
I don't care, we need to act.
Get as many people out
of their tents as you can!
-Oh shit!
-Okay, okay! All right!
Come on, with me, come on!
We'll take them to the bunker!
Quickly!
Yeah!
[applause]
Eject storage device one.
Ejecting storage device one. Please wait.
Medium is now safe to remove.
Reset watchdog program.
Watchdog timer reset.
Remaining time until shutdown
2 days, 23 hours
59 minutes.
Delete command log and terminate session.
Goodbye, Brother Fireheart.
My back!
Aah, I've been sitting in front
of this thing way too long.
Oh, I'm getting too old for this.
Oh, you must be Brother Fireheart.
Good thing you're still here, I
was afraid I was going to miss you.
Would you terribly mind
answering a few questions?
Who in the gods' name are you?
I don't think we've met before.
My name's Falconeye of Quail's Hollow.
I've been ordered to the stronghold at
Great Overseer Ironwill's personal request.
What is that in your hand?
It's a data crystal.
It's part of my work.
And whatever Ironwill ordered you here for
I would very much appreciate
if you did it somewhere else.
Goodnight.
It will just take a minute, I promise.
Please sit down.
I don't have time for this…
Oh, don't worry
you are going to have plenty of time soon.
What do you mean?
It has come to our attention
that there has been an unusual
amount of irregularities at the stronghold
Human artifacts disappearing over night.
Inexplicable power surges.
Records that don't match.
And what do I have to do with it?
I'm a scientist, not an accounting clerk.
A scientist!
That's human word, isn't it?
Oh I'm sorry if that confuses you, but yes
human artifacts and knowledge
are my field of expertise.
Now that's funny.
We just caught a group of
outcasts in the forest at Serpent River
and you know what?
They talked just like you.
And not only did they have their
pockets full of illegal human artifacts
they knew what they're
called, and how to use them.
Well, maybe you should invite them.
It seems like we can learn from them.
"It seems to me more like one
of us has been teaching them.
We are the Keepers of the Light, and we
are the keepers of the ancient knowledge.
If they know something
only we should know
that means we have a problem, doesn't it?
It means, someone
in our midst is a traitor.
Now would you mind telling me
where you are taking that data crystal?
To my room.
Sometimes I take my work up to my room.
And then what are you going to do with it
without a machine to read it?
You know nothing about this technology!
Oh, I do.
Everything you wrote about it, in fact.
I've been watching you for
many months, Brother Fireheart.
Studying your work.
Your records. Your life.
I know where you were
born, where you grew up
what you did during your time in Coldlake
and I know the name of every
single commoner you fucked with.
How many bastard children
did you conceive, Fireheart?
How many?
That is none of your goddamn business!
At least, thanks to the plague
you won't have to pay
much for child support.
You filthy son of a pigrat!
I could understand your
rage if I were making this up.
But I'm just merely stating the facts.
You seem to have a hard time
coming to terms with your own past.
Maybe you need to talk to someone.
Maybe it's time to confess.
Just let it all out.
Come on.
Relieve the rage!
There is nothing to confess.
And funny enough, that's not even a lie.
Because I already know it's you who
has been leaking our sacred knowledge
to the rebel underground
for all these years.
And I already know that
the rebel underground
is about to launch an
attack against the stronghold
using the very knowledge
and technology you gave them.
There's indeed not much
left to confess, I'll give you that
Except one thing.
And what would that
be, Brother Know-It-all?
Since the day you came here
you've been checking out a
double dose of the shadow remedy.
I checked all the logs against
the actual register of residents
turns out that one of the names belongs
to a brother who's been dead for years.
There's only one reason
to check out two doses
To keep someone alive
who's not supposed to be alive.
And I want you to tell
me who that someone is.
Only over my cold dead body.
[BRZZZZT]
Well, all in due time, Brother Fireheart.
We'll see to that.
All right, this is it.
Entrance B-35.
Aaaaaand - it's open!
I'll go in first and check it out.
The whole place is dark
Excellent.
We're going ahead as planned.
Follow me.
So far everything is exactly
as Fireheart promised.
That means we'll have about 10 minutes
to get to the 5 main control stations
before the power comes back on
once we've disarmed the guards
we'll round them up in the
old decontamination area and…
Fireheart?
FUCK! IT'S A TRAP!
Don't touch the barrier!
[BRZZZZT]
DO NOT MOVE!
All right, Ironwill.
I know you're in here.
[evil laughter]
Congratulations, Stormrunner
you caught on quickly!
But…
a bit too late.
Screw you, Ironwill!
How long has he been dead?
For about a month or so.
Sorry for scaring you like that
but he developed a bit of smell
so I put him outside.
Now drop your sword
or shall we shock the crap out of you?
Happy now?
Delighted!
You have been trouble for so many years.
Now you're finally in front of me
shitting your pants.
My day just couldn't get any better.
Oh wait!
Actually it could!
[SNAP]
[crowd exasperated]
[sinister laughter]
Now my day is perfect.
Ahh, look at what has become
of your laughable leaders!
Firehart! This is what happens to who
renounce the gods of the holy mountain!
Fireheart is dead!
Stormrunner is dead!
The rebellion is dead!
Hand over your weapons!
The rebellion will never die!
We will fight to the last man!
So touching to see how you hold on
to that little dream of yours.
You think: just maybe
your brothers and sisters of Camp
Freedom will come to save your sorry hides?
Well, it breaks my heart to tell you
that Camp Freedom is no longer anything
more but a pile of smoldering ashes.
And so are your brothers and sisters!
Don't... Don't believe what he says!
He's just trying to demoralize us!
Maybe you will believe my witness.
The only survivor…
[crowd becomes louder]
[crying]
He's right.
I saw the camp burn with my own eyes.
Everyone is dead!
If you keep fighting,
you will all die for nothing!
Please!
There, I told you so.
A keeper always tells the truth!
Then why don't you tell the people the
truth about the gods of the holy mountain?
And the dark plague and human technology?
How can you say you are telling the truth?
Knowledge is like fire.
Used carefully, it can warm
you on a cold winter's night.
But if set free, the fire spreads
and destroys everything in its path.
There once was a great
civilization before ours.
But the power of their knowledge had
become so strong that it destroyed them.
Today, nothing is left
of them but ancient ruins.
It is the Keepers' purpose to prevent
that from ever happening again.
The holy mountain is a hearth
of knowledge that we keep
so the people can bask in its
warmth without getting burned.
You may think yourselve as liberators
but in reality you are
just careless children
playing with fire.
For that, you should be pitied.
If you pity them, then show mercy!
When the crib is burning,
who deserves mercy?
The flames
or the child?
By your standards, I guess that would depend
whether the child has the plague or not.
[baleful laughter]
There's truly some Keeper's
blood running through your veins.
I would be tempted to see if
you'd carry the flame of truth
if you weren't a traitor's
bastard, of course.
Thank you very much, I'm sure.
Now what are you going to do with them?
Drown them in the nearest lake?
What a waste that would be.
No, they can serve a better purpose
they will be made examples of what
happens to betrayers of the Holy Mountain.
They will be tried and
executed in their own villages.
[direful laughter, crossing into coughing]
You don't sound so well, Irownill.
You should get that checked by a
professional human miracle scientist
before your peers decide
you're threat to mankind.
Happens quicker than you think.
I know what I'm talking about.
No.
No, Frostwind, you absolutely don't.
Come, and let me tell you
why you are on this side of the fence…
Follow me.
I need to show you something.
[bodeful laughter]
[applause]
Max, I really need to talk to you.
Jeff, sorry, I'm in the
middle of a phone call…
It's important.
Uh, all right.
Can I call you back? Ok, thanks.
OK, Jeff. What's the matter?
We have got to stop this madness!
-What happened?
-It doesn't work.
And it never will, and you know it.
Goldberg's team started
another trial run of Strain C.
And this time it didn't just go wrong.
No, it went horribly wrong.
You know, Jeff, we don't force anybody.
The subjects are all volunteers,
and they know the risks.
Someone has to make sacrifices
if we want humanity to prevail.
Oh, that's easy to say
if you weren't there.
It seemed to work for a minute or so
but then there was a glitch
in the communication matrix
and everything went out of control!
Can you imagine what it looks like
if a million nanites suddenly start
slicing randomly through a man's body?
It's the most disturbing thing I've
ever had to see in my entire life!
He was turned into a bloody pulp as if
someone had turned on a giant blender.
All the while he was fully conscious.
And it didn't stop at that.
The medics jumped forward to help
him, and as soon as they touched him
the nanites entered their bodies.
They both lost their hands
before the safeguards kicked in
and the swarm shut itself down.
It was a goddamn massacre!
Huh, Jeff...
I'm so sorry you had to see this.
But what else are we supposed to do
if we ever want to go
back to the surface again?
I have no perfect solution, Max.
We're all just poking about in the fog.
But this technology was
designed to be part of a machine.
And a military killing machine, at that.
It's a foolish idea to believe
you can somehow reprogram it
to repair a human body instead of a tank.
What if the swarm doesn't shut down
the next time, and it wipes us all out?
Jeff.
You do realize you need help, right?
No, you need help!
This isn't ethical! It's not even rational!
Please, Jeff, calm down.
You should go and see the counsellor.
And take a few weeks off, OK?
Take a few weeks off?
Oh no. I'll tell you what I do: I quit!
And let the geneticists win the race?
What, you think this is
some sort of competition?
Geneticists against Nanotechnologists?
And if they win, we lose?
Has it ever occured to you, that
if either team wins, nobody loses?
But if we wipe out our
own crew, we all lose!
Look, Jeff, I don't know about you,
but I want the real humanity back
A civilization of actual, genuine humans.
Not some tarnished, diluted chimera.
What is life worth if we no
longer know, who we are?
There is only one human race
and if I had to sacrifice my
own life to save it, I would do so.
If you have a problem with that,
you have no place in this organisation.
The old times are gone, Max.
And nothing will ever bring them back.
Evolution knows only one
direction, and that is forward.
*sigh* So you're changing camps?
Yes. And I'm sorry, Max.
I used to believe in nanotechnology,
but today's incident has opened my eyes.
If I have the choice between
creating new life, and taking it away
I know what's right.
You'll have my papers by tomorrow.
Good night, Max.
[repeated banging]
[creaky door opens]
Come in everybody
the keepers don't know about this entrance,
so we should be safe here for a while.
Where… are we?
We're inside the holy mountain.
The Keepers' stronghold at the
summit is just a very small part
of a much larger underground complex.
This part was sealed off a long time ago.
It's the last place
they'll be expecting us.
Amazing.
And all this was all built by the humans?
Yes.
Unlike the ruins you can find outside, this
place here was built to last centuries.
This place was once a
refuge for thousands of people
the final remains of a dying civilization.
How do you know about all this?
Fireheart studied the documents the
humans have left behind in this stronghold.
He shared centuries of history with us,
so we could use it to build a new world.
Ahh, can we save the history
lessons for another time?
All we had went up in flames anyway!
That makes spreading the
word even more important!
You know what's important to me right now?
All my friends are dead!
That's important!
I'm sorry. I can't turn back time.
I never liked the idea to take
the Keepers' Stronghold by force.
I think we should have put more
effort in actually educating the people!
But it was Stormrunner's decision
to make - he was the leader, not me.
Ah! Aha! And now you're in charge?
Are you ready to lead us?
He's the one who saved your sorry ass.
Show some respect!
Fuck you!
My friends are dead, and
he is all words, and no action!
Want action? Here!
Have some action!
Arrrgh! COME HERE YOU BASTARD!
-I will fucking kill you!
-Hey!
Hey!
Guys, er...
Hey, sto - stop it!
Will you CHILL THE FUCK OUT!
Stop fighting!
Listen!
They were my friends, too!
Do you even realize what
happened here tonight?
Stormrunner is dead!
We are on our own! We must stand together!
I'm sorry. It's just…
*cough* it's all been a bit too much.
I'm the one who needs to be sorry here.
If we hadn't come to your camp
I'm sure things would have
turned out quite differently.
Actually, I'm very glad you found us.
If there's anyone to blame, then it's me.
*sigh*
I had all the puzzle pieces,
and I knew something was wrong, but
by the time I figured it out, Ironwill
was already burning down the camp.
By the time you figured WHAT out?
Why Frostwind never showed any
symptoms of the plague all these years!
It was so obvious, but I didn't see it.
In order for her to survive
Fireheart must have some...
somehow he has supplied her…
or her mother...
with the radiation remedy.
Ra... Radiation… what?
Radiation damages the body's DNA.
But the humans found a
way to repair the damage
using swarms of specially
programmed nanites that…
What Brushie here is trying to say is
that the Keepers have a huge machine
that spits out little green pills.
And if you take one every
week you won't get the plague.
Exactly.
Frostwind suddenly getting the plague
means she no longer got the medicine.
And that in turn means that something
must have happened to her father!
I could have warned Stormrunner, but it
totally didn't occur to me
something could be wrong!
It's... It's alright Brushie.
We all try to do our best - it's
the only thing we can do, right?
Do you think Frostwind is still alive?
Yes. I saw Ironwill
carrying her out of the camp.
She must have something he wants.
So... So she could be
in this very building?
Maybe.
Maybe not.
But you can't just walk upstairs from here
and burst into the Keepers' living room.
-But...
-The inhabited area is pretty well
sealed off. And even if you'd find a way
they have ways of detecting
intruders you can't even imagine.
But we can't just sit here
and do nothing, either!
Frostwind might have only
a few days more to live!
You said that the keepers have a cure.
If all we need is a handful of pills
-then we - we just might…
[laughter]
What's so funny about that?
The machine that produces
the shadow remedy is
the single most well protected
thing in the entire Stronghold.
The holy of the holies.
What makes it so important?
The Keepers don't GET the plague!
Or do they?
Here's a little history lessen for you
The radiation that causes the
dark plague is the very same thing
that nearly wiped out humanity.
If humans still existed, and
you would put one of them
in the middle of Ferndale marketplaces
he would get sick and die.
But we're not human!
Oh yes. Yes, we are, my friend.
-Especially the Keepers.
-What?
Look around.
What do you see?
I see… cages …
Your own ancestors might once
have lived in one of these cages.
We're the creation of g...
We're not the creation of gods.
We're the creation of humans, my friend.
We're surrogates, bred to live in a world
no longer inhabitable for their own kind.
The Keepers are our own prototypes.
They have human blood.
-What?
-They are not immune to the radiation
and without the remedy, they will die.
All of them.
Guess why they are not allowed
to breed with us commoners.
And guess why they're protecting
the holy mountain like life itself!
Wow. That is…
just... wow.
Yeah, it floored me too.
The first 20 times I heard it.
Sparky!
*sigh* Alright. Fine.
I understand now what I'm up against. But
you know what?
I once lost a loved one just
because I was too afraid
to take things into my own hands, and
I'd rather die trying than
make that same mistake again.
I must go.
We can't come with you.
I understand.
But please, at least
tell me how to get there.
*sigh*
All right.
It was nice knowing you, my friend.
[applause]
Hrgsnm. Hrgmbrmbl. Hnnnnnrrrrgs.
Hrrrrrz. Uhhhh.
Hrrrrrr. Hrgggr. Hnnggs.
Uh-oh...
Aaaaaaaaaaaaargh!
AAAAAAAAAAAAAARGHHH!
Oh shit ohhh
Oohhhhh!
Aahhhhh!
Ouch!.. Ohh..
By the gods, that hurt.. Ohhh..
I see now why this wasn't the
rebels' preferred invasion route.
*sigh* Wow!
Woooow!
This looks so much nicer than the
prayer room of the chapel in Ferndale!
Everything's so bright and beautiful!
I wonder what kind of
ceremonies they conduct in here.
Oo-oooh drat
someone coming!
Why can't I keep my
god damned mouth shut...
All right, over there!
[creaky door opens and closes]
Dumm dee dumm dee dumm dumm.
Hmmm...
I could have sworn I heard a noise.
Eh
whatever.
At least there's still
time for some practice.
One, two
three!
four.
[organ music playing]
[creaky door opens again]
[BLAM]
Sorry my friend
Sorry, but I need this right now
c'mere...
*gasp*
Let me borrow that cloak for a moment.
Wahahaha!
Look at me, I'm Brother Riversong,
Avenger of the dispossessed, hah!
*sigh*
Now what I'm going to do with you?
All right!
Have a nice day, my friend.
[creaky door tries to open again]
Ooh nononono!
You're supposed to stay… inside!
No, that's won't work
Ahh! There.
Piece of cake, hah!
Now let's see... See
if I can find Frostwind.
Shouldn't be too hard,
now that I'm in disguise.
[muffled voices outside]
Dear Brothers and Sisters! *coughs*
Welcome to today's morning service.
Praised be the gods of the holy mountain!
[Everyone] "As it was, and always will be!"
Head Overseer Ironwill has *coughs*
called me up from my home village
to temporarily serve as a
replacement for Brother Swiftfoot
whose health sadly has deteriorated so much
that he can't be with us here today.
May the gods be with him and his family!
[Everyone] "As it was, and always will be!"
Before we begin with the festive part
Overseer Ironwill asked me to give you
a few updates about the current situation.
We... Mhhhm. Sorry.
We still have not been able
to restart the main light core
which means that the production
of the shadow remedy is still halted.
Our best researchers
are working on a solution
but until then we can only see it
as the gods' will
to test our faith.
[Everyone] "As it was, and always will be!"
Without the remedy, *coughs* the
darkness within us grows every day
and the Overseers are calling up
Brothers and Sisters from all villages
who are still of better
health to help us out.
Our healers have opened
up an extra basement level
which will serve as a temporary infirmary.
If anyone in your family
shows any signs of the plague
please take them down to level 12
and let the healers take a look.
Any questions?
Yes, please?
The scriptures say that the light
core is driven by the power of the gods!
Does that mean that the
gods have forsaken us?
No, no, of course not.
It is hard to explain
without getting technical
but according to Overseer Ironwill
it is not that the gods'
power is no longer there
but the machinery that
controls it has been locked down
so we can no longer use it.
Is it true that the lockdown
was Brother Fireheart's doing?
Yes. He was a servant of the darkness.
But don't despair.
Where there is a
lock, there is also a key
Fireheart's bastard daughter.
Ironwill is interrogating her right now.
So let's pray to the gods
of the holy mountain!
[Everyone] "As it was, and always will be!"
Let's sing the song of the uplifting
chant book page 437.
Music, please!
What are you waiting for?
I said, Music, please!
[organ cacophony]
By the gods, stop that dreadful noise!
What the hell is wrong with you?
*cough* *cough* *cough*
Oh um eh I'm... I'm so sorry …
I have the dark plague…
and the flu…
and the measles.
At the same time!
I can barely see. Or hear.
Or smell.
Or taste.
For goodness sake, then
why are you still here?
Get your tail down to the infirmary!
Oh yes, *cough* *cough*
thank you, Brother
Strongarm, for letting me go!
I would have gone to the infirmary
but I didn't want to disappoint you.
It's OK. Just - just go!
I tried my best, but it wasn't good enough.
-Don't - don't worry!
-Music has been always
my greatest passion and…
[THUD]
Wait!
Stop right there and show me your face.
Um...
Hello eh...
RIVERSONG!
-Eh...
-WHAT ARE YOU WAITING FOR?! SEIZE HIM!!
-Please don't - Aaaaaagh!
[BRZZZZT]
[applause]
[phone ringing]
*yawn*
What the hell…
This better be important!
Yes?
Uh, sorry to wake you
up, Paul, but it seems
we have a problem with
the power distribution.
Aha. And what is so important about that
that you need to wake me
up in the middle of the night?
I can't fix your power,
call a goddamn electrician.
Well, that's what we did. But
it's not a regular power outage.
We've lost contact to
the entire biolab section.
All five floors went dark at the
same time, including the backup power.
Also, the firedoors have
closed, so we can't get in.
Shit!
That's not supposed to happen!
Ahh... Any explosions,
fire, or other incidents?
No. We checked the surveillance
cameras… Nothing to see.
And no unusual environmental readings.
It was all quiet and normal, and all of a
sudden, all the circuit breakers tripped.
How many people are still in the lab?
Nobody. Security had
just finished their round.
5 minutes later, and they'd be trapped.
What the fuck is going on there?
*sigh* We're talking about at
least 3 independant systems here
all redundant - especially life support.
This can't be a coincidence.
Do what you can to get in there.
No shit, guess what we've
been trying all that time.
Oh wait…
Uh what?
Uh... The...
Jeff? It seems power is
coming back. Hang on.
And reset the goddamn fire doors!
OK, doors are opening.
Wait… what's… shit! CLOSE THE DOORS!
CLOSE THE DOORS! ARRGH!
Paul?
PAUL?
Shit!
Connection refused.
Oh no-no-no what the
fuck is going on there?!
[alarm]
The evacuation alarm. Oh, may god help us.
I knew this wouldn't end well, I knew it.
I got to get my envirosuit…. I….
AAARGH!
Bloody... Oh my god, Francis, you
nearly scared the living shit out of me.
Why do you always sneak up on me like that?
I'm sorry for not being as
noisy as your kind is, Master.
Well, very funny. Something
went wrong in the biolab
we need to get to the surface.
Have you seen my envirosuit?
Right over here, Master.
Wa... what?
What did you do to my
envirosuit? It's… torn to pieces!
And … what are you doing with that knife?
Today is the beginning of a new age.
Francis, what are you talking about?
It was me, who gave you gift of life!
I raised you, like a son, I
fed you, I taught you to walk
I taught you to speak - is this how
you are going to thank me for it?
Like your son, is what you say.
Like a slave, is what you mean.
I wanted to believe we're family.
I wanted to believe you care about us.
But then, why did I
have to call you Master?
From now on, there will
no longer be a master.
You can call me Jeff.
Listen to me, "Jeff".
Even if I look a lot like the cute little
kitten in that old family photo on your desk
I'm not stupid.
None of us are.
Did you really expect we wouldn't find
out how to use your fancy machines?
Did you really think you
could hide your plans from us?
I've been reading your emails
and I know what fate you
had in mind for our kind
now that we're obsolete.
You want us destroyed.
Every single one of us.
But it wasn't my idea! It's
an order by the commander!
He's a firm believer in nanotechnology
and now that the radiation cure works, he
ordered the end of all genetic experiments!
The genetic experiment begs to disagree!
I … I even fought for you!
I tried to convince him
to let you live, honestly!
Please, don't kill me! I'm your friend!
If you really were my friend,
you would have warned me, Jeff.
But you didn't.
You're all the same.
You cannot be trusted.
No… NO!
[SLASH]
This is the new age. Your
kind no longer rules this place.
[electric door opens]
Welcome to the inner
sanctum of the Stronghold.
Only a chosen few
ever get to see this place.
I'm honored… *coughs*
Please, take a seat.
Now what do you want from me, Ironwill?
Your father did something terrible,
and you are the only one who can stop it.
My father…?
This is the place your father used to work.
That huge thing over there
is called the main light core.
It harnesses the power of the gods
and like almost everything
made inside the stronghold
it's controlled by some
kind of artificial brain.
Brother Fireheart was our most valuable
expert on this kind of human technology.
You mean, before you killed him, right?
He brought that upon himself!
He gave away our
holiest secrets to the rebels
and of course we had to stop him.
The power of the gods is
mighty enough to wipe out all life
from the face of earth.
If it got into the wrong hands
that could mean the end of our world.
My father just wanted us to be free!
A freedom paid for with
the blood of innocents!
When he was still alive,
your father set up a trap.
He programmed the artificial
brain that controls the light core
to shut itself down unless he
personally delivers a special code word
at least once every
three days to prevent it.
And so, exactly three
days after his execution
the light core shut itself down
and with it - the production
of the shadow remedy.
He outsmarted you!
There is nothing funny about this!
Don't you realize what this means?
The Keepers are dying!
Thousands of good people.
No one will be spared
a slow and painful death.
Including you.
Unless you decide to help us.
Everything points to you being
the key to unlock this machine again.
You! *laughs*
You murdered my father and my mother!
You killed my friends in their sleep!
You took away everything that I ever loved!
And after all that, you
seriously expect me to help you?
Are you fucking kidding me?
The shadow remedy
will not only save our lives
it will also save yours!
I have been prepared to die
from the moment your people
burst into my mother's
home and slit her throat.
I am grateful for every
day I got to live after that
but I was always aware
that my days were numbered.
I have nothing left to lose
and if I can take a filthy
pigrat like you to my grave
so much the better!
Well, what a shame.
If I can't talk sense into you
I guess we have to do
this the old-fashioned way.
Send him in!
[electric door opens]
[groaning]
[ominous laughter]
RIVER!
Here he is, Overseer!
Thank you.
I knew you two would be
delighted to see each other again!
Mmmmmgmmhmmhmhm!
Ah...
Frostwind!
River!
I thought you were dead!
[minacious laughter]
So romantic!
Two lovers, re-united.
Too bad that the wedding
has to be canceled!
Hey!
What do you want with my amulet?
This should take some
time to get it from me
but your father went a long
way to make this machine useless
in case this petty rebellion fails.
But then our spy saw you present
your amulet to the rebel scouts
and say the secret phrase…
that showed us the way!
[computer sounds]
Token accepted
Please log in
LOG IN!
Login Passphrase Required.
Challenge: 'Light so bright'
"Light so pure!"
Login Passphrase accepted.
System is in Maintenance Mode.
Maintenance Passphrase Required.
Challenge: 'Keepers of the light'
And now, Frostwind
your moment has come to
heroically save the keeper race
by telling us the REST of this song!
Especially that very last line
that nobody seems to know…
except you.
Fuck you, Ironwill.
FUCK YOU IRONWILL is not
the Maintenance Passphrase.
Starting Over.
Dear brother
would you mind guarding the
door from the other side for a while?
It might get a little bit...
nasty in here.
Whatever you say, Overseer.
[electric door opens and closes]
Now just in case you want to
complain about my brutality again
Please notice that I
gave you not only one
but two chances to get
out of this unharmed.
You wanted it this way
not me.
[SLASH]
-Aaaaaaahhhh!
-No!
-Fuck!
My ear!
Ahhh. Now, sing, my darling!
Sing!
No!
Don't do it!
He'll kill us anyway!
-I said, SING!
-Aaaaahhhh!
I will do everything...
[rattle, screams]
-Brushie!
-Hah!
It ends here tonight, Ironwill!
In your dreams!
-Aaaaaaahhhh!
[portentous laughter]
You think dropping in makes you hero?
No!
For that, you're not man
enough to save your friends
[inauspicious laughter]
Now die!
[BRZZZZT]
Brushy! Are you alright?
Take my sword!
Take care of Riversong,
and lock the door! Quick!
Oh Frosty...
There you go!
I'm so glad you're still alive!
Hang on, Frostwind
Let's lock that door!
[BEEP BOOP]
That was a close call.
Brushy?
What do we do now?
Brushie? Oh shit!
BRUSHIE!
Brushie!
AAARRRRGH!
I don't make the
same mistake twice!
Stay away from me!
Sick bastard!
You will join our ancestors!
There goes your sword
Now for your life!
See you in hell, Riversong!
[BRZZZZT]
-Aaaaahhh!
River!
Frostwind
are you alright?
No! Nothing is alright.
River?
RIVERSONG!
Can you hear me?
River!
Frr...
Frosty?
Frosty, yes!
Yes, I can hear you.
How are you?
Can you... Can you get up?
We need to get you out of there!
Here, take my paw!
I...
I can't feel my legs!
I'm sorry, I can't move!
[banging on the door]
-Hello?
What's going on in there?
Ironwill? Are you there? Hello?
Oh shit! We're sitting in a trap!
It's only a matter of minutes
until they kick in the door!
We need to help Riversong!
Please...
The bottom of the chamber
is at least four meters deep!
If you've got any ideas, I'm all ears!
Isn't there something here we could...
Even if there was
how are we supposed to get out of here?
[banging on the door]
-This is your final warning!
Open the door and release the Overseer!
If you want us dead
you'll have to come and get us!
Alright, you had your chance.
We're coming in.
Okay, let's think.
Is there ANYBODY left out
there we could ask for help?
Sparky! Sparky and Longleaf are still
with the other camp survivors.
-I could try calling them.
-Calling?
But how would they be able to hear us?
The room has a communications
unit just like this one next to the door.
If we're lucky, it still works.
Let's try this.
[beep beep beep beep]
[phone calling]
Hey! Brushie!
I told ya it was a good idea to write
down that comm number! What's up?
We're boarded up in
the main control room
and the Keepers are
about to kick in the door!
Sounds like you should
get the hell out of there.
That's the problem. We can't.
And we're out of ideas.
Uh, lovely. Any news from team alpha?
Yes! They're still alive!
Ironwill had them
rounded up in the courtyard!
Well, that's your rescue squad!
All you gotta do is let them out!
Sparky, this isn't funny,
and not the time...
I'm not joking. You're
in the main control room.
The door locks, the power supply, the
intercom and even some of the weapons
can be controlled from there.
You're the gods of the holy mountain!
No, we're not.
Fireheart locked the computer,
and turned off the light core.
Can't you turn it back on again?
No. Riversong is inside
the reactor chamber.
It would instantly kill him.
Ah shit. Then we must find a different way.
Do it anyways!
No!
I could never harm
you, River! I love you!
Look around you! Maybe there's
something you can use as a weapon…
[BAAROOMMM]
The door!
-They're breaking through!
-No!
You must do it, Frostwind,
or they're going to kill you all!
No!
Ahh can someone shut! That! Guy! Up!?
If you can't, I will do it!
Log in!
Login Passphrase Required.
River! Are you crazy?
What are you doing?!
♪ Light so Bright ♪
♪ Light so Pure ♪
Login passphrase accepted
♪ Keepers of the Light ♪
♪ Answer me True ♪
Password accepted
♪ Light so Bright, so Pure ♪
♪ Light so True ♪
♪ I give myself to you ♪
Startup confirmed
If there is a life after this one
I will be watching over you, I promise.
Take care my love.
Take care.
Nooooo!
NOOOO! STOP!
MAKE IT STOP!
[dramatic orchestral music]
Dear Frostwind
If you are seeing this message, it
means that the rebellion has failed
and I am probably already dead.
In case this happens, I have
programmed the main computer
to shut down the fusion reactor and
secure itself for the period of one year
long enough to cause the complete
extinction of the Keepers' race.
I'm not sure if I can trust
my own sanity any more, but
there is more at stake
than anyone can imagine.
In a time long before we existed
the earth was ruled by humans.
They were incredibly powerful.
They lived in cities the size of kingdoms
they could fly to the moon, and
they had unlocked the mystery of life!
But they also built the
most terrible weapons
powerful enough to
destroy the entire world.
When the great war broke out
it wiped most of humanity from the
face of the earth in a matter of days.
Only a small group of scientists survived
hiding inside a secret underground facility
shielded by thick layers of rocks.
But the land above was now
poisoned with deadly radiation
and their supplies would not last forever.
They had to reclaim the
surface to survive - but how?
The scientists were divided into two camps.
The nanotechnologists, who believed that
humans needed to transform themselves
into a new superior species
A fusion of man and technology
their blood infused with
microscopic machines
keeping them alive in even
the most hostile environments.
The genetic engineers
were appalled by this idea
as it threatened to blur the
boundary between human and artifact
it was indecent, unnatural and unethical.
They proposed transfering
human DNA into lab animals instead
blessing them with just
enough human qualities
to perform complex tasks at
the command of their masters
and prepare the earth for
the return of humankind.
They had short lifespans,
but they bred rapidly
and consistent selection would make them
increasingly resistant to the radiation.
The nanotechnologists were
just as disgusted by this idea
as the genetic engineers were by theirs.
After many weeks of fruitless debate
the two teams eventually
struck out on their own
each of them hoping to be the first to
make the other group's efforts obsolete.
The genetic engieers made great
strides, and the results looked promising.
Each generation of animals turned out a little
bit more resistant against the radiation
and soon they were able to
permanently live outside the compound
performing the basic building and farming
tasks their masters had taught them.
Strict selection ensured that
only the most resistant individuals
were allowed to breed.
Those who turned out
ot be unfit to live outside
were trained to serve the
humans inside the compound.
But the geneticists' hopes
were rudely shattered one day
when the nanotechnologists
announced that they had won the race.
They could now manufacture the radiation
cure we know today as the shadow remedy.
The leaders decided that there was
no need for further animal testing
and all remaining specimens
were to be destroyed.
A simple administrative act - but
the last one ever to be
decided by a human being.
The animal slaves living inside the bunker
had wisely hidden how
intelligent they really were
and they did not take
kindly to their masters' plans.
Their revolt was bloody,
marking the dawning of a new age.
An age in which
humans no longer existed.
The former slaves took over the place we
now call the Stronghold on the Holy Mountain
appearing like gods to the commoners
still living outside the compound.
Reveling in their newfound power
eventually they became
the Keepers of the Light.
To this day
the Holy Mountain holds the
knowledge of an entire civilisation
but rather than share the knowledge
the Keepers horde it for themselves
and keep the population dumb
poor, and dependent upon "godly gifts".
Gifts that are really just
products of human technology that
they don't even fully
understand themselves.
Now that the rebellion has failed
you are the only one I can trust.
And I'm glad you were
able to follow my tracks.
Genocide is now no longer the last resort.
The Keepers' fate now rests in your hands.
Maybe you can do better than I.
Maybe you haven't gone insane yet.
I trust you to do the right thing.
I trust you to bring the world the truth.
Farewell, my beloved daughter.
Farewell.
Wow.
So this is what grandpa
Fireheart looked like!
Yes, Raindancer. I remember
it like it was yesterday.
I still miss him. And Riversong, too.
What happened after
you started the light core?
How did you get out?
Uncle Brushie used the main
computer to free the rebels
of team alpha that were still
being held in the courtyard
giving them instructions over
the intercom where to find us.
The Keepers were not
prepared for a sudden attack
and when they found
out that Ironwill was dead
and they no longer had
control over their own machinery
they eventually surrendered.
Wow! Huh, you're a hero!
Why didn't you tell me this before?
Because we wanted to be
sure you were ready for it.
It's quite a gruesome story after all.
Brushie…
I think he's old enough to
understand the real reason.
What is the real reason, then?
Because I am not a hero.
I'm a survivor.
And I feel guilty for that.
For Riversong, your father.
The reason I never told
you the whole story was…
I couldn't.
The scars needed to heal.
But it wasn't your fault he died!
*sigh* It's not that easy
to come to terms with.
Well, if it helps
For me, you're the most
awesome mom in the world!
Oh yes, it does!
And one day, I want to be a scientist
just like grandpa Fireheart!
By the way, uncle Brushie, um,
can I ask you a question?
Sure!
Um, my - my biology teacher said
that a species is defined as
the largest group of organisms
capable of interbreeding
and producing fertile offspring.
Oh, that's right, Raindancer!
You did your homework well!
But - but daddy was a cat.
Mommy is a fox, so...
How did that even work?
[laughter]
Yes, uncle Brushie,
how did it even work?
Well, you see, that's...
that's because we're not
all really different species.
Under the fur, we're all just humans.
We just look a little different.
Me too?
Yes, you too.
But enough heavy subjects.
Tonight's festival night!
-Don't you want to see your present?
-Oh yes!
Yes, yes of course! What is it?
Wow...
Wow!
This...
This is the...
The Tree of Knowledge Pendant?
Is that the real one?
Yes.
May it always protect you.
And may it always remind you
that your family and your friends
will be there for you at all times!
Oh thank you, mom!
-Hey, Brushie, old-boy!
-What
the hell! Sparky! Longleaf!
I haven't seen you in ages!
Did you come all the way
from Ironforge just to see us?
Well, drinking alone is
only half the fun, isn't it?
We're gonna get hammered!
Just like in the old times!
What a wonderful surprise!
Come on in, everybody!
My... My Lord!
I... I hereby most subserviently request
permission to get hammered, too.
Seriously?
Are you still holding a grudge
against me after all those years?
Oh well, go, meet with your friends!
Yipppiehh!
Citizens of Ferndale!
May I have your attention
while everybody is still sober.
We are celebrating a
special anniversary today.
It has been exactly 10 years since the
liberation from the Keepers of the Light.
And we've come a long way since then.
We are no longer blind to
the true origin of our species
The ancient scientific
knowledge is now free for all
and although we're not quite ready yet
to master it like our human forefathers did
it has already improved
our lives in numerous ways.
The strangling collar of the
Keepers' reign has been taken from us.
And so I wish to dedicate
this years' Festival of Light
to our heroes who lost their lives in
the most unlikely battle of our history
Fireheart of Coldlake
Riversong of Ferndale
and the rebels of Camp Freedom.
They will always live on in our hearts!
[Everyone] ♪ Light so Bright! ♪
[Everyone] ♪ Light so Pure! ♪
[Everyone] ♪ Spread the wisdom! ♪
[Everyone] ♪ Spread the truth! ♪
[Everyone] ♪ Sing it to the world! ♪
[Everyone] ♪ Let them know! ♪
[Everyone]
♪ Make the tree of knowledge grow! ♪
[everyone cheers]
[epic orchestral music]
[applause]
♪ Light so Bright ♪
♪ Light so Pure! ♪
♪ Keepers of Light, Answer me True ♪
♪ Light so Bright, so Pure, Light so True ♪
♪ I give myself to you ♪