Come on, baby, I know you can do it!
Huh. Maybe that screw was in the way?
Good riddance.
Now, let's try that again.
Hah-hah-hah, I knew it!
Screw you, you stupid screw!
Yes!
No, I mean, nonononono!
*cough* *cough* *cough* *cough*
Cake delivery for Mr French! *cough*
What's with the smoke?
Did you try to bake one yourself?
*cough* No no, it's just this piece
of junk that almost blew up on me.
Come on in, come on in.
Is that the cake I ordered?
Yes, if your name is Abraham French
this is your double
layer vanilla cream cake.
With a cherry on top?
Just like you ordered, sir!
Would you be so kind
as to sign the receipt?
Oh, absolutely! Let me find a
clean cloth to wipe my paws with.
A pawprint will do, I think, mister French.
All right!
Yeah, I think that'll do.
Thank you very much for
shopping with Harrington's
purveyors to Her Highness
the Queen of Astar.
I appreciate the speedy delivery, Miss.
The Hazelwoods will be coming over for
tea and the cake is a surprise for them!
I'm sure they will love it!
Good day Mr. French, and
best regards to the Hazelwoods!
Bye, miss Herrington!
Ok, where was I?
[door closes]
[door opens]
Umh. So sorry Mr. French,
I couldn't help but notice…
what happened to the poor bike?
Oh… Um... something's
wrong with the engine.
Nothing a woman would understand.
The HW-22 is the first of the series
with the new four stroke engine
and the lubrication
system can be a bit finnicky.
Now, if you have a 12mm wrench,
I can show you what I mean…
Uhm… Yeah, it's… over in the toolbox…
Um... are you sure you can… I mean… Uhm...
A-ha! The oil line check
valve is stuck on open.
That's typical. This engine
hasn't been run in a while, has it?
Why yes, the winter's been
too harsh to take her for a ride.
Purring like a kitten!
Growling like a tigress, more
like. How did you do that?
Something was wrong with the engine.
Nothing a man would understand.
Well played young Miss, well played.
Pardon my saying so, but aren't your
talents being wasted delivering cakes?
You're very kind, but my mother needs all
the help she can get in the pastry shop.
Wait a minute…
are you the daughter of Peter Harrington?
Of Harrington & Welsh?
Not any more. On both counts.
Miss Harrington - your father
literally invented the airplane!
And clearly the same grease
runs through your veins, too.
As a child, I wanted to be an engineer!
But...
after father's accident…
Mother never got over the loss.
She sold our part of the
company to Mr. Welsh, and
I had to promise to never
set foot in a workshop again.
Well, unless I'm delivering cakes!
[door opens]
Hey, French!
You gotta put this poster in
your window! It's from Mr. Welsh!
What in earth's name, Cal!
Can't you see I'm having
a conversation with a lady?
Put the bloody thing on
the counter, and bugger off!
Mr. Welsh says you
gotta to put it up right now!
The trans-oceanic expedition has returned
and you won't believe what they've found!
There's going to be a big show with brass
band, moving pictures, the whole shebang!
For a few bucks we'll give
you a tour of the airship
and of course we have
our special attraction:
The Beast from another world!
Oh! Can I have a poster too?
My father designed that airship!
Girl, we're not running a charity!
Printing these costs money!
I'll put it in the window of
our pastry shop! I promise!
Pastry Shop?
Does that mean you brought me cake?
No!
And what's that?
That one's for Mr. French!
Keep your dirty paws off!
Hmmm…. nomnomnom.
Hey! What do you think you're doing!
Hmmm…. so delicious and moist.
Mr. French paid for that cake!
You can't just come in and eat it!
And watcha gonna do about it, huh?
See you at the
exhibition on Saturday!
Bye-bye!
Uhhh!
How rude was that?!
Well, if that's Mr. Welsh's
new charm offensive
I see a lot of room for improvement!
I'm not going to let that
sucker ruin your day.
I'll get you a new cake, and
if I have to, make it myself.
Will 4 o'clock still be fine?
No no no, don't worry, it wasn't your fault
and there's still more left
than we can eat anyway.
Well... Are you sure?
And if you'd like to get
your paws dirty again
you're more than welcome
to come back after work anytime.
Or how about Saturday night?
I beg your pardon!?
Damn, that came out all wrong, didn't it?
I mean the exhibition.
I think we'd have a great time together.
Us. Two engineers at
heart. You know what I mean.
I... Uh... I don't think
Mother would allow that.
You're a grown up woman,
can't you go wherever you want?
*sigh* I wonder what you're really
interested in: The airship or me?
Um, maybe a little bit of both?
*chuckles* I see. But what about your wife?
Oh, Clarice? Pistons and crankshafts
would have bored her to death.
Would have?
Yeah, she's no longer with me.
Hasn't been for a long time.
Oh … I'm so sorry to hear that!
Life must go on, doesn't it?
Absolutely. You know what?
I think I'll bite. Saturday at 9 then?
Yes! Excellent!
Looking forward to lots of pistons
and crankshafts, Mr. French!
Me too! See you on Saturday!
Bye!
[door closes]
[applause]
[Music: "The Skies of Astar" by Fox Amoore]
♪ Just one touch tell me who you are ♪
♪ here beneath the skies of Astar ♪
♪ Spoken with no sound ♪
♪ foreign lands abound ♪
♪ wandering skies ♪
♪ for the voice that I lost... ♪
♪ though soon your land I view ♪
♪ above ♪
♪ (Just one touch from me) ♪
♪ Fly true, touch and breakthrough ♪
♪ brave new worlds tale ♪
♪ my voice unveiled. ♪
♪ Set sail... But unto the skies ♪
♪ and we will leave the world behind. ♪
♪ Sometimes our minds change ♪
♪ sometimes it feels strange ♪
♪ when you're alone above. ♪
♪ Land that is fleeting... ♪
♪ (Just one touch from me) ♪
♪ Fly true, touch and breakthrough ♪
♪ brave new worlds tale ♪
♪ my voice unveiled. ♪
♪ Set sail... But unto the skies ♪
♪ and we will leave the world behind. ♪
♪ One touch last forever ♪
♪ Fly true, touch and breakthrough ♪
♪ brave new worlds tale ♪
♪ my voice unveiled. ♪
♪ Set sail... But unto the skies ♪
♪ Let's leave, let's leave, ♪
♪ let's leave the world behind ♪
♪ Just one touch tell me who you are ♪
♪ Here beneath the skies of Astar ♪
[applause]
Oh wow, would you just look at her!
She is so much bigger than I thought.
Really?
I'd say she's exactly as
big as I hoped she would be.
I just wish we could see more of her.
Just wait.
They set up the biggest electric
light installation in the world
it is going to look gorgeous!
That is so typical for Welsh.
He'll never pass up a chance
to show off just how rich he is.
Ooh, do I hear a touch of envy?
The company "Harrington & Welsh"
was founded at my mom's kitchen table
by my father, the engineer,
and Welsh, the salesman.
He could sell you a cup of horse piss and
make you believe it's a '65 Chateau de Ferèt.
Florence! Such a potty mouth!
I have absolutely no
sympathy for this…
person.
But why?
Because my name is
Harrington, and I deliver cake?
Oh. Yeah. Point taken, sorry.
If you want my advice -
don't believe a word he says.
This is not an exhibition,
it's a sales pitch.
Yeah, but... the airship!
It is still marvelous!
Oh my god, yes she is
And guess who didn't design her!
[Loudspeaker] Ladies and Gentleman
welcome to "The Trans Oceanic
Expedition Magical Moving Picture Show"
Please take a seat, the
show is about to begin!
This is Feivel Mc Brookhaven
for Astar National Radio
reporting live from Port Ospen
proud capital of the
kingdom of great Astar.
The royal geographic society has
confirmed that Mr. Welsh's expedition
has indeed found a
mysterious uninhabited continent
far in the South Astarian Sea.
The Peter M. Harrington
Airfield is bursting with people
curious to see the incredible
spectacle that is about to begin
celebrating the return of
Mr. Welsh and his crew.
Harrington & Welsh,
conqueror of the skies of Astar
and suppressor of the uprising
of Vanos proudly presents
The Trans-Oceanic Expedition!
We have long shared the dream of
expanding our realm beyond the horizon!
But so far explorers have found nothing but a few
barren islands within the ice of the northern sea.
Thanks to the HW-129 long range airship
we were able to venture farther
than any explorer before us.
It provides twice the space for provisions
requires less than half
the crew of a traditional ship
and even carries two HW-21 war planes
in case defense becomes necessary.
The unnamed continent
is a rich tropical paradise
full of exotic plants and
animals never seen before
and millions of acres of fertile
ground rich in valuable minerals
waiting to be mined and traded.
But exploring a new
world is a dangerous affair.
You never know what awaits you.
Dangerous weather!
Poisonous plants!
Or even fierce, savage beasts!
We were peacefully flying along the shore
mapping out the coastline
when we were suddenly attacked
by these huge flying animals.
They looked like feathered dragons
trying to sink their claws into our hull!
We were in fear for our lives!
They were the most horrible
things we had ever seen
and they seemed to
have only one thing in mind
KILL! KILL KILL!
The audience reels in terror
as one of the beasts is
revealed in the flesh
showing its sleek red body and the
sharp fangs of a bloodthirsty predator!
What a horrific sight indeed!
I'm barely standing 20 feet away
and my legs are shaking.
SHAKING!
Fear not, people of Astar!
This beast can not hurt you.
It was subdued and brought to the kingdom
as a gift of gratitude to her
Majesty, Queen Irdis of great Astar!
Together we will conquer the world,
with Airships by Harrington and Welsh!
Oh - my - god! What a terrible show!
Really? I found it quite
entertaining, actually
It was dreadful! Horrendous! Abysmal!
No mention of any of the inventions that
made the ship possible in the first place!
The complex multi-plane fins
the two-row radial engines with
their centrifugal superchargers
using a gas as fuel…
Oh, I could go on like this forever!
You seem to know a lot about the airship!
Of course I do!
My father designed it!
The only thing Welsh ever
contributed to it was his name.
And who in their right mind puts
warplanes on a research vessel?
Maybe it's good for more than one purpose.
Damn right.
I told you it's a sales pitch.
The war against Vanos made
him the richest man in the world
but that's over now.
It's no coincidence he's showing us
the most scary beast he could find.
He needs a new threat to keep
his war machines in demand.
Father would have never allowed this.
He wanted to make the world a better place.
But would he have won the war?
In war there are no winners.
Hey, you! Stay away from the cage!
Or you'll lose an arm! Yes, I mean you!
HEY! How would you feel
locked up in a cage like that
thousands of miles away from home?
Oh shut up, woman!
Stop pestering the poor animal!
Can't you see it's scared?
I'm just showing her
who's the man in the house!
Is that also how you
treat your wife at home?
Haha, hello, if that isn't
our esteemed Mr. French!
How much cake did you
have to order for the date, huh?
One more word, and I'm
going to get up there and...
[BOOM!]
We interrupt our program
for these breaking news.
A bomb has exploded at the Peter M.
Harrington airfield just a few seconds ago.
People are running for cover,
trying to find shelter!
The airship does not seem to be damaged
but it's unclear how many
are wounded or even dead.
Is this a terrorist attack?
Is this the revenge of
separatists from Vanos?
We will…
[BOOM!]
We are under attack.
Prepare for immediate takeoff.
All crew on board.
I repeat, we are under attack.
Prepare for immediate takeoff.
Shine some torches over
here, I need some goddamn light!
Ahh...
Damn it!
It's stuck!
Come here! Come here
you sissies and help me!
[BOOM!]
No! The poor animal!
It might get hurt!
Calm down! Everything will be alright!
Hey, hey, keep away
from the cage!
You idiot! She will rip your arm right off!
Oh let me help you pull the rope!
The one that just broke?!
Uh, if you want to help,
then stay out of the way!
ACK! Dammit! Stop biting me!
Why won't you do what I
tell you! It's for your own good!
Goddamn bitch!
What the hell are you doing?
You're just frightening her even more!
What the hell are you
doing? Are you crazy?!
Hey there. Everything will be okay!
Just calm down! I'm not
going to hurt you. Just trust me.
Wait, what?
You're not deaf, like the other ones?
How is that possible?
And you have a name?
Florence?
Please help me, Florence! Help me!
I told you she's gonna bite
you, to stay away from the cage!
Stupid wouldn't listen!
She's not an animal!
What? What are you talking about?
She has said She! Is! Not! An! Animal!
What?
How… how the hell did
you calm her down like that?
You wouldn't understand!
Let's get her to the airship!
Or do you want her to burn alive?
Er, no, no. Of course not.
Batten down the hatches, close
the cargo doors, all hands aboard!
No!
Don't close the doors! Wait for us!
Florence, come back! What am
I supposed to tell your mother?
Just make something up! You're a smart man!
Are you kidding me?
Florence? Florence! Goddammit!
[applause]
[knocking]
[door opens]
I don't buy anything at the door.
So take your samples and your
magazines and have a good day, Sir!
Stop... Ms. Harrington, please!
Please, Ms. Harrington! My...
My name is Abraham French
I need to talk to you! It is urgent!
[door opens]
Have we met before?
Very briefly. I ordered a cake
from your shop a few days ago.
French, you say?
-French…
-Yes...
Double vanilla cream
cake with extra olives?
No, cherries.
Good grief, why would I think olives?
Actually, glazed olives might work
-on a savoury carrot cake, with the right...
-Ms. Harrington, please, Ms. Harrington!
That's not why I'm here.
-It's about your daughter.
-Oh.
Florence?
Can I please come in, Mrs. Harrington?
I'm afraid the matter is… delicate.
All right. This better be important!
So what did she do this time?
Florence and I went to see
Mr. Welsh's exhibition. Together.
Partners in crime! How romantic.
But don't you think she's a
little bit too young for you?
No! I mean yes… I mean… Mrs.
Harrington, that's not – I'd never…
You can stop sweating and fretting,
Mr. French, I'm only pulling your leg.
Consider it a mother's revenge
I told her not to go, and I'm
sure my daughter told you that.
But it's Peter's airship
so I doubt you had to work
hard to convince her to go see it.
I'm afraid it's worse
than that, Mrs. Harrington.
There was a terrorist attack.
Bombs – laid by vanosian
seperatists, so they say.
Oh my god, is Florence alright?
Mrs. Harrington… I don't know!
What do you mean?
She tried to rescue an animal
that was part of the show.
She jumped on board of the airship, and...
then it took off. With her.
*SIGH* That is my daughter.
Strong sense of justice,
her father would say
fool-headed, if you ask me.
You'll have to get used to that if
you intend to keep courting her.
Mrs. Harrington, please!
She didn't get hurt, that's what matters.
Thank you so much for coming
here and letting me know.
Clarice and I never had any children…
but if we had, I wished it
would have been a girl like Florence.
I convinced her to go, and I
was responsible for her safety
but I let her down – and I let you down.
I'm so so sorry.
Mr. French, please stop gushing.
Your worry does you credit,
but she's no child any more
no matter how much old
people like us wish she still were.
She made her own decisions
both to go to see the
airship, and to board it.
I just hope she's fine.
Florence makes good decisions
even though they can be damn inconvenient.
You and I may be worried sick
but I'm sure she's all right.
Say, do you have a telephone?
I'm afraid not.
Okay. But I do. And
Florence has my number. So–
Oh, so you gave her your number?
No! I assure you... *chuckles* Oh, I get it
You know, if she calls
me, I will let you know.
Otherwise I'll check
back with you tomorrow.
Let's do that. And thank
you again for your help.
We made it!
Yeah! Hard to believe, since I had
to drag YOU along by the petticoat.
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
Women, why do they
always have to get in the way.
You now stay off the cage.
Did I look like I needed YOUR help?
SHE did, you stupid thug!
She begged me to save her!
Oh, sure. You're crazy!
Maybe, but I'm still right.
And YOU are still a thug.
And SHE is an intelligent being, like
the both of us, and she's scared to death!
How would you know?
Beasts can't talk!
So she must not be a beast, then.
And she didn't… talk.
I mean with her mouth. She
just - told me. I don't know how.
Yeah. Enough of that rubbish!
You're not allowed to be here,
and I'll have to explain Mr. Welsh
what Florence Harrington
is doing in his cargo bay!
*sigh* This is bad. This is really bad!
Hey, where are you going?
I'm gonna try and convince Welsh
not to throw the both of us out the hatch.
Why would he do that?
Do you want it in alphabetical,
or chronological order?
Stay where you are, and
keep your paws off the cage!
I know it was real.
And if the entire world
thinks I'm crazy, I just know it!
Yes, I'm talking about you.
Do you understand me?
You spoke to me before!
Why don't you do it now?
Come on! Say something! Please?
Now you're just making fun of me.
You could have bitten my arm off.
But you didn't.
You can't be as evil as they say.
Good girl… there's a good girl…
Hello again, Florence!
Argh! What … what are
you doing inside my head?
And how do you know my name?
I'm not deaf, Florence.
You don't have to think so
loudly at me – or so much!
What – I think too much?
You sound like my mother.
What? Florence, I can barely
hear you over the noise of your fear!
Wait, that's not fear…
You're curious, aren't you?
Now you sound just like my father!
Your father – the accident – oh
please, don't feel so much at me.
Focus, Florence, focus
on me, on us, here and now.
Relax. Think less. Say more.
I'll try, Ortha. I'll try!
Ahhhh, yes! So much better!
Wait! Ortha? Is that your
name? How do I know your name?
The same way I know yours.
Yes, my name is Ortha,
guardian of the realm.
Realm? Which realm? Where are you from?
We just call it home.
Now, Florence, I would like to
know where I am right now.
This is the Kingdom of Great Astar.
That name doesn't mean anything to
me. Could you picture it in your head?
Yes, but I never got to
see much of it from above.
But you wanted to, didn't you?
To fly, like your father.
It breaks my heart to see you're still so
full of sadness, after even so many years.
Was I still thinking about him?
Wait… you're thinking about
someone too. Someone you lost?
My brother, Sitho.
He was a guardian like me.
The deaf ones came
in their flying machines.
We flew out to guide them
to a safe landing place.
But they attacked us, and soon the
sea was red with the blood of my kin.
Those who survived hid in the
forest, high up in the mountains.
I was injured, and
they captured me.
Deaf? You mean, you
couldn't read their minds?
To me, this is as normal
as talking is to you.
Oh, I'm so glad we found each other.
Everything makes so much more sense now.
So this Mr. Welsh is the
one who built the war ship
and I'm the trophy he wants
to present to his Queen?
Ortha! I definitely wasn't
thinking about any of that.
You were snooping!
Can you blame me?
I'm in a cage!
Now, you need to talk to Cal.
He is the only one who
can get me out of this thing.
Why would he do that?
He's like, Welsh's left hand!
I don't need to snoop to
find out what you think of him
but there's more to him than you know.
He cared for my wounds
he spent a lot of time finding
out what kind of food I like
and he made a lot of gentle mouth
noises when nobody was looking.
I think he likes me.
Not enough to let you free.
But enough to bring me fish.
Ew, could you please not
think about the smell so much?
And to me he's basically been…
An arsehole? *chuckles*
That is such a funny image.
No, don't blush. It's really funny!
A lady is not supposed to say that!
But you think it all the time.
Oh! Do you hear that?
I think someone's coming!
Will you stay close to me?
It seems we need to
touch each other to hear each other
maybe I can hear them through your ears.
There she is.
Well...
She's gone completely out of her mind!
I tried to keep her from
entering the ship, but
getting the beast out of
danger was my first priority!
Ms. Harrington, welcome
aboard my humble ship.
May I know the reason why you are
honoring us with this unexpected visit?
I helped Cal move the
cage into the cargo bay
and I didn't manage to
get off the ship in time.
As simple as that.
I suppose I should thank you.
This cage contains my
company's future, after all.
Nothing sells war planes
like a new threat from the air.
I'm sure the Queen will agree
especially after Vanosian
terrorists bombed my exhibition!
Did you have a hand in that?
The one Harrington who was never
supposed to set foot on an airplane again?
I have nothing to do with the
bombs, or the terrorists, or even you.
I just wanted to save Ortha.
Save who?
The beast. Her name is Ortha.
And she's not an animal.
She feared for her life
when the bombs went off
Cal needed my help
to get her out of danger.
She speaks with her
mind, and only I can hear it!
The bombs must have rung your pretty
little bell quite hard, Ms. Harrington.
I remember you as a young girl
far too clever to be such a terrible liar.
When your expedition reached
the coast of her homeland
it was YOU who opened fire ON THEM.
You didn't even consider the
possibility that they might be a people!
You wiped them out of the
sky, just because you could!
Tell me, does the Queen
know you're a war criminal?
Who told you that?
-Cal?
-No sir! I didn't, I swear!
He's right. Ortha did!
This is not a game, Miss Harrington!
If you don't want to hear the
truth, why do you even ask?
I don't take kindly to
terrorists on my ship.
Take her into custody.
Strip her down, and see if
she's got any explosives on her.
What?!
Then take her to Dr. McKenzie.
He knows how to make people talk.
Yes, sir.
Wait!
Cal! You must set her free!
She remembers how you treated her wounds
how you... How you tried to protect her…
and how you tried to soothe
her when she was scared
she knows how much you like her.
She says thanks for all the fish!
She is going to sing like a little bird
at the mere sight of the knives, sir.
Something is very odd about her.
She doesn't seem that insane.
Sir? You think she didn't make it all up?
You're going to stay
here and stand guard, Cal.
Don't let anybody near the cage.
Of course, Mr. Welsh.
I'll be upstairs. Doctor McKenzie can
sometimes be a little too enthusiastic.
Of course. Have a good day, Mr. Welsh.
The fish…
nobody... Nobody knows I stole the fish
how the hell does Florence know about it?
Can she really
talk to Ortha?
Ortha?
Is that really your name?
Fuck me backwards!
In all the time I've spent with you,
how could I've been so blind?!
You're...
You are not the beast.
Ortha, I'm the beast.
Fuck me.
Fuck me!
Look at me!
I…
I didn't... Didn't know you're a person!
I thought I was keeping you safe!
I didn't want you to be a prisoner!
I'm so sorry! I...
I love you Ortha! I really do!
Now I'm crying like a little girl.
Please, please don't tell anybody, ok?
Welsh is going to rip my head off.
But if I owe you anything, then it's this.
There. You're free. Go!
I said go!
What are you waiting for?
Oh...
Florence's scarf?
Yes! Yes, I get it! I will, yes.
Now go! GO!
[applause]
[Phone rings]
The Port Ospen Telegraph,
Emmet Crawford speaking.
Yes, I'm the chief editor…
George who?
No. No, we do not reveal our sources
No, what kind of newspaper
do you take us for?
Cause we adhere to the
journalistic code of ethics!
Yes, by all means, go get that
court order if you want to.
Yeah, yeah. Have a good day, sir.
Come in!
Excuse me, Mr. Crawford?
Oh, it's you.
Listen, if you're here to pitch
the Harrington & Welsh story again
save your breath, kid.
That's at least one size
too big for a first year trainee!
Please, boss, hear me out.
I've done some more
research, and I really…
No, Julian
why don't you do something useful?
After the recent attack, the Obituary
department needs all help they can get.
With all due respect, sir, I
came here to be a journalist
and the Telegraph is an institution.
Forgive me for eavesdropping
but I heard how strongly you
defended your source on the phone!
Please, give me a chance!
*sigh* All right, all right!
But just remember this
appealing to my sense of journalistic pride
will work exactly once in your career here
so you'd better make it count!
Now, what you got?
I'm sure I'm onto something.
Shortly after the death
of Peter M. Harrington
Sarkan T. Welsh bought out the
other half of the company from his wife.
The moment he had sole ownership,
he immediately changed the company's direction.
He diversified, founded a
weapons department, and
bought out a number of smaller
companies in the automotive
telegraph and telephone business.
And did you notice there were no
terrorist attacks before the buyout?
Oh, that's all public knowledge.
And it's not surprising, we were
heading directly into a war with Vanos.
You're mixing up cause and effect!
But also, Eva Harrington
sold the part of the company
she had inherited from her
husband way under price!
Well, I guess she's not a very
capable negotiator then, eh?
Don't waste my time, Julian!
Where's the scoop?
I compiled all the reports and eyewitness accounts
of the most recent attack at the airfield.
And they lead me to believe that Florence
Harrington is currently on board of the airship.
Eye witnesses?
Why, eye witnesses make good
headlines, but it's all hearsay, eh?
Where is the proof?
Boss, look at the big picture!
Something isn't right, and
I want to find out what it is.
Please, please let me!
Isn't that what good
journalism is all about?
All right
I hoped you'd figure this out by yourself
let me tell you something
about journalism, hm?
Sit down, kid.
Now, Julian.
You know who pays you, right?
Yes, the company?
Riiight! And who pays the company?
Uhm… our subscribers?
And our advertisers. Which are?
I don't know.
And you call yourself an investigator!
Hah! Snow Chemical
Bank of Astar, Redwood Motors
and Express Telegram.
Now guess who owns the
majority of those companies.
*sigh* Harrington & Welsh.
And guess what they'll do if we start
snooping around Mr. Welsh's
business practices, huh?
*sigh* They'll no longer pay us…
But if we let that hold us back
doesn't that violate all the
rules of good journalism?
Oh, my boy.
Journalism is a job like any other.
You work, you get paid,
you can put food on the table.
Welsh owns this country, like it or not.
And since I like being able
to feed my wife and kids
I don't care what's
right or wrong about that!
Even if you find out
that he's personally fucking
Eva Harrington's daughter
right up there in his
personal mile high club
I don't want to know about it!
Sorry to burst your bubble, kid
but we're a newspaper, not a charity.
Now go and help out
the Obituaries department.
Something tells me they're
going to get even busier…
Neee - naaaa - naaaa - neee - naaaa
Naaaa - naaaa - naaaa
-naaaa - nee-naa-naaa
Ah! A new customer!
How nice!
With whom do I have the honor?
Her name is Harrington.
Florence Harrington, to be exact.
Welcome to my office, Ms. Harrington.
It is a pleasure to meet you.
Who are you?
My name is Dr. McKenzie
and Truth is my One God.
He fears none.
He's without hate.
He never dies.
He's beyond the cycle of birth and death.
He was True in the beginning.
He was True when the ages
commenced and has ever been True.
He is also True now.
Are you ready to meet the One True God?
Ah!
McKenzie!
There are two things I need to know.
Number one: Why is she really here?
Number two: Who told little miss what
happened during the expedition?
And I need you to make sure
she survives the procedure.
Because otherwise I would
have to kill her mother too
and that would make
things really complicated.
And I hate when things get complicated.
Better don't even leave any marks.
Absolutely.
Who in their right mind could cut up
such a beautiful young face anyways?
I'm looking forward to the
report, mister McKenzie.
What...
What are you going to do to me?
Oh… that depends entirely on you.
If I need to know is the truth,
all I need to know is the truth.
And it will all be over in a minute.
Mr. Welsh said you're
not allowed to injure me!
And I don't have to!
This here, for example
is a fresh dose of red
shoelace snake venom.
It's like a fine wine for
the connoisseur of pain.
It starts off light,
ephemeral, almost fruity.
Like a tiny spark singeing
the fur on your arms.
After a while, that will make
way for a more rich
hearty, slightly crunchy taste of pain.
Not unlike to getting your
tail mashed in a revolving door.
And it will keep growing,
bold and unrelenting.
Like somebody is using a drill to
excavate your ingrown toe claw!
And then, finally, the
world will cease to exist
and there is nothing
but pure, intense, brilliant pain!
Now, are you going to talk to me or not?
[knocking]
Uhhh
What the hell is it?
I am serving a customer!
[door opens]
You ordered coffee, Sir?
No, I didn't! Are you new here?
I hate coffee!
Oh, uh, in that case I guess
I don't NEED IT ANYMORE
Aargh! The pain!
It's so good...
Enjoy it while it lasts, pervert!
What?
Cal!
Oh, uh, yeah
C... Cal!
Yes, that's my name.
All right, you need to get out of here.
Quickly!
Cal
I'm so glad that Ortha was right about you.
Let's get... Over with
before someone smells the rat
We don't have time for sentimental drivel.
You're free now, come!
Thank you, Cal.
Don't thank me too early, because you
and I are basically dead men walking
unless we get off this ship real fast!
What about Ortha?
I let her go, and she flew away.
Wow! You really did that?
Listen girl, there are two airplanes
in the back, fueled and ready to go.
I hope your daddy taught you
well to fly these
because I can't!
WHAT? But I've never
flown a plane alone before!
We have the choice between dying
up here, or maybe not dying down there.
But we can't just steal a plane!
Of course we can! No more
excuses. We have to go.
-Go, Go, Go, Go!
-All right! All right! Stop pushing me!
[applause]
Down the hallway, then right!
No, left! That's a shorter way!
How the fuck...
Trust me, I've studied
the plans a thousand times
I know this ship inside out!
[BONK]
Ouch! My Head!
Ah, so much for that!
They must've made a
few revisions since then...
Will you... Ever... Shut up?
Hey you! Stop!
The lower decks have been sealed off.
Security Reasons. I can not let you pass!
Uh, but I have a special
permit from Mr. Welsh.
Oh really? Can I see it?
Oh yeah, sure!
[BONK]
Ouch, ouch, auch, ouch, aahh…
What the hell is going on down there?
Shit, that didn't go well. Runrunrun!!!!
All right. Lock the door!
No use, it only locks from the other side.
But it'll take a moment
to get us ready for takeoff.
Then shut up and do it!
Seats Belts: Closed and Locked
Brakes: Who gives a damn
Circuit breakers: In
Master Switch: On
Are you done yet?
I'm not even half way
through the check list!
What? Check list?
We don't have time for shit like that!
The pre-flight checklist is essential to
make sure no important tasks are forgotten!
The only important task is
to get the fuck out of here!
Can you open the bay doors?
Uh...
I'll try!
Fuel shutoff valve: On
Propeller area: Check
Magnetos: Check
Ignition: Start
Throttle: 1000 rpm
Oil Pressure: Normal
Radios: On
Now we're talking!
Altimeter: Set
Fuel Quantity: Check
Autopilot: I wish
Suction gauge: Check
Engine Instruments: Check
Strobe Lights: On
Now is the time to show
what you are made of!
And I hope it's not cake!
Buckle up and hold on to your butt!
Ah?
Passenger briefing: Complete!
Aiiiiiiieiieieieiieieieieiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii!!
[gunshots]
[applause]
Uhh, Florence?
Um...
Florence!
Florence?
Are we there yet?
Where?
Wherever we are going!
All I know right now is that
we're somewhere above the sea.
The western sea?
I sure hope so, because
we're heading east.
Uhh, it's not going to get
any more specific than that?
What do you expect?
It's pitch black out there.
I have no landmarks, no coastline,
only the goddamn compass.
If we manage to reach the shore,
maybe we can spot something we know, like
the lighthouse at Port Ospen.
But until then, no, it's not going
to get any more specific than that.
Harrington & Welsh Airlines is
terribly sorry for the inconvenience
and our customer service
will gladly give you a full refund!
It's - it's just that our fuel
won't last forever, you know?
Look, Mr. Smartypants
I'm enough of a nervous wreck already
so will you please JUST … SHUT … UP?
Coward.
Asshole.
HRMPF!
Um... Cal? Cal?
I'm sorry. I didn't mean
to snap at you like that.
Oh, fuck you!
I'm thankful you saved me.
Really!
I'm just also very…
very scared.
I'm shaking so much I can
barely fly in a straight line!
Huh! Well, too bad for you!
Come on!
You love to talk big like a man
but the moment someone
dares to come back at you
you stomp off in a huff
like an injured prima donna!
-Ah, right!
-If you're trying to pretend
this doesn't affect you at all
you're doing a pretty bad job.
You're just as frightened as I am.
Woah, if you say so.
What makes it so hard for you to
admit that you actually have a heart?
The heart is weak.
Strength and intelligence makes you a man.
Unbelievable! It's like you WANT
people to think you're an asshole.
You saved my life.
And you set Ortha free.
If that didn't come from the heart
what kind of manly rational bargain
were you hoping to get out of it?
I think we can rule out job security.
What the fuck did you want from me?
I don't have to justify
myself to you or something.
I just had hoped there's at least a
little bit of compassion left in you.
That's a good thing, you know?
[radio] *crackle*
Hotel-Whiskey-3-2-9 - do you read me?
Ah, nono, don't - don't answer them!
Don't they already know where we are?
*crackle* Hotel-Whiskey-3-2-9, we
have located you by your radio beacon.
We are now going to escort
you to Port Ospen Airfield.
*crackle* Reduce airspeed immediately.
What are they going to do if we don't?
Well, first they'll hunt us down.
And then they will kill us.
Ah, oh, and your mother, too, if
they didn't do that already.
Are you kidding me?
I wish I were.
This isn't funny! What the hell
has my mother to do with all this?
More than you think.
You'd better talk straight to me,
or I will personally throw you…
-out of this...
-come on, you...
*crackle* Hotel-Whiskey-3-2-9,
the Harrington & Welsh company has
the exclusive air sovereignty
over the skies of Astar
and we have authority to use
any means necessary to stop you.
This is our final warning.
Okay, this is it. I'm giving up.
No! Don't fall for it!
They think you're a terrorist from Vanos!
Once we get in their
firing range, we're toast!
I'm not a goddamn fighter pilot!
I'm not even a normal pilot!
Ah, shut up and fly!
Oh shit!
Hotel-Whiskey-0-0-1,
Hotel-Whiskey-3-3-0 reporting
radio silence from Hotel-Whiskey-3-2-9.
Requesting further instructions.
Hotel-Whiskey-3-3-0, rogue
pilot is a Vanosian terrorist.
Keep the plane from falling
into the enemy's hands.
Deadly force authorized.
Repeat: Deadly force authorized.
Roger Hotel-Whiskey-0-0-1,
I'm on their tail!
[gunshots]
Oh shit!
[screams]
Aaahhh!
[gunshots]
Aaaah! Aaaah!
Hotel-Whiskey-3-3-0, Stop shooting!
We surrender! I repeat: We surrender!
ARE YOU OUT OF YOUR MIND?
NO, I JUST DON'T WANT TO DIE!
BUT NOW WE ARE GOING TO DIE!
Hotel-Whiskey-3-2-9, good to
hear you've regained your voice.
Let me catch up and I'll escort
you to Port Ospen airfield.
Try anything funny, and I
will blow you out of the sky.
Hotel-Whiskey-3-3-0, roger, will comply.
I don't think they are going to wreck one
of their own planes if they don't have to.
You naive little fool! Welsh
doesn't give a fuck about the plane!
Ahh, he cares about
me, and the things I know!
Oh, it's always about you, isn't it?
But it fucking is! I know a lot
of things most people don't.
Welsh used to trust me
like a member of his family, but now
I'm on a plane with the enemy!
Do you realize what that means?
And you gave all this up… for what?
[gunshots, screams]
What are you doing? You promised
us to stop shooting if we surrendered!
*laughs* What did you expect?
A slap on the wrist, and no dessert?
We don't negotiate with terrorists!
DIE, VANOSIAN SCUM! DIE!
[gunshots]
Aaaah!
Oh shit! We lost the rudder!
Oil Pressure's falling …
Our damn tail's on fire!
Ahh... this is really bad…
The Harrington & Welsh
company wishes you a safe landing! *laugh*
[gunshots]
Ortha?
WHAT THE FUCK?
AAAAAAARGH!
AAAAAAAAAAH!
Ortha!
Over here!
What the hell?
Your flying machine looks unhappy…
Help meeeeee!
-Waaaaa...
-We're not far from the shore.
I think I can carry you…
but only one at a time.
I don't think this thing will
keep flying long enough!
Florence?
Florence! Why aren't you saying anything?
Shut up! I'm talking to Ortha!
Uh, ok. And what does she say?
She says… that you
have to use the parachute!
-Eh...
-What?
-Hey, that's not what I said…
-She will
carry me to the ground,
and then pick you out of the water.
Oh, I can totally do that!
I have very good night vision!
Uh, and why me?
Because you're a strong
man! You can handle it!
Um, yeah, sure! But uh...
it looks kinda wet down there, you know...
Come on Ortha, let's go!
What?
Hey!
Oh, are you sure he will be allright?
Oh yes. A little cool down
will do him good…
Hey!
So that's what I get for getting you
out of that cage, you goddamn bitch!
Uhh, all right then…
one… two…
two and a half…
three…
two…
Ohhh...
oh fuck it!
Geronimoooo!
[applause]
[BOOM]
[door opens]
Mr. French!
Mrs. Harrington!
I've been waiting for you! Come in!
And? Did you get a call from Florence?
I'm afraid I didn't.
*SIGH* I thought this was
just one of her escapades
but she's been gone for a whole day now!
I wish there was anything I could do
but I can't leave the shop during the day.
Especially not when I'm a woman short.
And you don't have to.
I called a few friends,
and I did some research.
And what did you find out?
I've got good news and bad news.
And I've got a short
temper and a rolling pin
if you give me another cliché like that.
Alright, alright.
The airship has not returned to Port Ospen
and there's a rumor Mr. Welsh himself is keeping
the airship in a holding pattern off shore
to keep himself safe from further attacks.
You mean Florence is stuck
on the ship with Mr. Welsh?
Please let that be the bad news!
That was the good news
because it explains
why she is still missing.
But the ship has a radio.
It would have been a simple
thing to send a message.
Have you tried calling
H&W Headquarters?
Yeah, of course I did.
They referred me to
their official statement, and
just refused any further help.
So what is their official statement?
Please don't grab the rolling pin now, but…
Here come the bad news.
I checked with a friend at ANR
and the official statement is that
there is an ongoing investigation against
a group of vanosian terrorists
and that a suspect is being held
in custody on board the airship.
And you think they
might mean Florence?
But she would never do anything like that!
I'm convinved she only wanted to help.
But she hates Welsh.
So he has every reason to
doubt her good intentions.
*sigh* Welsh!
Schemers like him always think
everybody's as treacherous as they are.
Mr. Welsh? You know him, huh?
I wish I didn't.
Oh yeah, that's right. He bought your
husband's company, didn't he?
I'd rather not talk about it.
I just really, REALLY don't want
Florence anywhere near him.
Or on any of his planes.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Harrington,
I didn't mean to pry.
It's good to know you care.
Could you do me a favor?
Of course!
Please call me Eva. And
may I call you Abraham?
Abe. My friends call me Abe.
I'm so touched by all the
support you’re giving me, Abe.
And since I've had little to do but
worry, I made you a little thank you gift.
Awwww! Caramel Chocolates!
Thank you, Eva!
How did you know these were my favorites?
I have my sources, too!
Now it would be a crying shame to go
back home and eat these all by myself.
-Oh?
-Yes, I might
gain a tremendous amount of weight!
And besides, if Florence does call
you should be there to talk to her.
That does make sense.
But I still have to do the cash
check and tidy up the place.
I can help you with
the cleaning if you want.
After the incident at the airfield
my shop was practically deserted anyway.
You're too kind.
Anything for a lovely lady!
Well then… come this way.
If you're as handy with a
mop as you are with a wrench
we should be done in no time!
[applause]
Ortha?
Ortha! Over here!
Argh! ugh …
Cal! You made it! Are you alright?
I thought I was freezing to death!
W - Where the hell are we?
I can barely see the
lighthouse in the north, I think.
Oh great. I hope Vanos is as
safe as they say these days.
There seems to be a small farm nearby.
Maybe they will let you stay over night!
And there's still some light in the house!
Let's go!
No! No! We're fugitives!
What if they report us?
We're going to hide in the
barn and be off before sunrise!
They'll never know we were there.
Ahh, damn, it's locked.
That means we have to break in!
But that's illegal!
The fact we're still
breathing is illegal, ok?
Look over there!
That drain pipe! That will be our way in.
Oh, that's just stupid.
-I'll just walk over and knock-
-No!
You're going to wait right here!
Bloody women …
You need something done,
you've got to do it yourself.
I'm already wet to the bones, so
what could possibly go wrong?
Uh-oh...
Ew! Gross!
Is it going to stop
Caligula, the Savior?
No! It will only make him stronger!
Blergh!
Cat-eating tentacles!
Aaah, tentacle-eating rats!
Eh, that was...
That was weird!
I enjoyed that more than I should have!
Thank you for helping
me, my friend! Uh? Friends?
Aaaaagrh!
So much for being nice for a change.
Damn! This looked so
much easier in the comic books!
But turning back is not an option.
Caligula the Savior is not going to make
himself the laughing stock of the party!
Forward ever, backwards
nevAAAAAAAAARGH!
Aaaarhhh!
[applause]
Aaaarhg, this is so...
Whait, what is this?
I just don't really know, I think
Ah shit!
Well, that's my humble barn.
I wish I could offer you
something better, but...
All we need is a roof above our heads.
Thank you so much, Will!
We do value our
hospitality here in Vanos.
Can I invite you for breakfast tomorrow?
It ain't often a plane
crashes in my backyard!
Of course!
Now where in tarnation
is that friend of yours?
Uhm … good question.
When we left, he was just
checking out the drain pipe.
Drain pipe?
My barn ain't got a drain!
Help!
Heeeelp me!
That him?
I'm afraid so.
Cal? CAL!? Where are you?
Uh, I'm down here!
That came from outside…
What the hell are you waiting for?
Well, I'll be damned…
What the hell are you doing down there?
Eh, stop asking stupid
questions and get me out!
I'm on it! Hang in tight!
Allright!
Who are you, and what
are you doing in my toilet?
Name's Cal.
Royal pipe inspection service.
Did you know you have a serious
tentacle problem down there?
Very funny Cal, very funny!
But now it's time to GO
INSIDE AND TAKE A NAP!
I reckon Mr. Pipe Inspector here
surely could use a bath.
Well, I'll go and get a tub!
Only if it's not too much trouble!
Eh
it's allright!
I'll be back in a sec.
That was the most embarrassing
thing that ever happened to me!
-But I…
-No buts!
-You almost ruined it!
-What?
When will you stop throwing
your goddamn weight around?
Who are you trying to impress? Me?
I was... Only... Trying to help!
You smell like a maggot
infested raccoon
rotting at the bottom of a rain barrel!
FOR TWO WEEKS!
No, I...
IN THE SUN!
Yeah, but... Right, yeah, I
WITH THE LID ON!
Listen to me!
No!
How about you just shut up for once?
Think you can do that?
Good!
fuck's sake!
Don't be so mad at him.
He was just trying to help.
Oh, you find this pretty funny, don't you?
Actually … yes!
Pipe inspector…
Are you picking my mind again?
No, you're just still thinking very loudly!
Here we are!
Fresh bath for the deep diver!
Perfect. Thank you.
Eh, you're welcome!
Well, time for me to hit the sheets.
I'll be seeing you only
in the morning, allright?
-Good night, Will!
-Night!
You know what's funny?
You two-leggers have fur,
but you're still wearing clothes.
Why's that?
Oh, there's more than one reason.
They protect us, they look nice, and…
they keep things hidden.
What kind of things?
Uhm…
male and female things?
Oooooh!
Seeing him naked arouses you!
ORTHA! Those are my most private feelings!
Oh, the images…
so that's how you two-legged people…
ORTHAAAAAA!
Why are you so ashamed about everything?
I mean, how about you?
Aren't you curious how
it feels when WE do it?
NO!
Oh, what a shame. It's really good!
You just don't want me
to sleep tonight, do you?
Are you two talking about me again?
Of course.
The whole world revolves
around you, after all.
Oh for fucks sake!
Yes, I screwed up.
There, I admitted it, is that
what you wanted to hear?
Well...
It's a start.
Fine. Anything else?
See, he's not so bad!
Let's see if you can get anything
out of him to open up a little more.
You would make a great psychotherapist!
Well, I am, in a way.
So... Cal?
After you let Ortha free…
why did you come back to rescue me?
You were my only chance
to get off the ship alive, so...
I don't think that was the reason.
Something seemed to cause him grief.
I even saw him crying.
I had to push him a little
bit in the right direction.
Cal, be honest with me.
But I am…
Wait.
Damn. Ortha, right?
She told you everything?
Oh yeah, just keep
kicking me while I'm down
I'm well used to that!
Um...
Does she… know what I'm saying?
She understands everything I understand
as long as we're touching.
Fucking Brilliant!
Here I am, naked, smelling like shit
and there are you, with your living
lie detector, judging me smug as fuck.
[laughter, applause]
So much for your moral superiority!
Oh, I'm sorry!
It comes naturally, I
didn't think anything of it!
But you're right.
Whoops.
I didn't save you to save myself.
I did it because I owed it to you.
Both of you.
I had to make right what I did wrong!
I love you, Ortha!
You are the most magnificent
being I have ever seen.
When the bombs exploded, I was
more scared for your life than my own!
I feel so guilty for not
realizing you are a person!
I didn't have the right
to keep you in a cage!
I spent so much time with you, but I
was too blind to see what you really are.
I'm so sorry, Ortha.
I hope you can forgive me.
Oh!
So that's what he tried to
tell me back in the cargo hold!
Oh, If I had only known!
Poor Cal!
There goes my last shred of dignity.
Actually
that was the most dignified
thing I've ever heard you say.
And of course Ortha forgives you.
You were very brave!
Thank you.
You...
You too.
I'm...
I'm sorry for being so mean to you, I …
What was that? What... What did I do?
What the hell?!
Oh no, not again!
Cal… I saw your thoughts!
Your feelings! Everything!
What?!
You...
And...
Wait!
You thought about my father!
-I...
-Why
did you think about my father?
You s… You saw that?
Cal… WHY?
I...
It is quite unpleasant to be
overwhelmed with someone else's thoughts
but
it's gets better as soon as
your mind begins to take it all in.
It felt the same way it did when
you touched me for the first time.
But how can this be?
Cal has touched you countless times
and there never was a connection!
Uh... A connection? Is that how it feels?
I think it's you, Florence.
You mean…
if I touch you…
and someone touches me…
Let's do it again!
No!
Talking to me has always
been one of his greatest desires.
We should let him. I think so.
No!
It felt like a steam train
running right through my head!
His mind is a mess right now.
If he could somehow
manage to calm himself down
it won't nearly be so bad.
Pretty pretty please?
All right.
But there's something you must know.
Unlike her, we have not learned
to keep our thoughts to ourselves.
You might tell us your darkest
secrets, your most intimate desires
things you never wanted anybody to know.
Are you ready to pay the price?
I've never been so ready.
All right. Close your eyes.
Clear your thoughts. Relax.
Now take my hand.
Hello, Caligula, my savior!
Hello Ortha.
I... I love you.
I know. I can feel it.
And...
And I - I have to tell
you something, Florence.
The death of your father was no accident.
Welsh had him murdered.
[applause]
I can't believe Welsh killed father just
so he could have the company to himself!
Does he have no heart?
Feelings can be so confusing!
With Welsh, I always knew where I stood.
He said what he meant
and meant what he said.
Very rational man, I admired that.
I'm not very emotional myself.
You're lying to yourself, Cal
but don't lie to me.
Right now, you're bursting with emotion
and you don't hide them well.
I'm sorry.
No.
I am sorry.
For what your mother did to you.
And your father.
HOW DO YOU KNOW ABOUT THAT?
I NEVER TOLD ANYONE!
You did.
To me. Right now.
I warned you.
Keeping your thoughts to
yourself takes a lot of restraint.
W - what else do you know about me?
That you cried every time
your mother abused you.
And your father wouldn't believe you.
He'd threaten you if
you didn't stop crying.
Yes! 'Stop crying!' he said.
'Or I'll give you a reason to cry.'
That's terrible!
I don't want your pity!
Pain is a good teacher, you know.
And talking doesn't make
anything better, so why bother?
I didn't want to hurt you, I swear.
I can't read your
thoughts against your will.
And...
no, Florence, he does
not have a crush on me
because I'm a giant
furry surrogate mother.
Stop thinking that. It's not true.
Oh...
Did I?
You both have a lot to learn.
Your thoughts are as
loud as screaming children.
This is intimate, so be
gentle with each other.
And don't judge.
So, how did you end up working for Welsh?
An ad in the newspaper,
if you can believe it.
I wanted to leave this mess
of a family as soon as possible.
I applied shortly after
Welsh took over the company
and they gave me the
grand title of deputy assistant
to the secretary of Mr. Welsh.
I made coffee, ran errands,
and I never asked questions.
That must have impressed him.
And you never felt any remorse?
I was his assistant, not his hitman!
Still, you knew everything.
I didn't make those decisions,
I just had to do what I was told!
It is all alright Cal.
We all can't change our past
but we can change our future.
This is awkward.
I used to be pretty
much the opposite of you.
All heart and no head.
Always wanting to make
everyone around me happy.
And you can't imagine how
many times that was a stupid idea.
Don't believe you were all wrong.
I wish I was more like you.
Well
a little bit at least.
And if you want me to be your
giant teddy bear every now and then
I'll be happy to oblige.
I DID NOT JUST THINK THAT!
Loud and clear.
Ah fuck me in a hammock!
Oh come here, you
poor two-legged creature.
And what about me?
And you too.
Let's call it a night and
share some dreams, shall we?
[applause]
Hello my little friends!
Isn't it a wonderful day?
Come here, I have a treat for you!
There you go!
Oops!
I'm sorry!
Let me just put this over here…
Your Majesty, Mr. Welsh awaits
the privilege of your company.
Punctual as ever.
Show him in.
Your wish is my
command, your majesty.
Mr. Welsh.
Your Majesty.
You may approach.
I do hope you're bringing good news.
Damn butterflies!
Oh yes, your Majesty.
The banquet manager and I
have put our heads together
and we've come up with a way to
make the upcoming state ceremony
even more spectacular.
Indeed?
Your plans must be sensational
if you presume to charge even
more to the Royal Treasury.
Nononono, absolutely not, your Majesty.
Here, please have a look.
Huh!
Okay...
So... Hmm...
Hmm... hmm… hmm…
I see…
an even bigger cake …
if you insist …
more electric lights …
a gold plated cage for the beast?
Really?
It looks magnificent!
Everybody will want one!
That may be, but the
budget remains fixed.
The House of Astar
should be well presented
but we will NOT be
remembered for wasteful excess.
Do we understand each other?
Your Majesty will be remembered for
ensuring the safety and prosperity of Astar.
The cage and the animal are my personal
gift for your Majesty's collection.
All preparations will of course
be done at my own expense.
In our experience, nothing
costs more than a gift.
Presumably there's a price that
you didn't write on this piece of paper?
Well … we have to make
few small adjustments
to the list of suppliers
and a slight change in the schedule
but that's it.
Such as?
I have talked to Eva Harrington
and I'm afraid supplying a cake of
these dimensions are beyond her capacity.
So that commission would have to go to
Cantrell's Bakery in Chultberg instead.
And the gold plating on the cage
will take three extra days to finish
so it would be great if we could postpone …
No!
I'm sorry, your Majesty?
Apology accepted, Mister Welsh.
We're pleased you regret
bothering the butterflies
with such disagreeable demands.
Your Majesty. I don't think I understand.
As you know, Mister Welsh,
you serve the House of Astar
and the Royal Court is not
one of your carnival attractions.
You must be so embarrassed
for thinking you could dictate
the terms of our arrangement.
I assure your Majesty
that all my intentions are only
in the Crown's best interest!
Of course, Mister Welsh
and your service is appreciated.
Such as your impeccable consultations
of the imminent uprising in Vanos.
Do you remember?
The one that never happened?
Oh your highness
we've been through this before.
I swear by my life, I never
withheld any information from you!
Vanos was a peaceful country
its borders undisputed for centuries.
We marched in like invaders!
Tens of thousands of innocent
civilians paid with their lives.
And the Kingdom of
Astar has been re-united
something that nobody had thought possible.
And all thanks to you, my Queen
and your wise decision.
That is the official version.
And the version that we
both come off best with.
And that is the only reason
you're not dangling from
the oak tree on timber hill yet.
You're a cunning man
and in these troubled times,
we value your connections.
And you are very useful to the royal court.
But don't treat your
Queen like a fool ever again.
The war on Vanos was one of the
biggest profit you ever made.
Your own little empire only
exists because we allow it.
And I am eternally grateful for
your generosity, your Highness.
The Kingdom of Astar prospers.
Our cities grow.
At some point, our island will be too small
and colonization will become inevitable.
Our interests are well aligned with yours
right now.
But in the great equation
of our country's history
the Crown is the constant.
And you are merely a variable.
Of course, your Highness.
The date of the state ceremony stands.
And we will not break our long and
excellent relationship with the Harringtons
over a few more levels on a cake.
We appreciate that you so graciously
agree to the wisdom of these decisions.
Thank you for the paper, Mister Welsh.
We're certain the moths
will gladly accept your gift.
Uhg!
If Mr. Welsh please would
follow me to the door.
Would it be possible to use the … um …
mobile phone before I leave?
I have a few business arrangements
to make for the state ceremony.
Certainly. Please wait here.
Heavens!
Pardon me, sir
there was something
funny with the cable, sir.
Thank you.
Now, if I could have some privacy please.
Important royal business matters.
Of course, sir.
Hello? Operator?
Please give me number 4441.
Thank you.
Hi there, it's me, Welsh.
I'm using the Phone in the Palace
so I'm pretty sure nobody is listening.
They are not going to
postpone the reception.
That means you have
three days to get Ortha back.
Ortha.
The beast.
Yes.
I know!
I don't care how.
It has to work!
We got away with the whole Vanos affair
but if we want to do it again
I need the Queen to trust
me, no questions asked.
We'll be safe once past
the point of no return
but that's a long way off.
Call the think tank.
Let them do their thing,
propaganda, bribes
let them stage something!
as long as the Queen thinks
we saved her royal hide.
No, that's not all.
About the Harringtons.
Florence is dead
and that means Eva Harrington
needs to be terminated, ASAP
What?!
Florence is still alive?
And Cal too?
Where are they?
Why don't you tell me that earlier?
I KNOW I TALK A LOT, THAT'S
BECAUSE I HAVE A LOT TO SAY!
So what are you waiting for, kill them!
Yes, all of them, including Eva!
Because otherwise they'll spill the beans
that's why YOU MORON!
ARRGH!
[applause]
Ortha?
Yes?
What exactly does "Guardian
of the Realm" mean?
It's not nearly as exciting as it sounds.
It's my duty to fly along the
border and report anything unusual.
From bad weather to unexpected guests.
Oh, so there is more than one realm?
Five, in fact.
Dumarth, Onedoth, Klam
Serotho and the desert in the south
nobody lives there.
Does the continent have a name, too?
We just call it 'home'.
And that's also its name.
How do your people live?
I mean …
do you have houses? Streets?
Do you know numbers and letters?
Of course we have houses.
And proper ones, of course.
Not as tiny as yours!
We also have streets, but
only for moving heavy goods.
Why walk when you have wings?
The best houses are at
the cliffside of the mountains
and there's no path leading there.
You have to fly.
But nobody sees that as an inconvenience.
We're much more versatile
in the air than we are on foot.
And yes, we know numbers
not that I'm very good with them, though.
And your diet?
Do you only eat fish and fresh meat?
We cook, we have many
ways to preserve food.
How else are we supposed to eat in winter?
I prefer fresh meat, though.
So if you're hungry,
you have to go hunting?
If I have the time,
and friends to go with …
we hunt more for fun
than for anything else.
It's a lot more convenient to just
buy your food at the town market.
Also, the quality is so much better!
How do you talk to each other?
I mean, do you always have to hold hands?
And what if you want some privacy?
Our minds are our voices.
We don't need to touch
if we want to be heard
far away, we think loudly
and when we want to
keep something to ourselves
we think quietly.
Unlike you two.
This sounds so fascinating!
And the images …
I wish I could visit your realm one day.
It's like nothing I've ever seen before!
It's a beautiful place.
But don't let that deceive you.
We have our share of trouble and politics.
In that regard, we're not that
much different than you two-leggers.
Can you lie to each other?
Are there criminals?
Why am I not surprised you
are the one to ask that question?
We can lie, which makes justice
as difficult for us as it is to you.
When someone is accused of a crime
they're brought to the
trial before the elders
and can defend themselves.
Only in extreme cases can they be forced
to expose their most private thoughts
and memories to the court of the elders.
I thought you can't read
someone's mind against their will?
Nor can I speak to someone's
mind against their will.
But the elders can, when
joining their minds together.
It's a brutal and painful procedure
especially if the subject resists.
Some have even lost their minds.
It's very scary.
There's a huge political debate going on
whether this procedure is a necessary evil
or if it should be
outlawed once and for all.
I don't even want to know
what they could do to our minds …
Your thoughts are so frail and brittle.
Talking to you is like walking on thin ice.
But I like you.
I could never harm you.
Besides, we are not a violent people.
If we cause pain to one another
we can feel it like it was our own.
If that doesn't stop you
you have a heart of stone!
Like Welsh.
You can't imagine how much I wish I could
make him feel the pain he caused.
That would teach him a lesson.
I'm afraid we'll have to find another
way to make him pay for his crimes.
And you know a lot more
about those than I do!
Yeah, we're not going to run out of
things to talk about anytime soon …
Someone needs to write a book about this!
I didn't know you could write!
Oh shut up, woman.
thbbbbbbt!
[applause]
Yeaaaaaah!
We are the dragon riders of Vanos!
And we are going to avenge
our brothers and sisters!
Why do I always have to sit in the back!
Because you're stupid!
No I'm not!
Yes you are!
You don't even know how to ride a dragon!
Oh yes I do!
No you don't!
Just wait, I'll show ya!
Rarrrgh!
Hey! Hey, be gentle!
Ortha's not a toy!
Mommy!
It's enough!
Out with you, all three.
Out out out!
Go play on the beach!
Can we keep her?
She's so fluffy!
No, we can't.
She's not a pet, you know?
Oh man …
Goodbye, Mrs. Ortha!
Ah, it's so nice to have
children in the house again …
but sometimes silence IS golden.
Ortha says they're adorable
and you should be glad
they don't grow wings.
Oh my god, yes!
Are they all yours?
Oh no, no, no.
They're orphans of the war.
Will is teaching them how to read and write
and be good farmhands.
My own son moved out ages ago.
And what about you?
Are you still living with your mom?
Yes. And she's
probably dying of sorrow
not knowing where I am.
Do you have a telephone?
I'm afraid not.
Next one is at the post office in
St. Eliza, about 15 miles away.
Damn.
Then we need to find
someone to take us there.
Huh...
Do you think the people here will help us?
Oh, why shouldn't they?
Because for them I'm probably the most
Anti-Vanosian guy save for Welsh himself?
*sigh* Oh rubbish.
It don' matter who you are
it matters what ya' do!
They may be patriotic
but they're not stupid.
When they see Ortha, they
have no reason to doubt you.
I'm back, honey!
Oh!
Hello everybody!
Come in and have a seat!
Awrite!
Sorry for dragging you
in like this by your tails.
Let me make y'all
aquaintances to my guests
This here is Florence Harrington
she is the gilr of Peter Harringtonn.
And that next sir here is Caligula Davis
he was former assistant
of that Welsh fella.
And that's miss Ortha
neither beast nor a dragon,
no matter what she may look like.
Then what in the land's name is she?
She is a person.
Her people have a highly developed culture
but they communicate with their minds only.
For some reason she can only speak to me.
Well, and those who I can touch.
Uh, I wonder how much effort it's
taking them to not stare at me.
Oh shush!
That sounds pretty fantastic.
How do we know you're
not making it all up?
Uhmmmm…
Thank you, I guess...
Anyway, I accidentally
discovered that Ortha is telepathic.
She begged me to help her
and that's how I ended
up in Welsh's airship
when it took off after the
bomb attacks in Port Ospen.
I was Ortha's guard at the time.
Don't ask me how, but Florence
managed to convince me to switch sides
and set Ortha free.
We tried to flee from Welsh's
airship in one of his fighter planes
but his men shot us down.
Only thanks to Ortha's
help we managed to survive.
Their plane crashed right into my backyard!
Well, since you're
obviously holding up so well
why don't you go back to
Astar where you came from?
Because Welsh wants us dead.
That's almost as bad as the
Queen herself wanting us dead.
Astar is no longer a
place for us to go home to.
Now isn't that ironic?
Certainly not for Ortha.
She's stranded thousands
of miles away from home
in a world she does not understand.
Vanos versus Astar means nothing to her.
I still don't trust ye.
Did you know the Queen never
wanted war against Vanos?
Welsh conned her into it.
What?!
I knew this would get you interested.
Father's early planes were designed
for entirely peaceful purposes.
Welsh, however, figured
they would earn a lot more
by selling them as instruments of war.
When father refused, Welsh
sabotaged his plane, and
he died.
Welsh then forced my mother to
sell him father's half of the company.
He threatened to kill me if she refused
or the truth ever came to light.
And now, what sells
weapons better than a war?
Welsh spread rumors about a huge
secret armament happening in Vanos.
Bombs exploded at strategic
places in Astarian cities.
And soon everybody was in
fear over the threat from Vanos.
A threat well fabricated enough
to convince the Queen
she needs a royal air force.
And that's how Welsh became
the richest man in the world.
If that were true, history
would have to be rewritten!
After the war, Welsh needed new
threats to keep his business running.
Ortha's kin is that new threat.
That's why they didn't
kill her like the others
but brought her back
as a gift to the Queen.
They didn't expect her to be sentient.
And it occurred to no one that
they had just slaughtered an entire …
ARGH! ORTHA! PLEASE!
What?
I'm sorry …
I'm so sorry.
I … I'm trying... I'm doing my best to
to keep my feelings to myself, but
the horrors of that day...
I couldn't hold it back!
It's alright, Ortha!
We're here for you...
let's... Let's think about something else...
W... what...
just... happened?
Ortha was just overwhelmed
by the memories of her brother
dying before her in a hailstorm of bullets
and she inadvertently
shared it with me.
For a moment it was like
I had been there myself.
The world needs to know about this!
And then what?
You think they're be all 'well,
oh pardon me folks, my bad', and
give us our land back?
No, but the blood of our friends
and families is on Welsh's hands.
If there's a way to make
him burn in hell for his sins
I'll be first in line.
Us against the most
powerful man in the world?
That's... That's hopeless!
Ooh, powers can be taken away
just as easily as they were granted.
Yeah, but who could do that
except maybe the Queen herself?
Exactly!
-Are you crazy?
-No!
Do you see how Ortha's
memories affected Florence
when she remembered the massacre?
If we can give Queen Irdis the
same profound first hand experience
of Ortha's horrible memories
she is not going to
question what she will see.
Intruding someone's mind against their will
it's - it's a big taboo among my people!
It can even make them go mad!
But he's right, isn't he?
Probably.
Look.
Tonight will be the first
new moon of summer.
Like every year, the
Queen is going to visit
the shrine of the forefathers at
the south end of the palace garden
lay down a single white rose and
pray for the goodwill of their spirits.
It's going to be dark, and
she is going to be all alone.
Nobody is going to expect
anybody coming from the air.
So he wants me to swoop
down on her and carry her away?
It's not that easy!
I don't want to hurt her!
If the slightest thing
goes wrong, we're dead
and even if I manage to bring
her here and share my memories...
we have no idea how she's going to react!
Yeah. Yeah, it's crazy to bet
everything on one card like that!
Does anybody have a better idea?
*sigh* Listen.
If we don't act now, you will soon be dead
and Ortha ends up as an exhibit
in the Queen's zoological garden.
Welsh is out to get you as we speak.
Ortha?
Technically, I could do it.
It's against my innermost beliefs though.
It just doesn't feel right.
But I also feel how desperate you are.
And I - I don't have a better plan either.
Do you think it will work?
It could.
Then I'll trust you. I will do it.
I can drive you all to Port Ospen.
My truck fits two horses...
or one Ortha.
Oh, can someone please
bring the children back in?
At least they thought I was a dragon...
I'll be coming with you.
And me too.
Meet me tonight at nine, behind my house.
[applause]
Good evening everyone!
Are we ready to go?
I'd like to go through the steps
again one more time before we start.
Yes, that's a good idea.
I don't have a very
good feeling about this.
Alright. So here's the plan.
Correct me if I'm wrong, Illyan.
Florence, Cal and Ortha
get on the back of the truck
and Illyan drives them all into the city.
Check.
Illyan then stops at the north end
of the park, behind the hedge.
Check.
Then right before midnight
miss Ortha flies northeast,
over the palace wall
and does some circles till that she
can spot the Queen down in the garden.
Yes, correct.
Miss Ortha goes down, grabs
the Queen, and gets her to car
Cal and Florence
are going to watch her then
and Illyan drives everyone back.
Yup.
I reckon we got about an hour or two
before anyone will notice the Queen's gone.
Which means that if we don't
manage to bring her back until then
we're fucked six ways to Sunday.
Oh, that's a new one.
Okay, Ortha, ready to go now?
I'm a bit worried about the wind
spot landings are tricky with
heavy crosswinds. Even for me.
But I'll make do.
Then let's get on the truck.
I... I really don't like
small enclosed spaces.
I've been in a cage for too long.
We'll be by your side
the whole time. Relax.
There's nothing to worry about.
If you say so...
Wait... Wait... something
doesn't smell right...
GET BEHIND ME! IT'S A TRAP!
Don't shoot... we need her alive!
I said don't shoot at her!
Aaaaaaaaaaaaaaa!
Bloody tranquilizer is not working!
You can do it, Ortha!
Oh f.. Shit, I'm out of ammo!
Why didn't you shoot the tires?
BECAUSE WE WOULD BE DEAD NOW!
No!
Ortha! No, Ortha!
Don't give in!
You have to get off the truck, now!
Come on!
They...
I think they poisoned me...
-What?
-I can't move my legs any more...
NO! ORTHA!
Run!
Run, you fools!
No! Florence, help me pull!
Come one!
She's way too heavy!
Cal!
I'm not going to let you go!
Ever!
Cal...
this is our last chance to run!
RUN YOU IDIOT
[applause]
♪ Why don't we do this more often ♪
♪ Why don't we ♪
♪ Just what we're doing tonight ♪
♪ What a lovely night ♪
Oh damn, my glass is empty again.
Let me fix that.
This is really fine wine.
It must have cost you a fortune!
Not really.
You know what's better than being the
official confectioner of the royal family?
Being the favorite confectioner
of the royal family's staff.
Lowly working folk like
us take care of each other.
I see! - *hic!*
I have to restrain myself
or I won't be able to walk you home!
Who said I'm going home tonight?
Oh!
But don't you have to work tomorrow?
Every single person in this
goddamn bakery is always late!
Why can't I be the one
who's late for once?
Too right.
To hell with work! Cheers!
Cheers!
What on earth is going on out there?
The fire station is around the corner
you get used to it after a while.
There are so many ways
to set your house ablaze...
Forgetting the pot in the
oven, smoking in bed...
Did you know more than 5000
people die that way every year?
[Radio] Ladies and Gentlemen
we interrupt this program to
bring you a special news bulletin.
An ongoing series of explosions is
still shaking the city of Port Ospen.
The police department reported
another detonation around 11 pm
at a bakery on Lewse Road
- Lewse Road? That's my shop!
- following the attack on the Peter M. Harrington
-Abe, that is MY SHOP!
-airfield the day before.
-For god's sake! It is!
-The building is on fire
and has partly collapsed.
-Florence...
-What?
Something must have happened to Florence!
Eva, wait!
What does Florence have to do with this?
She isn't even here!
You don't understand!
Damn right I don't!
Those were no terrorists.
It was Welsh.
He wants to kill me!
Because Florence is dead!
-Why?
-I already told you
I can't talk about it!
Eva, please, I'm on your side.
Please let me help you.
Please trust me.
You're right.
It's too late anyway.
Peter was a genius, you know?
If he had an idea, he would
spend days locked up in his office.
And the more people told him
that something was impossible
the more stubbornly he would move forward.
But a businessman he was not.
He knew Welsh from his university days
and with his MBA degree he seemed
to be a good man to partner up with.
At first, all was great.
Welsh secured funding, ran
the books and hired new staff.
Peter was happy as long
as we didn't have to starve.
Welsh, however, wanted more.
When the kingdom began
to arm itself against Vanos
Welsh saw a golden opportunity.
When Peter refused, Welsh threw a tantrum.
'Unfit for business, unfit
for life', that's what he yelled
and then he slammed
the door in Peter's face.
And he hated Peter so
much that he had him killed?
It wasn't even hate.
For him it was more like a
change in business strategy.
Removing the single point
of failure from the process.
All he had to do was to disable
the fuel gauge on Peter's plane.
A murderer AND a coward...
Welsh took me aside during the funeral
and told me what he did.
And that Florence would
soon share Peter's fate
if I didn't voluntarily
relinquish my inheritance.
What stopped him from
killing both of you anyways
after he got what he wanted?
I'm not sure.
Maybe my relationship to the royals.
I've been living in fear ever since.
And I tried to keep Florence as safe and as
far away from anything that Welsh controls.
That he tries to kill me now
after so many years of
silence can't be a coincidence.
Something must have happened that
made him think he can no longer control me.
Something must have happened to Florence!
If that is true, you should stay here.
Nobody knows you're here.
Don't let Welsh know
that you're still alive.
And then... what next, Abe?
What about Florence?
And my house?
I can't just sit here and do nothing!
My life just went up in
flames, don't you understand?
We'll find a a way.
We're the good guys, Eva.
The good guys always find a way.
[applause]
Florence, Cal, what on earth happened?
Illyan betrayed us!
We were ambushed by Welsh's henchmen.
They shot everyone down.
Oh my Lord! Will?
Will!
He's the only one still breathing.
Everyone else is dead.
Illyan, that bastard!
I always knew something
was sketchy about him...
Will!
WILL! Talk to me!
DAMN!
You two stay here and have an eye on him
I'll go get the doctor!
Be quick, he's bleeding to death!
Then do something about it!
Cal, come over here and help me!
What am I supposed to do?
Get me some fresh towels.
Allright.
So what now?
We're going to make a tourniquet.
A... A what?
A tourniquet!
They taught me how to make people bleed
not the other way around!
What the fuck is a tourniquet?
I'll fold up this towel
and put it on the wound.
Now take the other towel,
and tie it down really tight.
The pressure stops the bleeding, allright?
Allright.
Good!
I think that's pretty much
all we can do for now.
How... How do you know all this?
Father insisted I take the courses.
I was the only girl in the class.
And the boys beat each other up
who's gonna be the next dummy!
Wait...
Is he still breathing?
What?
No!
Nonono, we're losing him!
Shit.
One. Two. Three.
Four. Five. Six
Seven. Eight. Nine.
I am the one who
deserves to die, not Will!
I am guilty of this whole mess
One.
as much as Welsh himself is guilty!
Six. Seven. Eight. Nine.
I used to be one of his
men! How could I? HOW?
I'm not going to give up on him just yet!
Jack and Sly are gone! What is
going to become of their families?
Their children?
Working for Welsh always
felt like a game, but suddenly
it's all dead serious!
I did whatever Welsh wanted
to whoever he wantet me do it to, but
I never felt anything for them.
But these are my friends!
I'm such a piece of shit!
Oh will you shut up
and stop pitying yourself!
This is hard enough as it is!
Yes!
That did it!
Get in there, move, move, move!
Thank god you're here!
Don't set your expectations too high.
I had to pluck him from
under a table at the tavern.
Why can't a man enjoy
his time after work?
Listen, my husband is dying
if you want to be able to enjoy
anything in your life after today
you'd better MOVE YOUR
BUTT AND DO YOUR WORK!
Okay.
lets see...
The victim...
No! The patient...
he looks kinda miserable.
What happened to him?
Well, he got shot at.
Three hits, one to the
shoulder, two to the thigh.
Good, good!
What?!
Yeah, no vital organs in there.
Does he bleed from both sides?
Uhm... yeah, kinda...
Lucky Bastard.
What?
What are you talking about,
he's in a goddamn coma!
Sure, he's lost a lot of blood.
But it means the bullets
went straight through.
A lot less damage that way, and
you wouldn't want me to poke
around inside of him right now!
Let's see.
Ah, yeah. This right here.
Eh, honey
if you would be so
nice to hold this for me.
Thank you.
Now...
Step back.
Ready...
Set...
Go!
Ouch!
Ha-ha, bullseye!
Fifty points!
Good thing he's unconscious.
[applause]
A stiff drink gives you a steady hand!
What is this?
Shal...
shaline sholushion.
Not as good as fresh blood
but it'll give the old
heart something to pump.
If we manage to pour more of
this in than blood comes out of there
he'll make it through the night.
Now I... I need a bowl of water
and a bottle of stroooooong alcohol.
Allright! I'll get the water.
This is for disinfection, right?
Damn straight! Give me that!
HURGH!
I guess that's all the help
we are going to get for tonight.
Yes, but I think I can take over from here.
Stay strong Mae.
Stay strong.
Um...
Hey.
How are you doing?
I've never felt so useless.
Yeah
I know that feeling.
When my life suddenly changed
from airplanes to cream puffs
it was just the same.
Our only friend out here is
dying on the kitchen table
even the goddamn shitfaced
doctor is more useful than I am.
I used to be strong
and in control of my life.
Now look at me.
For the most part of your life,
you only had to follow orders.
You didn't give a damn about
anything because you didn't have to.
But now you do!
This is how it feels to care!
You're finally taking control of your life!
Then why the fuck am I so scared?!
Finding a new purpose
in life is a scary thing.
So what is my purpose?
Why settle for one?
For me, there are so many
things that give life meaning!
Happy ones, like supporting my
mother or bringing joy to my friends.
Dark ones, like avenging
the death of my father.
Or simple ones, like
just enjoying the day.
The only thing I can think
about right now is Ortha!
Then Ortha it is.
She has definitely
awoken something in you.
Something that has lain
dormant for way too long.
Something beautiful!
You know what separates
good people from bad people?
The good ones can change
and they will always find a way.
If there were a way to save
Ortha, I wouldn't be sitting here!
But there might be!
Let's get some sleep.
And tomorrow, we're going
to make a few phone calls.
[applause]
Eva...
Hey, Eva...
come on...
wake up!
Mmm...
Hrmblbrmglbmlml
-I've got great news!
-What?
What is it?
Florence just called!
Really?
She's in St. Eliza
she's free, and she's doing fine!
Oh, thank god...
is she still on the line?
Can I talk to her?
Uhh sorry, she called about an hour ago.
Why didn't you wake me up right away?
You lay awake the whole night.
I didn't have the heart to wake you up.
Besides, she was calling
from the post office, and
she had a long line behind her.
But I've got the motorbike fixed up
and I'm going to pick her up
in St. Eliza in about an hour.
So she'll soon be here and you'll
be able to talk to her in person.
She's got one hell of a story to tell.
Did she tell you what happened?
Naa, only the essentials.
She escaped, she's fine
she knows everything about
the conspiracy against you
and she needs our help to end it!
Wait, what?
Yeah, you heard me right.
She has a plan, and
she insists we play along.
We'll see about that.
She wants us to get her
and a friend into the palace.
They would still let you
in, wouldn't they?
Only when I'm making a delivery.
But my kitchen was in my house
and my house went up in flames.
But if you could, you could get us in?
Maybe.
Hah! Excellent.
I once fixed a friend's car for
free, and now he kinda owes me a favor.
His sister owns Cantrell's
Bakery in Herringstown
and she has everything we need.
She expects you to be there at noon.
Abe, I'm not even fully awake yet...
Oh, and since you won't
be able to do it alone
I've also sent the neighbor's boy
to wake up all of your employees
and send them to Herringstown right away.
Be honest, Abe
the only reason you didn't wake me
up was that you were afraid I'd stop you.
This is crazy, even by
Florence's standards!
Do you think she'd have
accepted no as an answer?
She's Peter's girl after all!
You didn't even tell me what the plan is!
I can't, because if I did, you'd stop me.
Now, if you will please excuse me...
Abe, for heaven's sake!
Where are you going?
To St. Eliza.
Picking up Florence and Cal.
Cal? As in Cal Davis?
Oh, didn't I mention that
he's on our side now?
I need a cup of coffee.
It's on the kitchen table!
I... uh...
Now what are you waiting for?
It's time to get ready!
FOR WHAT?
To bake a cake.
FOR THE QUEEN!
[applause]
Oh, I hate ceremonial occasions.
Always the same people,
always the same endless smalltalk.
Such a waste of time.
Well, this is going to be
different, let me promise you that!
Really? Well, we'll see.
The best thing about these
receptions is usually the cake.
Didn't you hear?
Eva Harrington's shop burned down!
What?
No cake at all?
All right, that's it. I'm leaving...
Ladies and Gentlemen
let's raise our glasses to Irdis the First
by the Grace of Gods, Queen
of the Kingdom of Great Astar
Defender of the Faith!
The Queen!
My Lords and friends of the Royal Family.
The people of Great
Astar are diligent and fertile.
But we do not know for how much longer
the land that our thriving industry
is built upon will be able support it.
We have reached a point where our borders
are no longer restricted
by opposing territories
but by the mere coastline of our continent.
To conquer new lands we must now go
where no one has gone before.
In this matter
I have invited the esteemed Mr. Welsh
who is going to talk
about his latest discoveries.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
A few weeks ago, we have returned
from our Trans Oceanic Expedition
and we...
Who in God's…
EVA HARRINGTON?!
Oooh, and she brought the cake!
Ahh! It's so beautiful!
I'm so sorry Mr. Welsh
I didn't mean to interrupt
you! Please, go on!
Alright, what kind of
game is being played here?
I beg your pardon, sir?
I'm delivering the cake you ordered!
How is this even possible?
By the skilled work
of artisan pastry chefs!
This has to be a trap, right?
No... It's a family recipe!
Well then, thank you for
the cake, Mrs. Harringon.
YOU MAY NOW LEAVE.
God save the Queen!
Yeah, yeah.
Now look at this!
This work of arts!
So much CHOCOLATE
And cherries on top!
Fine...
But I bet you didn't
expect that I could do THIS!
HAH!
Ehehehehe...
A nice trick, huh?
My father used to be a magician!
Mr. Welsh, your behavior is most peculiar.
Is everything all right with you?
Oh, yes, of course,
your Highness, of course.
I am sorry, I think the
workload is getting to me.
Anyways, let's go on with the presentation.
Where was I...
Yes, the ex-oceanic
transped... Transpedition…
I mean, the Trans Oceanic Expedition.
Eh... at the perils of our lives, my
men and I have found a new continent
that shall from now on be known as Irdisia
in honor of... uhm...
Majesty the Queen of Great Astar!
It's a land... rich of... many riches, like
trees... mountains... rivers!
The... the coast is
guarded by flying beasts
against whom we prevailed
and one of which I hereby
present to you, your Majesty
as gift and sign of loyalty!
Behold, THE BEAST!
As you can see...
it is very dangerous!
As I said
dangerous!
IT'S WELSH! RIGHT THERE!
Open the cage! Now!
Ignore Welsh, Ortha.
Remember our plan?
Go for the Queen! The
rest will sort itself out!
OH I HATE HIM SO MUCH!
I'M GOING TO KILL HIM!
KILL HIM! KILL HIM! KILL!
Florence! Now?
NO! Don't open the cage!
Something's wrong with her!
But we can't wait any
longer! It's now or never!
No!
What?
What's happening?
DON'T CALL THE GUARDS OR
YOU'RE GOING TO REGRET IT!
Ortha, what are you doing?!
AAH!
So, what are you going to do, Florence?
Going to shoot me?
No!
THEN... GET... OUT... OF... MY... WAY!
ARGH!
Quick, get inside the cage...
it's the only place you'll be safe!
Help me!
What the hell is Ortha doing?
I don't want to die!
Her hate for Welsh is so strong,
it almost knocked me off my feet!
She's out of control!
You have to get her back to her senses!
You can talk!
We're going to die.
Does she want us to die? ASK HER THAT!
No, I have a better idea.
Hey, Welsh! Take the knife!
You need something
to defend yourself with!
Why are you doing this?
JUST TAKE THE GODDAMN KNIFE!
Hey! Let go of my hand!
This is going to be painful,
but it's for your own good.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING TO ME?
You killed my neighbors.
You killed my friends.
And you killed my brother.
This is how it feels, Welsh!
THIS IS HOW IT FEELS!
Sister, what's going on?
Sitho! The flying machines
are shooting at us!
What? From this distance?
I don't know what is is...
but it's much faster, and
much deadlier than arrows!
They killed Urnith and Thorna...
and we will be next if we don't retreat!
But we have to defend ourselves!
Brother, please! Turn back!
-NEVER!
-SITHOOOO!
SITHOOO! NO!
NOOOOOO!
I'M GOING TO MAKE THEM PAY FOR THIS!
I SWEAR BY MY LIFE, THEY
ARE GOING TO PAY FOR THIS!
Help! Help!
IT HURTS.... I'M FALLING! AAAAAARGH!
Oh my god...
so... so much... pain...
so much... hate...
What... what have I done?
You made sure his mind will never
be at peace again for the rest of his life.
I... I nearly killed him...
He's in pain!...
Oh my god, I must have
broken every bone in him...
I... I didn't mean to do this!
I'm so sorry!
I never realized how much grief and
hate you were carrying with you.
I hid it from you.
Why?
I didn't want to burden you with it.
And... I was ashamed.
I didn't want you to ever see me like that.
Oh Ortha...
Sorry to interrupt your intimate moment
but you do realize we're
going to die soon, don't you?
Can someone explain to me
what on earth is going on here?
I've seen you before.
You used to work for Welsh.
And you're Eva
Harrington's daughter, right?
And this is Ortha.
Ortha, bow before your Queen.
She does tricks?
What is she? Some kind of pet?
She is a person, and no
more an animal than we are.
Welsh did terrible things
to her and her people.
If it is like you say, why
doesn't she talk to us?
Oh, she'd love to.
All you have to do is
touch my paw.
I beg your pardon?
Look, I'm not armed.
And Cal is going to drop his gun, too.
Am I?
Absolutely.
All right.
This is not a revolt.
You are my Queen, and I do not
have the right to force this upon you.
However, I know that you are a good person.
Yeah, and what separates a
good person from a bad person is
that a good person can change
and they will always find new ways.
Decide to end our lives now
and everything will stay the same
and ignorance will prevail.
Choose to trust me
and you will learn things that
are of utmost importance for you
and the entirety of your kingdom
and many new ways will
open up for you to take.
The choice is yours, my Queen.
[applause]
Welcome to the evening
news on Astar National Radio!
Great Astar's most proficient
industry magnate Sarkan T. Welsh
faces a devastating new scandal
following a whistleblower report.
The royal house confirmed that
they are investigating evidence of fraud
attempted murder, blackmail
multiple anti-trust violations,
embezzlement and treason.
The Harrington & Welsh company did
not respond to our request for comments
but a copy of the report
was leaked to this reporter.
The allegations, if proven, will
forever tarnish the company's reputation
and its owner's
Evidence strongly points
towards the crucial role
Mr. Welsh played in the
escalation of the conflict with Vanos
with the sole goal to increase
his profit as an arms manufacturer.
A particularly explosive revelation
is that he might be personally responsible
for the death of Peter M. Harrington
aviation pioneer and national hero
and the attempted murder
of Eva Harrington, his wife.
In a statement to the
Port Ospen Telegraph
Eva Harrington confirmed the accusations
stating that she did not agree to Welsh's
acquisition of the company under her own free will
therefore making the
contract null and void.
She has appealed to the
queen to award her with
the full ownership of the company
after her house was recently
destroyed by a bomb blast
engineered by the company under
the guise of a Vanosian terrorist attack.
Furthermore, the royal geographic society
has withdrawn their support of
the findings of Mr. Welsh's so called
"Trans-Oceanic Expedition".
After close examination
it is highly doubtful that the
expedition took place in the form
the Harrington & Welsh company claimed.
When police searched
company headquarters
the fantastic "beast"
was nowhere to be found.
They did however find a
workshop with materials suitable
to build a highly sophisticated
mechanical puppet.
In all likelihood, the beast was nothing
more than a very realistic marionette
and it fooled us all.
Whether the new continent
really exists remains to be proven
but the Queen has put all research
projects in that regard on indefinite hold.
Sarkan T. Welsh is being detained in
the high security prison in Port Ospen.
The Queen's medical adviser
reports that he is in poor mental health
and is showing signs of delusion and mania.
The company was put under
forced administration by the Queen.
This story will surely keep the
country in suspense for weeks
as new details of these tremendous
conspiracies are revealed.
As always, stay tuned for
updates from Astar National Radio!
One final announcement on our own accord
It is with great sadness
that we have to report
the death of our friend and colleague
Mr. Feivel Mc Brookhaven.
He died in the performance
of his duties as a field reporter
on the Peter M. Harrington airfield
struck down by the
explosion of a terrorist bomb.
He will always be remembered.
A memorial service will
be held on August 21st
at 2 p.m.
at the Memorial Church in Kempton Yard.
[applause]
Greetings, Ms. Ortha!
You look marvelous,
my Lady, as always!
So glad to see you again!
Hello my Darling!
Do you know where Florence is?
Is she on the airship with Cal?
Mom, Abe! Hello!
Oh, so good to see you!
I've just helped Cal finish up packing.
Hello Mr. Davis.
Hello Mr. French. Why suddenly so formal?
Oh, I'm just giving you the
respect you finally deserve.
No, I don't know...
Oh do not sell yourself short, young man.
You are about to leave this
continent, possibly forever.
You are going to be a
ground-dwelling stranger
in a society of airborne people
whose language you'll
never be able to speak.
That doesn't just take courage.
That takes ball bearings of steel.
So, Hats off to you, Mr. Davis.
It seems like nothing ever scares you!
Oh, I am very scared.
The moment the Queen
told us that society isn't ready
for contact with another species yet
I knew I had to go with Ortha.
I love her so much
I'd rather be with her
than with anybody else.
It will be worth it.
How are you going to talk
to her without Florence?
Ortha is picking up more
and more of our language.
Florence has been a great help in teaching
her the basics in just a few weeks.
And did you know that Ortha's
people have a written language, too?
It's surprising that someone can
have such a sophisticated culture
and on the other hand still
hunt the neighbor's sheep.
Hah, no! No, she's a civilized person
she would never do that! Right, Ortha?
It's all right. It's all right.
Florence, do you want to
hear some really good news?
Yes, mom?
We received a letter this morning!
Welsh has been dispossessed
and the Queen herself signed
the company back over to us!
Oh, that's wonderful news!
And guess what's even better?
-Abe and I are going to get married!
-What?
Harrington & French, how
does that sound to you?
Ah, that sounds awesome!
Congratulations!
Does that mean I can
become an airplane engineer?
Hmm, yes. No more cake!
Oh, that's what you've been talking about.
Congratulations on your new job!
And my best wishes to Abe and Eva!
I'm so happy and so sad at the same time
I think my head is going to explode...
By the way, is there any
news about Mae and Will?
How are they doing?
Well, Will is still
walking on crutches, but
his leg is getting better every day.
Mae is struggling to keep the farm running
but she's getting help from a few friends.
I understand.
Please give them my best greetings.
They are good people.
I will. I promise.
It's time for us to go.
I still can't believe today is
the day you're going home.
You're my friend
and it feels like I've
known you for all my life.
Maybe we will come back
one distant day. Who knows.
I'm going to miss your voice in my head.
Oh - oh yes, me too.
Me too.
Have a safe trip home, and
take good care of each other.
Farewell my friends!
Farewell!
Bye bye Cal, Bye bye Ortha!
Farewell Mrs. Harrington.
Farewell Mr. French.
Bye bye!
I will never forget you!
[applause]
♪ Spoken with no sound ♪
♪ foreign lands abound ♪
♪ wandering skies ♪
♪ for the voice that I lost... ♪
♪ though soon your land I view ♪
♪ Fly true, touch and breakthrough ♪
♪ brave new worlds tale ♪
♪ my voice unveiled. ♪
♪ Set sail... But unto the skies ♪
♪ and we will leave the world behind. ♪
♪ Sometimes our minds change ♪
♪ sometimes it feels strange ♪
♪ when you're alone above. ♪
♪ Land that is fleeting... ♪
♪ Fly true, touch and breakthrough ♪
♪ brave new worlds tale ♪
♪ my voice unveiled. ♪
♪ Set sail... But unto the skies ♪
♪ and we will leave the world behind. ♪
♪ One touch last forever ♪
♪ Fly true, touch and breakthrough ♪
♪ brave new worlds tale ♪
♪ my voice unveiled. ♪
♪ Set sail... But unto the skies ♪
♪ Let's leave, let's leave, ♪
♪ let's leave the world behind ♪
♪ Just one touch tell me who you are ♪
♪ Here beneath the skies of Astar ♪