Spiraling down,
tryna go around and around
And it's better not to fall off the edge
Spinning as a coin,
down an endless road
Where can I go,
the center it flows
Do I put my trust
in a faith that’s new?
Does no one really listen,
except for you?
Except for you?
What's this light
that draws me near?
A keeper,
or something more to fear?
How can I put my faith in you
Your words are strong,
does that make them true?
I reach far out,
for one to hold
To give one strum,
so I'm undone
I can't do this alone,
I need someone
To take my soul and fears
The wound that will not heal
Feed me my own pain
I'll never be the same
To take my soul and fears
A wound that will not heal
Feed me my own pain
I'll never be the same
My faith is you!
So take my soul and feel
The wound that will not heal
Feed me my own pain
So I'll never,
ever be the same.