♪ Open your eyes, and here you'll see it all ♪
♪ Where shattered shadows always call ♪
♪ Raise up your ears, and now you'll hear my will ♪
♪ Righteous thunder, ♪
♪ light-filled wonder ♪
♪ Lets their aura still. ♪
♪ Give them my path, I'll go through them  ♪
♪ Hold deep my hand, guide me right ♪
♪ Goldeneyes so they can see their last light ♪
♪ Leave me untouched ♪
♪ and you'll have lost control ♪
♪ Let's make our power become whole ♪
♪ With but a flash, ♪
♪ they'll barely hear their fate ♪
♪ Swords and sticks will hold no tricks ♪
♪ They're already too late ♪
♪ Give them my path, ♪
♪ I'll go through them ♪
♪ Hold deep my hand, guide me right ♪
♪ Goldeneyes so they can see their last light. ♪
♪ Faster than sound I'll undo them ♪
♪ With but a pull your divine ♪
♪ Goldeneyes, you'll be forever mine ♪
♪ Give them my path, I'll go through them ♪
♪ Hold deep my hand, guide me right ♪
♪ Goldeneyes so they can see their last light. ♪
♪ Faster than sound I'll undo them ♪
♪ With but a pull your divine ♪
♪ Goldeneyes, you'll be forever, ever, ever ♪
♪ Mine ♪
♪ Goldeneyes ♪
♪ Yeah ♪