Hello?
I'm still up here!
Hey! Come back!
It's always the same.
Hey, you assholes!
If you don't want me to be with you,
why don't you just tell me?
We're all grown-up people, aren't we?
Hey, come on! Give me a chance.
I bet I can be a good prisoner, too!
Shit!
I gotta get down here by myself, then.
I give up.
I'm completely tangled in this ...
fucking parachute! Shit!
I'm stuck!
Lionel!
Mika!
Come back and get me down!
Lionel?
Mika?
Lori?
How am I ever supposed to get ...
out of this fucking tree?
Ooh! Out of my way! I can't stop!
Step aside! Incoming!
Uh oh ...
Timber!
Ow!
Oh, fuck!
Hey, what's up with you?
Have you been living in a cave?
And I thought Lori was a bad driver.
Oh well, at least
I'm on the ground again.
I mean ... I like bondage but ...
this is ridiculous.
Okay ... now what?
These trees look all the same.
Should I go this way?
Or that way?
Or, what about the way back?
Come on, Poke, time to think.
You must think your way out of here!
Think!
Come on! Think!
Think! Thiii- ack!
I must have snapped
a muscle in my brain.
Man, that hurts!
I guess I'll just lie down here and ...
think a little bit more carefully.
Think!
Thi- uh ... Think!
Hey! Hey!
Can't you see here's a genius at work?
How am I supposed to think with ...
all this ooga-booga stuff going on?
So?
Hey, stop complaining!
We're doing an important job!
Does it look like we're
running about just for fun?
Who are you, anyway?
Hey, that's funny. I just wanted to
ask you the same thing.
We are the honorable carriers of ...
the sacred chest of the old ages.
And who are you?
I'm ... Poke.
You're a "Poke"?
I've never heard of a "Poke."
What's a "Poke"?
I'm Poke!
I am the "dick" in "ridiculous"!
You are the what in the what?
Ah, forget about it.
So you're the fucking carriers of
the fucking something.
So ... what the heck are you doing?
We are carrying the sacred chest
of the old ages.
Isn't that obvoius?
Okay, I can see that, but ...
What for?
Why are you running around
all the time?
Mh ... could it be to make sure ...
that nobody gets the chest?
Okay ...?
But wouldn't it be easier to simply ...
guard the chest? I mean,
without moving.
No, what a foolish idea!
Everybody knows, guards can be
overwhelmed!
Well then, what about
locking it away?
In a crypta, or in a vault
or something.
Now, that would be an even
more foolish idea!
Everybody knows, locks
can be broken!
Well ... are you sure you still
got all marbles ...
Listen, we've been doing this
for two thousand years.
Do you really think we never
thought about all this?
Okay, I'll explain it to you.
Let's pretend we made all the effort
of putting up guards ...
and walls and locks and
traps and stuff.
This takes ages!
And now, some adventurer
comes along ...
Tricks the guards, breaks the locks ...
and defeats the traps.
And in the end, the only option
you're left with ...
is grabbing the artifact and
run away as fast as you can.
Now, if running away
is your only option ...
what was the point in setting up
all these barriers ...
in the first place?
Uh ... yes.
So the high council of ooga-booga
has decided to save our energy ...
for the really important matters.
We skipped the whole effort and
just started running from the start.
And we've proudly been doing so ...
for two thousand years.
It's the most efficient way to
protect the artifact.
End of discussion.
Okay. What's inside this chest that ...
makes it worth running to and fro ...
for like two thousand years?
And what's that pounding noise?
Err ... We don't know exactly.
All we do know is, that it must
be a very mighty artifact.
And ... well ...
that it obviously makes
very strange noises.
The high priest gave it to us
to make sure that ...
only the chosen ones may get
hold of it.
And what's your job in this affair?
I am the apprentice of the
honorable chest carriers.
Once I'll be grown up ...
I'm going to be a chest carrier, too!
But before I can become one ...
I have to complete a highly
sophisticated ...
and challenging two year
training program.
And what kind of
highly sophisticated training ...
is that?
What do you have to do?
Well ...
I've got to run after them and bring
them water when they're thirsty.
That's all?
That's the ooga-booga university?
Hey wait. this is not as easy
as it seems.
Being a chest carrier requires
highly trained skills.
It's very hard to run at precicely
the right speed, you know.
If you go to slow, someone could ...
catch up with you
and steal the artifact.
Yes, and running too fast will
make you pass out.
Well, no.
That's actually not the problem.
The catch is, you've got
to stay below the speed limit.
Err ... what?
There's a speed limit? I mean ...
in the jungle?
Hey, think about it!
This is the brazilian rainforest.
If everyone was allowed to
go as fast as they wanted ...
there wouldn't be a single tree left!
Uh oh ... there goes another one.
Ah, one day, I'll be one of the
honorable chest carriers.
Running through the forest,
swiftly like the wind ...
Listening to the birds,
and the pounding in my chest.
Always remember the lines
from the book!
"I hear a pound pound
pounding in my chest."
Uh ... Wait wait wait wait
wait a minute!
That sound coming from that
box ... I mean ...
How should I say ...
I think I need that artifact.
Heh, yeah, sure!
But only the chosen ones may
approach the chest.
And how can you tell that someone
is the chosen one?
We don't know.
We're supposed to recognize them ...
when they come.
Here I am! I must get the chest!
But you can't. You don't look
like a chosen one.
Okay, so let's pretend
I'm not the chosen one.
Would there be any other way
to get the artifact?
Maybe. Maybe not.
Ah come on! You can tell me.
Everything will be cool!
I can keep a secret.
Well, I probably could tell you ...
if there is a way to get the
artifact, but ...
There is no such thing as a free lunch
if you know what I mean.
Okay, I'll bite.
What do I have to do?
The carriers are thirsty, and it's my
duty to bring them water.
But I'm feeling pretty
exhausted, you know.
And I thought, maybe you
could give me a hand.
All you've got to do is to take
this bottle of water ...
and run after them, so they can
have something to drink.
Alright, and then you'll tell me
if there is a way ...
for me to get hold of the artifact.
Well, fair enough.
That sounds easy. Gimme that bottle.
Hey wait! Guys, guys!
I got water for you!
I said wait!
My ... gosh ...
Man ...
That was more exhausting than
being the guest of honor ...
on a rabbit swinger party.
I told you it's harder than it looks.
Okay.
I carried the water for you ...
now you must tell me if there is a
way for me to get hold of the artifact.
Yes, you're right.
Now I can tell you.
There is no way to get hold
of the artifact.
What?
But you promised!
Yes, I promised to tell you
if there is a way.
And there is no way. I told you,
just like I promised.
What?
And I just found something
out about you.
You are precicely as dumb as you look.
Thanks for doing my work, ferret!
What ... Maybe I look dumb ...
But you can't imagine how you are
gonna look after I broke your nose!
I was fast enough to catch up
with your ooga-boogas ...
and I'm certainly fast enough to
catch up with you, too!
Well ... catch me if you can!
Hey!
When I catch you I'll stick your ...
bloody artifact up your god-damn arse!
What was that?
A speed trap?
In the middle of the jungle!
What the fuck?
I think I'm blind!
Uh, who, me?
Uh, how much?
You guys must be joking!
But ...
I don't have any money.
I just fell out of a plane.
And I don't have anything except ...
for my big bottle of arabian mocha.
So, now what?
Ouch ...
Ah, I get it!
You guys want my parachute!
Para-Choot. Gah!
Okay ...
Let me just fetch it for you.
It's pretty messed up, but ...
here it is!
If it makes you happy.
Have fun with the parachute!
I can't believe that this
little sucker escaped.
If I ever meet that guy again ...
This is getting worse and worse.
Ah, well. At least I was lucky.
They took my parachute
and not my precious coffee.
"There's an awful lot of
coffee in Brazil!"
Suddenly everything is so clear!
Now I understand everything!
My brain! It works!
I can think!
The powers of caffeine! I ... I ...
Oh, shit ...
It's over ... but ...
Hey! I got an idea!
Now I know, how to get to the chest!
I will prove those guys, that I ...
look much dumber than I really am!
Hello? Hello?
Are you thirsty again?
I got something for you!
Oogey-Boogey!
Hello?
Is everybody gone?
Ah ... Let's see, what we have here.
Oh ... wow!
Shiny thing!
Wow, cool!
This is what we've been looking for?
It's round, and flashy, and shiny ...
and ...
And it's beautiful!
And it's mine!
Nobody shall have it!
It's mine, mine alone!
My motherfucking precious!
I must not let them have it!
Whoa!
Wow!
Caffeine flashback!
Alright, Lionel! Here I come!
Never underestimate the power
of arabian mocha!
Poke wins, carrier lost! Yay!
"That's the way - I like it!"
Ow! Shit!
I don't understand ...
Why don't they open the gates?
I feel they have the key ...
but don't they know how to
open the gates?
Has the key fallen into the
wrong hands?
Or has the knowledge of the
ritual been lost?
Am I doomed to stay here forever?
I can feel the darkness
growing stronger.
I must do something but ...
my hands are bound.
This place is like a golden cage.
While it protects me from
all that is dark ...
it bars me from fighting
the darkness outside.
Oh Gods ...
Please let them remember
how to use the key.
Let them remember
the ancient words ...
to set me free.
Alright ...
Now you've arrested us ...
What's going to happen next?
Are you just going to let us
rot in here?
Ah, shut up!
The mighty producer is on his way.
He wants to talk to you.
You'll live at least as long ...
as it takes for him to arrive.
So, enjoy your lives while they last.
Yup, enjoy yourselves.
Who the heck is the producer?
And what makes im mighty?
Oh, you naive little thing!
Don't you know what a producer is?
Who do you think writes all the ...
high-scoring top-ten chart-breakers?
The musicians themselves?
Those are just puppets.
Barely intelligent enough
to hold a microphone.
The producer is the one who
draws the strings ...
making them dance.
Without the producer ...
there would be no music.
Yup, no music at all.
But that's complete bullshit!
Every talented person can write music.
I must know.
My father was both ...
a singer and a songwriter.
You don't expect me to
believe that, do you?
I know that is completely impossible.
No producer, no music.
Now, silence!
There he comes!
Ladies and gentlemen:
The Producer!
At your service, oh mighty Producer!
Lionel Cristopher Scruffycat.
So we meet at last.
I must say ...
You have a striking similarity
to your father.
You knew my father?
Yes, I did.
I wasn't always a producer, you know.
Many, many years ago ...
your father and I ...
used to be good friends.
He was an aspiring musician.
And I used to be a talent scout
for the record company ...
that was publishing him.
At first everything worked out fine.
Your father was a pretty
successful musician.
Later ...
when I eventually got promoted ...
they gave me the chance
to name a successor.
And I thought ...
your father might be a good choice.
So he got the offer ...
and gladly accepted.
But ...
But then ... what happened then?
Well ...
It seems your father had a few ...
misconceptions about the duties
of a talent scout.
You know ...
Many people think that ...
record companies send out
talent scouts ...
in order to search for
talented people ...
in the hope of discovering
the stars of tomorrow.
But when your father was clued in
on the real mission ...
he was supposed to fulfill ...
Mmh, how should I say ...
he suddenly began losing his ...
enthusiasm.
Or in other words,
he threw his carreer.
What was so horrible
about his new job ...
that he absolutely couln't tolerate?
There is a secret ...
that is well-kept from people outside
the corporation.
I'm not supposed to tell you either.
But you're not going to live
to tell anybody.
The inspiration behind all music
does not come out of thin air.
There are actual ...
physical sources of inspiration.
From them inspiration
used to flow freely ...
equally enlightening all of
the people ...
across the lands.
Now, seen from a
business perspective ...
this is not exactly the ideal.
How are you supposed
to sell something ...
which is a resource free for all ...
like te air you breathe?
That's where our talent scouts come in.
They used to be the ones searching ...
and finding these sources
of inspiration ...
and bringing them under our control!
Your father was horrified
by the very idea.
He didn't like the concept of
running short inspiration ...
To artificially increase the value
of our products.
Mh ... I can relate to that.
At one time ...
we thought we had all sources
of inspiration ...
under our control.
Talent scrouts were no longer needed.
However ...
your father believed that there was ...
one more source of inspiration ...
that we had failed to discover.
He was determined to find it
and make sure ...
that we would never gain
control over it.
At first we didn't pay much
attention to him.
We thought he was just a ranting ...
disgruntled ex-employee.
However ...
we were smart enough to
keep his research activities ...
under close supervision.
He knew that, of course.
He never let anything slip.
Until now!
In a way, I have to thank you.
Without you, I would never
have been able ...
to decode the riddles
in your fathers journal.
Now we know that there is indeed ...
one last source of inspiration ...
hidden within the walls of the
long forgotten ...
Temple of Dunnowhat!
And in just a few hours ...
it will be mine!
You!
You are such a piece of ...
You ...
I'm speechless!
And what's going to happen
with us now?
You know ...
I really hate to get my paws dirty.
I tink I'll just leave you here.
And soon ...
nothing will be left of you but ...
a bunch of nameless
rotting skeletons ...
in the middle of the
brazilian rainforest.
And nobody will ever find you!
I must go now and
prepare the ceremony.
Have a nice death!
Oh come back you coward!
You slimy rotten scoundrel!
Come back and fight like a-
Mika! Mika stop!
You know this is not going to
get you anywhere.
And remember, there is still hope!
Poke is still out there.
You're honestly putting
your faith in Poke?
I don't know ...
I think, the only thing
Poke would be capable of ...
is making things considerably worse.
Think of it.
Following our tracks
and showing up here ...
would be about the
most stupid thing ...
he possibly could do.
because, when he comes here-
Ta da!
Poke to the rescue!
Time to surrender!
You have no chance!
I got the green belt in take-one-leap!
Boot to the head!
Ow!
Ow ...
What the hell is this?
Do you know this guy?
This must have been the ...
the most stupid rescue attempt ...
I've ever witnessed!
Oh Poke, you idiot!
You ruined everything!
You've been our last hope!
Alright!
You wanted to meet your friends?
No problem There's enough
space in the cage ...
for all of you.
Yup, lots of space.
Hey, let me go! I'm not an idiot!
Yes, you are.
No, I'm not!
At least not compared to
these two boneheads.
Hey, buddy ...
You obvously don't know
what you're saying.
We're captains of the mighty
Producer's personal guard.
We are members of the
international elite!
Yup, elite!
I believe it when I see it!
I'm much smarter than you are!
And I can prove it! Come on!
Challenge me! Give me a puzzle
or something.
Hey, do you know the riddle
with the shepherd ...
the sheep, the cabbage and the wolf?
No, never heard of it.
Oh, very good!
I mean ... may I explain it to you?
Fire away.
Well ... There is a man with a boat ...
who must move a wolf ...
a sheep ...
and a box of cabbage
to the other side of the river.
But there is a catch.
The boat is very small ...
So the poor guy can always ...
only take one thing with him.
And now his problem is that ...
when he leaves the wolf
and the sheep alone ...
the wolf will eat the sheep.
When he leaves the sheep and
the cabbage alone ...
the sheep will eat the cabbage.
So, what does he have to do ...
in order to get all three things ...
safely to the other side?
Ha! That's easy! That's easy.
Okay, ferret guy! You're toast!
Yup, toast!
Alright!
Then let the contest begin!
Poke, the ferret, starts!
Alright, he's not going to solve
it anyway.
Hey! Okie-dokie! Let's see ...
Just a second ...
Alright, let's see ...
Uh, first he moves the cabbage
to the other side ...
And then ... no, wait ...
Then the sheep will be fucked.
So then he has to
move the wolf first ...
Oh, come on, come on,
you're so stupid!
If he moves the wolf first ...
he will leave the sheep
and the cabbage behind ...
and the sheep will eat the cabbage!
Don't you get it?
No no no, wait, wait!
I just need a little visualisation.
So, let's pretend that ...
you are the sheep ...
and you are the wolf.
Yup, the wolf.
And I am the cabbage.
Okay, now ... what?
Okay ...
Let's pretend ...
this bridge is the river.
Of course ...
the first thing, you have to do ...
Is taking the sheep over
to the other side.
Watch me, I'm the sheep!
Baaaah!
Then, the shepherd gets the wolf
over the river.
That's you!
Yup, that's me!
- And now ...
- Arooo!
And now ... uh ...
The shepherd sends the sheep back ...
over the river,
because the wolf is here.
Baaaah!
Wait ... wait, wait ...
This didn't get us anywhere, did it?
And besides, it's my turn!
You messed it up, and I ...
have to start all over again!
Now, let's pretend, you ...
are the cabbage ...
and I'm the shepherd.
Now I, the shepherd, take you, the
cabbage, over the river.
Good, and now I'll go back to
pick up the sheep.
There is no sheep. You forgot
to say who is the sheep.
What? Uh, shit!
Okay, give me one
final chance, alright?
Okay, but this will be
really the last chance, buddy.
Okay, I'll make sure not to forget
anybody this time.
I'm the shepherd ...
Mika is the cabbage ...
Lionel is the wolf and ...
Lori is the sheep!
Of course.
Hey!
Wait ... Wait, wait, wait!
Now I got it!
Hey, it's still my turn!
Oh, Poke. Come on!
Don't be a spoilsport!
If he wants to solve it ...
why don't you let him?
Well, if I have to ... Go ahead!
Okay, okay! Step one:
The shepherd takes the
sheep over the river.
Alright, I'm the shepherd,
I'll do everything you say.
So ... Step two:
The shepherd goes back and takes
the cabbage over the river.
Okay, your wish is my command.
Now!
Now comes the trick!
Step three:
He takes the sheep back with him ...
so it won't eat the cabbage!
Smart move! You're good!
- Keep going!
- Yeah!
Step four:
Now the shepherd takes the wolf ...
and brings it over the river,
leaving the sheep behind.
Excellent!
I think you're on the right track!
Yup!
And finally, step five:
He goes back and brings the sheep
over the river.
And that's it!
I solved it!
Yeah!
You're so good!
You really beat me! Good job!
Keep going!
Yeah, was fun!
I'd really love to hang out
some more with you ...
but it's getting late ...
and we really have to go now.
I hope we'll see each other again!
Bye!
- Bye!
Thanks for stopping by!
See you, guys!
Woo-hoo!
We're the smartest guards in the
whole wide world!
Yup, we are! We truly are!
Man, that was exhausting.
It's time for a nice hot cup
of brazilian coffee.
- Make that two!
- Sure! I'll bring you one.
"They've got an awful lot of
coffee in Braz-"
Oops ...
Are you sure this is the way they went?
Yes. I've been following their tracks.
And they are leading right this way.
We could at least have taken ...
one of the torches with us.
It's so dark!
I can't see anything.
Ah, don't worry.
I'm a cat!
A feline nose is one of
the most sensitive things on earth.
I can smell our enemies clearly.
And as long as I don't
lose the track ...
we will find them.
Trust me.
What a relief!
Poke, that wasn't necessary.
Mika, lead on.
Where do we have to go?
I don't know, I lost my sense of smell.
Okay, so that's what you get ...
when you let a girl navigate.
Step aside and let a man handle this.
All we have to do is follow trhe wind,
because ...
If there is wind
coming from a tunnel ...
There must be an exit
on the other side.
I saw this on television.
You mean, we have to go ...
chase your fart?
Don't be so cynical.
Poke's right, for a change.
Yes, I am! Now, follow me!
That's strange.
This tunnel has a metal floor.
Yeah, and it's getting steeper
and steeper.
Uh oh ...
I think, I know what's going on ...
What is it, Lori?
I think ... I think, we're on a slide!
Aaaah!
Ow!
- Ah!
- Ow!
Ah ... Is everyone alright?
Oh ... I'm here!
I'm here.
Uh ... I wonder where
the slide dumped us.
I don't know, but ...
It feels like we're still moving.
No!
- No!
- Aaah!
Aaah!
Fuck!
We're going way to fast!
Everybody hold on tight!
There's a left turn coming up!
Aaah!
So this is what you get
when you let a guy navigate?
Hey!
And he always calls me a bad driver!
Right turn!
Aaah!
Does anybody know where the heck
we are going?
We are going to die!
Hey, stop complaining!
We're going to die in the name of
Lionel's father!
We should be proud of ourselves,
shouldn't we, Lionel?
Oh, be careful what you say!
We didn't force you to come with us!
Feel free to jump if you want to.
Oh, shut up you two!
This is neither the right place ...
nor the right time for discussion.
No! I kept my mouth shut long enough!
This is precicely the right time
for discussion!
Lionel!
I need to have a word with you ...
about you and your father.
It can't go on like this!
It is very important that you finally-
It's going down!
Aaah!
Get off me!
Oh, I can't believe that grown-up
men can be such cowards!
Uh ... where was I?
Ah, yes!
Lionel ... Lionel I-
Mika, I really appreciate your
involvement, but ...
uh ... in case you haven't noticed ...
we're in a runaway lorry ...
going steeply downhill!
Yes, and so this may be
the last chance!
No! No, I don't want to die!
Lori ...
Lori, we are not going to die, okay?
Okay ...
Lionel, listen to me!
We all know you made mistakes
in the past ...
But sometimes you just have to ...
put your past behind you.
We're going all the way
with you here ...
and something is really-
Hey look! I see a light ...
at the end of the tunnel!
Uh, what?
Yes, I see it, too! We're saved!
Uh, wait ...
It's coming closer!
Yes, it's coming closer way to fast!
That's not the exit!
It's a train!
Aaah!
Oh, my gosh!
That was close!
That was too close!
Mika, I'm sorry but I completely ...
forgot what you were about to say.
You wanted to tell me something
about my father.
Now, tell me. I'm listening.
Alright. I said ...
We all know you made
mistakes in the past.
Hey!
Come on, get to the point!
I was just about getting to the point!
Stop shouting!
I'm not shouting, I'm screaming!
For heaven's sake, just tell me
what you want to say ...
preferably before we all die!
Okay, Lionel!
I just wanted to say that ...
I know that you made
mistakes in the past.
But you can't go on like this, if ...
- Aaah!
-Aaah!
Aaah!
Lori! Hold on!
Welcome to the "Runaway Lorry"
thrill ride!
Please keep your paws, feet and
tail inside the vehicle ...
at all times!
That's not funny! Help me!
Hold on!
We must get the two halves
together again!
Sure! But how?
Grab Lori's tail!
Okay!
I will grab her paws!
Now pull!
No! Don't pull! No!
Okay!
One ... two ... three!
Aaah!
Lori?
Are you alright?
I'll live ...
... barely.
I guess I will never have to
wear high heels anymore.
Alright ...
Now, before anything else
gets in the way.
Lionel ... it can't go on like this!
We've been going all the
way with you ...
and something is very
obvious about ...
the relationship between
you and your father.
But you have to realize ...
that it is over now.
Let me tell you something about
when I was little.
My mother had to work all day ...
so I was home alone all the time.
And whenever I-
We're under fire!
Pirates!
Aaah!
They're going to kill us!
No! They are not going to kill us!
Return fire!
Aye aye, Captain!
Fire!
Aaah!
Too short!
Okay, okay. That was close!
Aim higher!
Aye aye, Captain!
And ... fire again!
Woo! Full hit!
Guys?
- Guys!
- Woo-hoo! We did it!
- What?
Are you all nuts?
I don't care about your discussions.
We've got to stop this thing!
Ah ... stop this thing!
What a brilliant idea!
And how are we gonna do that?
If you don't want to try, I will try!
I've got a licence!
Do you think, because I'm a girl
I'm too dumb to drive?
- Be my guest!
- Let me get to the front here.
Okay ... It's been a while ...
Let's see ... where are the brakes?
Ah! This must be the brakes.
No, no! Okay, okay ...
Wait a minute ... wait a minute.
This one here!
Oh no! We're doomed!
Okay ... Okay, okay!
One more try, okay? Okay?
Okay ...
Welcome to "Traffic Professional"
navigation system!
Please wait while loading!
Locating vehicle.
Destination found.
The Temple of Dunnowhat.
Distance to destination:
One kilometer.
Hey, that's pretty cool!
We've been on the right track
all along!
I knew it!
I knew I could do the right thing!
Distance to destination:
Five hundred meters.
Uh Lori? Don't you think we're
going pretty fast?
Hey, the faster we go,
the sooner we'll be there.
Distance to destination:
Three hundred meters.
Uh, Lionel? Did your father mention
this in his book?
Uh ... If he did I obviously
didn't get the clue, because ...
I don't remember.
Distance to destination:
Two hundred meters.
Yay! We're almost there!
Dunnowhat, here we come!
Guys, I've got a very bad
feeling about this ...
Warning! Warning!
End of tracks in one hundred meters!
Warning!
- What?
- Aaah!
- No!
- Ow!
- Uh!
Ouch!
Okay ... We have arrived.
You have reached your destination.
Thank you for using "Traffic Pro".
Congratulations.
Is everyone alive?
Okay, I think I need a
moment to recover.
Uh, Mika? Didn't you want to
tell me something?
Now is the chance.
Did I?
Uh ... never mind.
Look! We found it!
This must be the entrance to
the Temple of Dunnowhat.
Ah, yes indeed!
I remember the drawing in the diary.
So, this is our goal, but ...
but what are we supposed to do here?
How about ...
going inside?
In ... side?
Uh, no. Actually, we got chased around
the world by the music gestapo,
kicked out of a plane,
run over by rolling stones ...
and nearly eaten by voodoo people
just to turn around and go home.
Not!
You can jump into a lake if you want to
but I'll go with Lionel.
And so will I.
But ... that's not what I-
You don't have to come
if you don't want to, Lori.
This is something between
my father and me.
Oh, no way!
We will stick with you until the end.
Won't we?
Yeah.
Let's go and kick some ass!
Come on, Lori!
O-okay. Let's go.
Lionel! You go first!
I don't think it's a good idea ...
to just walk inside.
Don't forget, we're
hopelessly outnumbered.
Wait here ...
If I go alone, maybe they
won't notice me.
I'll take a look around the corner
and check on the situation.
My dear comrades!
The time has come!
History is about to be made!
From this day on there will be ...
no other producers than us!
With all sources of inspiration ...
under our control ...
We will be able to control ...
all music on this planet!
Unlimited wealth!
Unprecedented increase in
shareholder value!
The ultimate return on investment!
Gentlemen!
Power up the amplifiers!
Let's start the show!
Ha ha ha!
Yes!
My Producer! It is done!
There's no inspiration left!
Yes!
Very good!
Very, very good!
Now it's time to celebrate!
Ha ha ha!
Oh no!
- Oh no, it's too late!
- What?
What did ... what did you see?
The source of inspiration!
They destroyed it! We came too late!
Aw, shit!
Oh no!
Is there really nothing we can do?
We must stop them!
Oh, get out of my way!
Nobody messes with Mika!
I will walk right in there and ...
kick those guys' butts
into next Monday!
No, let me go! Let me go!
Mika! Mika! It's pointless!
Mika, it's pointless.
The source has already been
destroyed!
Don't tell me you're giving up.
You're the big thinker ...
so think of something, already!
If not for us, do it for your father.
Alright.
Let's give it one last try.
Okay guys ...
What do we have?
Well ... well, we have the diary.
No Lori, I lost it when I
crashed into the forest. Sorry.
Uh, well ... then I guess ...
we don't have anything else.
Except ... except maybe ...
But I guess it doesn't mean anything.
Except for what?
What do you have?
Anything might be important!
Show it to us, Lori.
I found thois stone-egg in the
cavern in the jungle.
It seemed to be unimportant so
I didn't mention it.
Oh, what?
You found one of those, too?
I have another one.
It just looks the same!
But it makes a different sound.
Yeah.
Guys?
I think, I must tell you something.
Yes, Poke?
I ... well ... Look what I found!
Three of them!
This can't be a coincidence.
And each of them makes a
different sound.
Is this another puzzle?
Let's see what happens when ...
we let them play together.
Mh ... that's a good idea.
The tune sounds familiar to me ...
but ... where do I know it from?
It sounds really beautiful.
Yeah, sounds like the music of a
second class porn movie.
No, it does not!
What? You watch porn?
Oh ... well ...
Lionel, do you know this melody?
Mh ... It's nothing more than a faded
memory from long ago.
It sounds like a song my father
used to sing to me ...
when I was little.
Your father used to sing
porn soundtracks?
Ow!
? ? ?
Try to remember it,
it might be important.
Well ... I think ...
I think it went like this:
"Let's call to battle
on a musicial scale."
"Through song and through dance..."
"The good will prevail!"
What was that?
I don't know ...
Spooky ...
Try it again! But this time,
keep singing!
This is harder than you think,
I can barely remember the song.
Try!
"Let's call to a battle
on a musicial scale."
"Through songs and through dance
the good will prevail!"
"The power of music
in it's true form of art..."
"Doesn't come in a package,
no it comes from the heart!"
Free, at last! Whew!
That was about time!
What took you so long?
Wait a minute ...
You're not the high priest!
And you!
You're not the master of ceremonies!
Yes, and you are not Santa Claus!
Tell us something we don't know.
You don't know, who I am?
I've been alive since time began.
Not beast, not God, and yet not man.
I am the music and the dance!
I'm the piper, who enchants!
My name is Poke, my teeth are shiny!
I tell all the girls they can kiss my-
Poke!
That is the strangest welcome
I've ever received.
Times must have changed a lot more
than I thought.
Alright.
Let me put it ?sicintally?.
My name is Heather ...
and I am the spirit of inspiration.
And ... by the Tritons!
It's been ages since someone ...
called me finally and
summoned me here.
The last source of inspiration
has been destroyed ...
five minutes ago. I was there.
So tell me who you really are!
Inspiration can never be destroyed!
It's ...
It's one of the forces that
binds the universe together.
You mean, like duct tape?
What?
What are you talking about?
I really am the spirit of inspiration!
How come you don't know me?
How could the people survive
without inspiration?
This ritual has been passed down
from generation to generation ...
and you ... you have the three keys.
and ... and you know the song to
open the gate to my dimension ...
and now you tell me, you don't
know who I am?
I'm sorry to say this but ... no.
Who are you?
I already told you!
And I wish I knew what's going on.
Have people forgotten about me?
Long ago, they used to summon me ...
every week!
We used to sing and dance and ...
and our hearts and minds would soar!
Those were the days ...
But then, the summonings became
fewer and fewer ...
and eventually stopped altogether.
I can't remember ...
how long ...
and for centuries I've waited ...
lonely and restless so ...
Finally, you called me!
This couldn't be a coincidence!
Oh, well ...
Getting together,
singing and dancing ...
this has become rare, lately.
Really? How so?
Music is not free anymore.
All the music there is is being
controled by the big corporations.
They have the full power to decide ...
what kind of music is made ...
who may listen to it ...
and what the price is.
Yeah ...
We even had to pay a licence fee ...
to be allowed to sing
"Happy Birthday" ...
for Lionel the other day.
Lionel's father had discovered ...
why those corporations could
become so powerful.
Nobody knew that there were actual
sources of inspiration ...
hidden all over the world,
which all creative people in the world
were drawing from.
The music corporations found
out about that ...
and destroyed all of them.
Except one ...
which remained hidden.
My father quit his musicial carreer
after he found out ...
about this last source
of inspiration ...
in order to save it.
But he was too old to finish
what he started.
He wrote down all hos findings
in his book ...
encoded in a way only
I could decypher.
We followed the lead,
but we came too late.
The last source of inspiration was
destroyed before my eyes.
Tell me ...
What exactly was it that you saw?
What did it look like?
Well, it looked like a
sparkling fountain ...
brilliantly glowing in a bright light.
I see!
There's really not much of the ancient
knowledge left, is there anymore?
I'll tell you what you've seen.
What you've seen ...
is a fountain of inspiration.
But where do you think that
inspiration comes from?
Inspiration is like spring water, it's ...
it's fresh and it's new and ...
and even though it is
fresh and new it's ...
it's not being produced by anything
or in any way ...
Like spring water, it ...
What you see as spring water ...
actually just been the rain in the
hills that's come down and ...
And inspiration is like
that spring water.
It's a very part of yourself
and everyone else.
What you saw being destroyed ...
that's just merely an outlet.
It's like the well.
You know,
It's not where the water is made ...
it's just a place where it surfaces.
I am the spirit that brings
inspiration to the surface.
So, you are taking all bad ideas
that went down the toilet ...
and turn them into
inspirational spring water?
No ...
I mean ... yes ...
Uh, no!
Is he always like this?
So that means, there is still hope?
And what about the bad guys?
Yeah, there's still a bunch of
bad guys in the temple ...
musically pissing into your fountain!
What?
Yes.
It's the Producer and his minions.
You mean, those are the people
who drained all my fountains?
Yes, that's them.
Alright!
Now watch! Listen closely!
I'm going to show you how to
deal with guys like this.
Hey you! Fancy-Pants Producer!
What are you doing in my temple?
Who are you?
I am the owner of this fountain ...
and I don't tolerate any unwanted
guests in here.
Now ...
The fountains of inspiration
will be refilled ...
and music will be free again!
No! Never!
I've worked all my life to get
to this point ...
and I will not let you ruin it!
Ow!
"Did you really believe
you could own inspiration?"
"And through money and greed
achieve world domination?"
"This song is our weapon
against all evil powers!"
"We've come to claim back
what has always been ours!"
How do you think are musicians
supposed to earn their money?
By putting up a tip jar?
Let me tell you this:
Your tip jar belongs to us!
Because we are the ones making
people like you successful.
We know what the consumers want ...
Because we make consumers want it!
How are you going to do this with ...
inspiration?
Minions! Adjust the speakers!
Turn up the amplifiers!
Attack!
What is that ... crap?
No ...
"You like to pretend
you're promoting the arts."
"But your only worries
are your stock value charts."
"This noise you call music
full of violence and hate,"
"Will soon be forgotten
and meet its due fate."
No!
It will never be forgotten!
Because our music is our
intellectual property!
And we can release the same songs ...
again and again ...
for every generation!
We're making sure ...
only a fraction of all the
music ever made ...
is legally available.
So there is always a market ...
that is never saturated!
Isn't this wonderful?
You want music to be free?
Only over my dead body!
Minions! Get ready to fire!
Attack!
"Your greed is unmatched
and your arrogance strong!"
"You don't even see
that you're terrible wrong."
"Now comes a new era
where your rules don't apply."
"Putting back into music
what money can't buy!"
No!
This can't be!
Ths can't be!
?
This is impossible!
Ah! Aaah!
"Let's call to battle
On a musicial scale."
"Through song and through dance
the good will prevail!
"The power of music
in its true form of art"
"Doesn't come in a package,
no it comes from the heart!"
"Victory is ours
and the battle is won!"
"But let's not forget
that the war still goes on!"
"The fountain's refilled
which may help just a bit."
"But the future will be
what you make of it!"
"Let's call to battle
on a musicial scale!"
"Through song and through dance
the good will prevail!"
"The power of music
in its true form of art"
"Doesn't come in a package,
no it comes from the heart!"
"Let's call to battle
on a musicial scale."
"Through song and through dance
the good will prevail!"
"The power of music
in its true form of art"
"Doesn't come in a package,
no it comes from the heart!"
Woo!