Trust
is a thing that is earned through my fire,
It's so easily burned.
Dreams
are my craves to the deep
Beneath a world we're struggling to keep.
Help me free myself,
myself from my chain,
So that we can fight this machine again!
The tides - they are changing,
Trust is forsaking,
fulfil me!
My fear is surrounding,
Tearing and drowning,
nowhere to hide...
Here comes the end tide...
Change
in the void of the storm through my fire
my desires will swarm,
Bold
my wings open on land
To face our trial that's at hand
Help me see myself,
myself through this veil
So that we can fight this machine again!
The tides - they are changing,
Trust is forsaking,
fulfil me!
My fear is surrounding,
Tearing and drowning,
nowhere to hide...
Face it and ride,
Here comes the end tide.
Water may heal but reveals all is dark
Deep in the void we make our own mark
To fear what we know
to the world we must show:
The end tide!
The tides - they are changing,
Trust is forsaking,
fulfil me!
My fear is surrounding,
Tearing and drowning,
nowhere to hide...
We stand side by side
Until the end tide!
The tides - they are changing,
Trust is forsaking,
fulfill me!
My fear is surrounding,
Tearing and drowning,
nowhere to hide...
Here comes the end tide!
Here comes, here comes,
here comes the end tide!
Here comes the end tide!