It was the year 385
after the Awakening.
The village of Ferndale lay cozily nestled
in the valley of the Serpent River
where the winds sweeping
down from the Holy Mountain
tingled with the scent of pine trees
and the streets were filled
with the sounds of playing children
and oxen carts on cobblestone.
As with every other village,
each household
needed to have its own holy light.
These were nothing like ordinary lanterns.
They were gifts from the gods.
They shone bright as fire, yet without
flame, and nothing could extinguish them.
But the most important thing was that,
while even the strongest walls and gates
could not keep the dark creatures away
that came from the forest in the night
the holy light could.
A home without a light would not
have been a safe place to live
and leaving the village without one
at night would have been plain suicide.
Over the course of months, however, even
a holy light would eventually begin to dim.
And so, once every year
at the time of the summer solstice
farmers, millers, blacksmiths, bakers,
carpenters, spinsters, weavers, cobblers
everyone in the village
who could afford to do so
would lay down their work for a day
and celebrate The Festival of Lights.
Families would gather in their homes
and selebrate each other’s
company with lots of mulled
wine, mince pie, and
other festive specialties.
Parents would give their children
homemade presents
and in the evening the village priests
would walk from door to door
giving everyone their blessing,
and renew the lights in every house.
For the villagers, this was
the happiest day of the year
as the return of light to their home
reminded them
that the gods and their earthly servants
would always be there
to love and protect them.
For they were the Keepers of the Light.
[Music: "Keepers of the Light" by Fox Amoore]
♪ In a world forsaken by time ♪
♪ Is a light that always shall shine ♪
♪ It flows from out of your breath ♪
♪ Putting all the darkness to death ♪
♪ A torch in the dark is my own will ♪
♪ To light this place and let the white fill ♪
♪ Come forth now, oh so bright ♪
♪ Come with me and show your might ♪
♪ So the keepers can see ♪
♪ The keepers can feel me rise ♪
♪ Then shine ♪
♪ Keepers of the light ♪
♪ Shine! ♪
♪ Oh, keepers of the light ♪
♪ Shine your will so bright ♪
♪ Keepers of the light ♪