Back in the times when the kingdoms and castles
were shrines to our knowledge of old
Few will remember the legends and whispers
of magic and stories untold...
Under the earth where the secrets were kept
Mana at heart, crystals in debt
Summon a power in this final hour
And now our fate is set
So...
Hold Tight
(Hold Tight)
Under the magic of dark in the sky
We will fly home with a roar
that shakes the night
Cast my name, start a new age
You will become the new first mage!
Yet some who take all the magic's pure light
Total control, everyone's blight
They are the ones that my claws will now fight
Evil queens and shadowed paws!
Hold Tight
(Hold Tight)
Under the magic of dark in the sky
We will fly home with a roar
that shakes the night
Cast my name, start a new age
You will become the new first mage!
Hold Tight
(Hold Tight)
Under the magic of dark in the sky
We will fly home, with...
With a roar
that shakes the night
Cast my name, start a new age!
You will become the new first mage
Cast my name!
Start a new age!
You will become the
new first mage!