Long before our time,
the Earth was ruled by humans.
They could fly to the moon and lived in cities the size of kingdoms.
But for all their great achievements,
they also built the most terrible weapons.
When the Great War broke out,
it wiped their civilization from the face of the Earth in
a matter of days,
and only a few survived in shelters deep underground.
Unable to return to the surface,
the humans decided to create a new kind of creature to rebuild the world they had destroyed.
These creatures were just enough of a human to understand their master's commands,
but also enough of an animal to be denied their freedom.
The humans discovered
much too late that they had not created an army of willing slaves,
but rather a new people whose intelligence,
curiosity, and desire to live free was just as strong as their own.
The revolution was swift and cruel,
and this time,
no humans survived.
The leaders of the uprising called themselves Keepers of the Light,
and their mastery of
human technology gave them godlike powers.
The common folks worshipped them like saints
and simply accepted them as their new rulers,
for this was all they knew.
Generations passed,
and the memories of the uprising faded into legend,
and from legend into myth.
Common folks as well as people among their own ranks became increasingly wary,
until,
in the year 385,
a terrible bloodbath finally ended the Keepers' reign.
It was us,
the rebel underground,
who finally put an end to the Keepers' tyranny,
and ever since it has been our mission to give the Keepers' legacy of human knowledge back to whom it belongs.
You,
the true descendants of humankind.
This is why you are here,
at the Institute of Science, History, and Morality,
and I would like to wholeheartedly welcome all of our new students who have joined us today here in Ferndale for the beginning of the new semester.
Same old speech.
Yeah,
I've heard the professor say this so many times I can almost repeat it word for word.
Well,
if you two already know it so well,
I'm sure you know what this symbol here on the wall means.
It's the tree of knowledge,
and it means, well, it's a tree and it grows,
just like knowledge.
It used to be the secret symbol of the rebel underground,
but it stands for more than just knowledge.
It also stands for the ideals of a new society,
peace, progress, and freedom.
And who were the heroes who gave their lives for that freedom, huh?
You over there.
Um,
let me think.
I
think it was Black something and the other guy.
See?
That's what you get for talking all the time.
Does anybody else know?
Rain Dancer,
how about you?
Why always me?
Okay.
The three great dead people of the Rebellion.
Brother Fireheart of Cold Lake,
founding father of the Rebellion,
executed by the Keepers of the Light.
Stormrunner of Camp Freedom,
who died in the heroic fight over the Holy Mountain.
And Riversong of Ferndale,
who infiltrated the Keepers' stronghold all on his own,
sacrificing himself to end the Keepers' reign.
He will always be remembered.
Blah, blah, blah, blah.
Come on, Rain Dancer.
Riversong was your father.
You should be proud of your family history.
Well, so what?
I've never met him.
Besides,
he's not the only one who died in the Rebellion, you know.
The Keepers burned down an entire Camp Freedom.
Aren't those people heroes too?
Maybe you should mention that it was Stormrunner,
the great Rebel leader's fault,
and that he was...
Thank you, Rain Dancer.
I think that's enough.
We don't want to confuse our newcomers on their first day, do we?
Okay.
In short,
the Keepers are gone,
a lot of people died,
and the fatherless children who remained are now very proud.
Applause!
Close the curtain.
There he goes again.
What?
I'm so sick of talking about dead people all day.
I want to learn about physics and math and biology and the things that really matter.
Oh, you're such a nerd.
What?
No! No, no, no!
If you're not here to learn,
why don't you go the fuck home?
Silence! Silence! This is a university,
not a kindergarten! I said silence!
Oh,
excuse me.
Is this the class of Professor Bottlebrush?
Huh?
Hello?
Did I miss something?
What the hell is that?
Is that what I think it is?
Oh,
you must be Winstar's foster child.
Yep, that's me.
I'm sorry for bursting in.
I really wanted to be on time,
but I'm new here,
and well, you know how it goes.
And I...
Hey, why are you all staring at me?
Have you never seen a pig before?
You'll have to excuse them, dear.
Pigs are not very common around here.
Actually, she's not a pig.
She's a Red River Hawk, right?
Very good,
Rain Dancer.
Yes, she is a Red River Hawk,
and her name is Potami.
Class, say hello to Potami.
Hello,
Potami.
Hello, everyone.
Welcome to our class,
Potami.
Feel free to pick a seat.
Thank you.
I
hope you don't mind if I hog the space.
No, of course not.
Why should I?
Oh,
well,
class, it seems like it's time for a break.
The class will resume at half past twelve.
See you then, and please, try not to kill each other in the meantime, all right?
Fine.
Welcome to the Dead Hero Society.
What was your name again?
Potami, was it?
Yeah,
and hi.
What was your name?
I'm Rain Dancer.
It's nice to meet you, Rain Dancer.
So, you really don't mind sitting next to a pig?
No, no, why?
Well, is it just me,
or are the people in this village a little bit narrow-minded?
Yeah, this place is pretty backwards sometimes.
I've been living here all my life,
and people still think I am a weirdo.
Well,
people still think that I am a pig.
So,
if you're not a weirdo,
what are you?
Oh, a bit of this,
a bit of that.
A bit of fox,
and a bit of...
cat?
Yeah,
must have been some wild party.
So, and you've lived here all your life?
Yeah, I'm afraid so.
I really want to go to Ironforge when I'm ready for it,
but Uncle Brushy says I have to finish school first.
Professor Bottlebrush is your uncle?
Yeah,
well, not really, but that's kind of a long story.
Another one of those wild parties?
No, no, no, not like that.
Not like that.
Freeze!
Don't you dare make a sound,
or I'll put an arrow right between your eyes before you can even scream.
My,
my, what quick learners you are,
and so obedient too.
You all get an A plus from me.
Now, students, I'm afraid there has been a bit of a change in today's lesson plan.
It's time for all of you to go on a nice long field trip with us.
I promise the experience will be
educational.
This way,
we go out the back window.
Come on, move it,
and not a sound.
Who are you?
Where are you taking us?
Oh, you'll find out soon enough.
Now shut up and move!
Welcome back, students.
Break is over and it's time
to...
Where
is everyone?
This better not be another of your silly pranks.
Hey, this isn't funny.
Come out!
What's this?
A note?
Oh, shit!
Open your eyes and here you'll see it all
Where shattered shadows always call
Raise up your ears and now you'll hear my will
Righteous thunder,
light-filled wonder Let their aura still
Give them my path,
I'll go through them Hold deep my hand, guide me right
Open eyes so they can see their last light
Leave me untouched and you'll have lost control
Let's make our power become whole
With but a flash,
they'll barely hear their fate
Swords and sticks will hold no tricks They're already too late
Give them my path,
I'll go through them Hold deep my hand,
guide me right Golden eyes so they can see their last
light
Faster than sound, I'll undo them With power I'll pull your divine
Golden eyes, you'll be forever mine
Give them my path,
I'll go through them Hold deep my hand, guide me right
Golden eyes so they can see their last light
Faster than sound, I'll undo them With power I'll pull your divine
Golden eyes, you'll be forever, ever, ever
Mine
Golden eyes
Yeah
Natty?
Natty! Hey, moron!
Oh, Nettlebosh! Wake up and stay awake, stupid!
Someone needs to watch over the hostages!
Yeah,
yeah.
Don't worry,
I've got everything under control.
The breads are all tied up,
no one's going anywhere!
I should hope so! If we lose them,
they're gonna cut off your ears!
All in the name of the opposition!
What do you think they're gonna do with them anyway?
Don't know,
don't care.
I'm not in it for the politics,
just the money.
The Institute, the opposition,
all them fucking keepers of the light.
Whoever wants to pay us,
no questions asked.
You think, you think they're gonna kill him?
Nah,
then we wouldn't be hauling them through them fucking forests here.
Right,
right.
Um,
say,
Ivy?
Oh, what?
Would you mind pulling over?
Why?
I, uh,
I gotta pee.
What?
Are you fucking serious?
Oh, for the love of- No!
They said we mustn't stop no matter what happens,
so you better hold it in!
But I really have to go!
Look,
we don't know if there's anyone following us,
and I don't want to be the one who finds out.
You should have gone before the raid!
I did go before! Come on,
we've been racing full speed for hours and I always have to go when I'm nervous!
Just get your shit together!
I'm trying! Try harder!
Hey! What the hell are you doing?
I've gotta do what a man's gotta do!
Seriously?
You're seriously going to pee off the side of a moving fucking wagon?
What do you want me to do?
Wipe my pants?
No, let me do my business!
I don't fucking believe this!
That left...
that thing tastes like my mother's old socks!
Hey, Rainancer,
turn around so I can chew through your ropes quick!
Are you done yet?
Sit down, man!
Hey! I can't pee if you're watching me!
This is my fault now! You were the one that decided to stand right there to piss!
Well, you were the one who wanted to stop the wagon!
Ugh...
You're free!
Wow,
thanks.
You've got some sharp teeth.
Yeah, I hate being hogtied.
So,
should I ask you why you know how your mom's socks taste?
No,
you should untie my paws!
Oh, right, yeah.
Quick, before that moron comes back!
By the holy monk, that's disgusting!
Try not to hit the canopy, you idiot!
Watch the bloody roads!
Oops, was that a bottle?
Oh, my bad!
Oh, look,
there is another one!
And...
another one!
Phew, there were so many in this road all of a sudden!
I'm gonna kill you! I swear! As soon as we're back in Ironforge,
I'm gonna kill you!
God...
Yes, thank you.
Rainancer,
quick, where did they put my bag?
We need to free the others!
Yeah, but I need my bag! This is important!
Okay...
Oh, gosh, there it is!
Got it!
Alright!
I feel so much better!
No thanks to you and your driving!
Congrats, you fucking lations! Achievement unlocked! Now get your bloody arse back there and do your fucking job!
Yeah, yeah...
Oh, quick, quick, quick! It's returning!
Oh, shit! We are out of time!
What?
We need to free the others!
We have to jump! No, no!
Yes!
I said jump! Now time!
Oi!
Oi, stop it! Oink, oink, motherfucker!
Stop
the wagon! Stop the fucking wagon!
What the fuck is going on back there?
Two of the damn Brats just jumped ship! We gotta go after them!
No fucking way! It's the Darkwoods, remember?
They don't have a light!
Those two aren't going to get far before the beasts will make a quick snack of them!
The nights out here are dark and full of terrors!
It wasn't my fault! I swear!
Of course it's your fault! If you had been watching,
then they wouldn't have gotten free!
No fucking way! I'm gonna waste more precious time!
Just cause you're just literally too stupid to piss!
But, but, but, but, but...
No buts! We're already running late! And we still have plenty of Brats left!
Now go and check on the rest! We don't want to lose another one!
And if they do cut our pay,
it's coming out of your share!
Okay...
Fucktards!
Damn idiots!
The
privilege of opening the first trial for the crimes committed by the Keepers of the Light imposes a grave responsibility.
The wrongs which we seek to punish have been so calculated and so malignant that civilization cannot tolerate their being ignored,
because it cannot survive their being repeated.
The defendants in this case represent sinister influences that will lurk in the world long after their bodies have returned to dust.
We will show them to be living symbols of hatred,
terrorism,
and violence,
and of the arrogance and cruelty of Power.
It would have been easy to treat them in the same way like they treated their own adversaries,
but these trials shall be the most significant tribute that Power has ever paid to reason.
The accused will be given a fair opportunity to defend themselves,
a favor which the Order of the Keepers rarely extended to their enemies.
Despite the fact that public opinion already condemns their acts,
they must be given a presumption of innocence.
I now call the defendant to the witness stand.
Will you give your full name?
My name is Falcon Eye of Quails Hollow.
What was your rank within the Order of the Keepers of the Light?
Security Administrator.
According to our new procedures,
you have the right to appoint a Defense Counsel.
I would rather prefer to defend myself,
if you don't mind.
Very well.
Prosecutor,
you may begin your examination.
Falcon Eye,
you are being accused of murder of Brother Fireheart of Coat Lake,
the complicity to murder in at least 300 cases by your involvement with the so-called Cloak and Dagger Decree,
and at least another 250 cases by the obliteration of the Rebel Headquarters at Camp Freedom.
What do you have to say regarding these accusations which have been brought against you?
I can only say that I asked the Tribunal to decide upon the degree of my guilt at the end of my case.
I, myself,
speaking from the very depths of my feelings,
want to say that now,
after I have gained a full insight into all the horrible deeds which have been committed,
I am possessed by a deep sense of guilt.
Are you trying to say that you knew nothing about the atrocities at Camp Freedom?
That is hard to believe.
This operation was executed directly by Great Overseer Ironwill.
I had nothing to do with it.
As my fellow brothers can testify,
I was at the Holy Mountain the whole time.
But you also did nothing to stop him.
I did not even know about his plans until he and Brother Strongarm returned with the prisoner.
You were poorly informed for the Chief Overseer Security Administrator.
You cannot prove what I knew or not.
There is no question you knew about the Cloak and Dagger Decree.
I have here the original document, Exhibit FE-001.
Let me quote.
Hence, the Keepers of the Light is,
on principle, the death penalty.
Offenses are to be dealt within the field only if it is probable that the sentence of death will be passed upon the offender and the execution can be completed in a very short time.
Otherwise, the offenders are to be taken to the Holy Mountain.
In case anybody inquires about such prisoners,
they are to be told that they have been arrested but the proceedings do not allow any further information.
End quote.
Did you write this decree?
Yes.
So you assume full responsibility?
No.
But you wrote it.
Well, there is a principle which says that nobody can transfer more rights to anybody else than he has himself.
I was just a subordinate to great overseer Ironwill.
He wanted to keep the population quiet by demoting an atmosphere of mystery and fear.
Acting pursuant to order of a superior does not relieve you from responsibility.
You could have made a moral choice, but you didn't.
Because of your decree,
hundreds of citizens disappeared overnight,
and their families never knew what happened to them.
Please leave the judging to me,
prosecutor.
I'm sorry, your honor.
I was getting carried away.
Fork and I,
what about the murder of brother Fireheart?
Are you going to deny responsibility for that too?
I did what I was ordered to do.
These were thankless and difficult tasks.
I had to fulfill the overseer's commands under the hardiest exigencies of duty,
often acting against the inner voice of my conscience and against my own convictions.
The fulfillment of urgent tasks assigned by overseer Ironwill demanded complete self-abnegation.
I don't know what to say.
Your honor,
I need a break.
This is my first trial under the new rules,
and staying professional turns out to be a lot harder than I thought.
This is just the first trial of many.
What the Keepers stand for,
we will patiently and temperately disclose.
And we do not depend on their testimony or that of their foes.
We have undeniable proof of incredible events.
The tribunal will now adjourn until ten o'clock tomorrow morning.
Come in.
Lady GoldenEyes,
Sir Whisperwind wishes to speak with you.
Finally,
send him in.
Yes, my lady.
Whisperwind, I've been waiting for you all day.
What took you so long?
I'm doing fine, thanks for asking.
How about you, my lady?
So, tell me, how did the mission go?
Without a hitch.
Ivy Dash and Nettlebush made it back from Ferndale in one piece,
and they brought a good dozen hostages with them.
What a great day for the opposition.
How have they been holding up?
Was there a lot of resistance?
They had an easy time.
The teacher wasn't in the classroom.
All they had to do was round everyone up and go.
That sounds good.
Two of them managed to escape from the wagon during the ride,
but they are not going to be a problem.
And that sounds not so good.
Who were they?
Don't ask me.
One of them was some kind weirdo of Mongrel, the other one...
a pig?
Wait,
what?
A pig?
Yeah, I'm pretty sure that's what they said.
Why?
Oh, stupid idiots!
I am sorry?
Why didn't they go after them?
The kids are probably already dead,
and if not, they will be soon.
Calm down.
Everything will be okay.
The scheme is still going to work.
That's not the point!
Then what is your point?
By the holy mountain,
why do I have to justify everything to you?
Because as your future husband I need to understand what the hell you're up to.
You seem just a bit too eager for your new position.
This is so much more than just a new position.
We are at the beginning of a new age.
Lord Quicksilver, may he rest in peace,
has been gone for many years,
and there is still no legitimate successor.
I am his only heir.
It doesn't get more legitimate than that.
But people don't see you like that.
They see you as the Lord's widow, nothing more.
But as soon as we are Lord and Lady,
this will change, and the opposition will firmly stand behind us.
Don't forget, I still have the powers of the ancestors ready at my fingertips.
And that's good,
but it's a single artifact and it's not going to last forever.
We need to learn how to build our own,
but that might take a long time,
even if the Institute gives us what we want.
And for that you just stirred up the hornet's nest.
Ferndale is a long way from here.
I really don't want anything bad happening to you.
I love you.
Then stop acting like you're already the king of the land!
I have my personal reasons,
and I am still the Princess of Ironforge.
I can do whatever I please.
If you won't go after the escapees,
I will.
But that's crazy.
If the Institute has sent a search party,
there's a good chance you will run straight into it.
Why do these two kids matter so much to you?
Greenfield, get my mount ready.
I need to go out of town.
Meet me in the courtyard in an hour.
Yes,
my lady.
Your wish is my command.
Golden Eyes, you can't leave so close to the wedding.
What if something happens to you?
I need you here.
Ironforge needs you here.
Then you go! But why?
Is there anything I can do for you, sir?
This woman is giving me a hell of a headache.
I'm sorry to hear that, sir.
Would the sir like a glass of water?
Yes, that would be good.
Or wait, could I have a cup of tea instead?
Certainly.
Which kind of tea would the sir prefer?
I'll have rosehip tea,
please.
Rosehip and ginger,
with
a little bit of orange blossom honey.
Yes, could you do that for me?
I'm not sure we have that,
but I shall certainly try.
Thank you very much, Greenfield.
Just take your time.
I am not in a rush.
As you wish,
sir.
I hope that will keep him occupied for a while now.
Let's
see...
She never had second thoughts about our relationship.
Why is she suddenly getting cold feet?
Does she know something I don't?
Also, why does she suddenly bring up the artifact?
Wait a minute...
She used to wear it on her belt pretty much all the time, but not today.
It might just be a coincidence,
but what if it isn't?
Now where does she usually keep that thing?
Ah, there.
Now comes the moment of truth.
Oh,
it's not even locked.
Wow.
Now this explains a lot.
Okay, Bottlebrush, that's it.
I am not going to wait any longer.
If you don't act now,
I will.
Oh, Thistlethorn, what happened to knocking first?
I thought Raindancer was like a son to you.
I don't understand how you can just sit there and do nothing.
These are our children,
for the gods sake.
Yes, they are.
And just because I'm not running around like a headless chicken doesn't mean I am doing nothing.
You keep saying that,
but where are the results?
We are running out of time.
Why don't we negotiate with them?
Because you don't negotiate with blackmailers unless you absolutely have to.
But we only have two more days.
Two days can be a lot of time, Thistlethorn.
I trust my men to know what they are doing.
They have already tracked the kidnappers halfway through the dark woods,
and we have narrowed their possible destinations down to less than a handful of cities.
Ha! Less than a handful.
What an achievement.
Look, Bottlebrush, I am not stupid.
It's been raining all night.
If there were any tracks,
they're gone now.
Your experts are stuck.
Why can't you just admit it?
They are using proven scientific methods.
Methods that nobody has ever tried before.
Our ancestors aren't quite nobody,
are they?
You have a smug answer to everything, haven't you?
Professor Bottlebrush,
the smartass in charge.
And yet it is you and your damn institute who got us into all this trouble in the first place.
Hundreds of rebels have died to free our ancestors' thoughts and ideas from their Keepers of the Light,
and you have done nothing better than locking them back up.
The knowledge of an entire civilization put behind iron doors.
No wonder the opposition thinks we're scum.
The Keepers of the Light are gone,
but nothing has changed.
I have a question for you, Thistlethorn.
Do you know what the most defining characteristic of human civilization is?
Oh,
enlighten me.
It no longer exists.
The very science that led to its rise also led to its downfall.
Do you want history to repeat itself?
If yes,
go ahead and drop all that human knowledge on our society like a bomb.
If no, we have to share the knowledge responsibly.
That is what our schools are for.
We do not only teach science,
we also teach history and ethics.
Those things must go hand in hand.
I promise you that knowledge will not remain locked up.
We will share it, all of it,
but we'll do it responsibly.
We own the biggest arsenal of weapons in the world.
And yet we let those criminals walk into our classroom with nothing but swords and crossbows and take our kids.
Is that what you call acting responsibly?
Would you have preferred them walking into the classroom with grenades and assault rifles instead?
That is not what I said.
No?
Then what do you think would happen if we opened the walls underneath the Holy Mountain to everyone?
Thistle, it doesn't work that way.
We will get our sons and daughters back.
And we are going to use weapons if we have to.
But it will be the last thing to try, not the first.
I wouldn't want to live in a world where it is.
Would you?
No.
No, I wouldn't.
Queenie, no!
Holy mother of all that is fluffy.
We did it.
That must have been the scariest thing I've ever done in my life.
You get used to it after a while.
I have done this so many times.
I knew it would work.
It always works.
Well,
most of the time anyway.
This better be worth it.
Oh, trust me.
I've been on my own for such a long time.
I know how to get rid of the pig rats.
Just do what I do.
Okay.
Really?
Do I have to?
Oh, come on.
Just do it.
Okay.
Good.
And now we put them on display for the others.
Mine goes over here.
And yours goes over there.
Wow.
This is seriously creepy.
Mm-hmm.
And the great thing is,
it's creepy for other pig rats too.
It will make them stay far away.
That makes a lot of sense.
It must be part of their herd instinct.
Avoiding places where others have died gives them an evolutionary advantage, you know?
Yeah,
exactly that.
Whatever that means.
I
think we can light the fire now.
Oh, yeah.
I can do that.
Just give me a second.
Oh.
Wow.
How did you do that so fast?
This is called a lighter.
It's a human artifact.
I took it...
I mean, I borrowed it from Uncle Brushy.
We live in the same house, kind of.
Oh, the good old five-finger discount.
No, no, no.
I was going to give it back.
Hmm.
Oh, come on.
Since the keepers are gone,
everyone and their kids is out for the hunt of human artifacts.
I would do the same.
Uncle Brushy can't stop ranting about how everybody is now hoping to find something ancient they can sell for money.
The moment the keepers were gone,
some sites were literally ripped apart by treasure hunters.
Seems like this was one of the few things the keepers did right when they were still around.
A lot of people say there is not much of a difference between the Institute and the keepers.
Who would say such a thing?
The opposition,
for example.
They're wrong.
The Institute is a scientific organization.
Then why do they guard their knowledge like it's sacred?
Because they're afraid that history will repeat itself.
Our culture is not ready yet.
The Institute works hard to make sure that one day we will be,
but until then, some things are better kept under wraps.
But that's almost exactly what the keepers said.
No, no, no.
You just don't get it.
Whatever.
I'm just a pig.
What am I supposed to know about politics?
Well, you did join us for a reason, didn't you?
Just because of personal reasons.
Nothing political.
Your family?
I don't want to talk about it.
Why?
What happened to them?
Well,
what happened to yours?
Well, my father died saving the world.
And now everybody expects me to do the same.
You're not quite dead yet.
No, and I'm not planning to save the world either.
I just want to learn.
Isn't that the university symbol you are wearing around your neck?
The Tree of Knowledge?
Yeah, my mother gave it to me when I was little.
It has a long history,
like everything else at our home.
There's so much to discover in the old books that I could spend a lifetime in Uncle Brushy's room and never finish it all.
Like all the super secret stuff?
Most of it isn't,
but nobody really cares.
Like what?
Look at the sky.
Would you believe they could put machines up there?
They put machines up there which stayed there
on their own for hundreds of years.
Most of them have stopped working a long time ago.
And whenever you see a shooting star,
it might actually be one of the old satellites
burning as it falls back to the earth.
Wow,
that is amazing.
I could go on like that for hours.
I can imagine.
But no matter where we will go,
it's going to be a long walk.
We really should get all the sleep we can.
I don't think I'll be able to.
I never slept outside before.
It's scary and cold.
Then why don't you come over here?
And then?
Well,
we could cuddle up and keep each other warm.
What?
But we barely know each other.
Oh, well, we will know each other much better afterwards.
And it will make the night a lot less cold and lonely.
Seriously?
You like to cuddle with random guys?
No,
only with those I like.
Oh, OK.
Yeah.
Thanks.
What's the problem?
It's going way too fast.
I don't even I mean,
I've not been with.
Oh,
you've never been alone with a girl before.
Wait, wait, time out, time out.
Like not at all at your age.
I mean, how did that happen or rather not happen?
Because I'm a bloody nerd.
And what's the problem with that?
I don't know.
I mean,
you know what?
You don't know what, huh?
How?
How to how how to have sex with a girl?
Oh,
well, don't worry.
I can teach you that.
Oh,
come on.
I was just messing with you.
Believe it or not,
I'm cold and lonely, too.
How come you never seem to be afraid of anything?
Because being a pig means having a tough life.
I just stopped being afraid at some point.
And you know what?
Life has been a lot easier since then.
I have to show you something.
OK, what is it?
Just a second.
Have you ever seen something like
this?
Holy fuck.
Point that away from me.
Oh, it seems you have.
Oh, well, don't worry.
It's broken.
It doesn't do anything.
Where on earth did you get this?
That
is a gun,
a pistol, a human weapon.
You're not supposed to have that.
If the Institute find out you have that,
then...
Shh, calm down.
Nobody knows.
I found this on my way through the sea of debris.
I was digging for truffles and...
Truffles?
It's a pig thing.
OK.
Anyway, this was in a sealed box wrapped in some kind of oily rags.
How did you even know what it was?
I
heard about it before.
It's supposed to contain some kind of evil magic.
But I think it's long gone.
It doesn't do anything.
Oh.
Can I have a look?
Give it to me, please.
Carefully.
OK.
It's not loaded.
But it's in very good condition.
Exceptionally good.
I know a few people who would pay a fortune for an artefact like this.
I wasn't going to sell it.
Yeah, and you shouldn't.
If this gets in the wrong hands,
all hell is going to break loose.
It is that dangerous?
Oh,
yes. It's a deadly weapon.
And it cannot only hurt others, but also you.
You have to keep it oiled and clean.
And if there's any rust or dirt blocking the barrel,
it can explode right into your paw.
The bullets go in here,
into the clip down here.
And then you need to flip the safety off here.
Then you work the slide.
And that will move the bullet into the chamber, like this.
And then you point it at your target...
and pull the trigger.
Uncle Brushy let me fire a gun like this once.
Wow.
What is it like?
Not very nice.
It makes a really loud bang.
And the recoil makes your paws hurt.
I...
well, you could instantly kill anybody it's pointed at.
It scared the hell out of me.
Wow.
Well, good thing I didn't leave the bag on the carriage.
Unfortunately, a gun is useless without ammunition, so...
I feel so bad about the other students.
We could have saved them.
Hmm.
Maybe we can still do that.
If we only knew where to find some ammunition.
It's ammunition,
not ammunition.
Bullets.
But even if we had any,
and we knew how to find the others,
what would you do?
Walk in and kill everybody in your path?
Don't you have at least a little bit of your father's hero blood?
Trivia question.
What is the biggest difference between me and my father?
Beats me.
My father is dead.
Yeah, touche.
That sounded almost literate.
Oh, you!
Don't take me! No, no, no!
See?
I touched you and you didn't die.
Can't you ever take anything serious?
Ah, screw serious!
Survival happens in your head.
Are you sure you want to sleep all alone in the cold?
I promise you don't have to be afraid of me,
or anything else, as long as I am around.
Hmm?
Oh, come here.
I will take care of you.
And I'm a lot fluffier than I look.
Oh, what the hell, why not?
Thanks.
You're really nice.
Oh, shh! Don't tell anyone.
Oh.
Oh
Quicksilver,
this city is going to the dogs and no matter what I try,
it just keeps getting worse.
Tomorrow is the wedding.
I've been told it's the right thing to do.
The right thing for Ironforge.
And yet,
it feels so wrong.
I know you believed in Rebaian and that's why you had to join them.
But now that you're dead,
I don't know where to write or write anymore.
I miss you so much right now.
For
the last time,
no money, no booze.
Now get the fuck out.
You're a joke.
A fucking joke.
We know where your house lives.
And you're a fucking whore of a wife.
Yeah, I bet she didn't have a good fucking years.
Buy some real men,
not some lame dick like you.
Yeah,
yeah, let's go and fuck her good.
Come on, I still have a few bottles of Golden Marywood at home.
Fuck yeah.
Hey,
what the hell?
Do you see what I see?
Where?
Over there.
Isn't that the good lady Golden Eyes?
Holy shit, she's hot.
Hey, what's a pretty kitty like you doing here all alone?
That's none of your business.
Well,
if it isn't the grave of Lord Quicksilver,
the old coward.
He was not a coward.
Now get lost.
Not a coward?
My ass, he fucking ran away for a bloody rebellion.
For a rebellion that did nothing.
You'd better watch your mouth.
I am the Princess of Ironforge.
Princess of Ironforge?
You're not a princess.
You're a pussy.
What you gonna do?
Scratch us with your pretty claws?
Kill us with your magic stick?
We ain't got nothing to lose.
Nothing's worse than living in this shit hole.
We should remain named to
Ironforgery.
Fuck you and fuck Lord Quicksilver.
You know what?
I'm gonna piss on his grave.
Oh no, you won't.
Oh yes, he will.
Stop.
Pussy has claws, eh?
Now that turns me on.
And me too.
Hey, pussy, pussy, pussy.
No,
go away.
Leave me alone.
Look,
the pussy wants to play.
I can see it in her eyes.
I think she loves you.
I think so too.
You little pussy.
Just watch this, or you'll never have it.
Give me your pussy paws.
Help me.
Help.
Seems she left her magic stick at home.
Don't worry,
I've got just the need for her.
By the gods, are you okay?
Yes,
I'm fine.
It's okay.
You're safe now.
Those two aren't going to bother you ever again.
Thanks.
You're lucky that Greenfell saw you sneaking out.
Otherwise I wouldn't have known where to find you.
I'm so sorry.
Oh, my little kitty.
When are you going to learn?
Being a princess means a lot of responsibility.
I'm sorry too that Quicksilver is gone,
but now it's up to you to rule this city.
I can't do it,
Whisper.
I just can't do it.
If you manage to survive just one more night,
you won't have to carry this burden alone anymore.
I promise I will be there for you until death do us part.
My lady,
I'm neither a soldier nor a wizard.
To ensure your personal safety,
I would kindly request that you coordinate any nightly excursions with me first.
Are you putting me under arrest?
Of course not.
How am I supposed to take care of my city when I'm locked up at the palace like a scourge in a museum?
I need to be out here with the people in the city I grew up in.
I can't believe this is coming from the same woman who nearly got raped five minutes ago.
Would you have preferred we hadn't come for you?
I know I made a mistake.
And of course, I'm glad you came.
Next time I'll be more careful.
That won't be enough.
Ironforge has changed.
A lot of people want your throne.
It might change when we can finally build our own firearms,
but until then it's not safe out here.
Weapons, weapons, weapons!
For you, it's all about weapons!
Everyone's going at each other's throats.
Chaos.
Anarchy.
Building our own firearms will be the only way to ensure our freedom.
But instead of giving us the blueprints we need,
the Institute keeps them locked up in their ivory tower just like the Keepers did.
I know.
Then please tell me why I just had to save the woman who owns the most powerful killing device on this side of the Serpent River.
Because this place is a sanctuary.
I came here to grieve,
not to kill.
I'm sorry.
You could have died tonight.
I was worried.
You're right.
I should have been more careful.
Do you still love me?
Of course I do.
I know I love you too.
Now you go home with the guards.
I'll stay here with Greenfield and clean up this mess, alright?
The last thing we want is a public outrage.
Alright.
Good night, my love.
Good night.
Greenfield,
let's get these bodies out of sight.
We'll drop them by the mortuary so the Undertaker can take care of them tomorrow morning.
You take the arms,
I'll take the legs.
Yes, sir.
Heavy bastard.
How ironic.
Shot in a cemetery.
I
hate killing people in public places.
So many precious lives lost every day.
It's a tragedy.
You know,
the worst thing is the paperwork.
They want to know everything.
Why,
how,
when,
where.
Once I'm Lord of Ironforge,
this will get so much simpler.
I beg your pardon, sir?
The city needs a proper Lord again.
GoldenEyes is just too sensitive,
too soft.
You know what I mean.
I'm not entirely sure I do,
sir.
And I still don't get why she didn't bring her gun.
I mean, I know the whole killing business is not her thing,
but she knows how dangerous it is out here at night.
Yes,
sir.
Very peculiar,
Stop playing dumb, Greenfield.
She doesn't have it anymore,
am I right?
I'm not allowed to talk about it.
Oh, look how late it is.
I have to be right back.
Greenfield.
Please,
sir.
If I tell you this,
she's going to shoot me.
Greenfield.
First of all,
you just gave it away.
Secondly,
how?
I'm sorry, sir.
I'm not very good at politics.
That's fine, Greenfield.
Just tell me what you know.
Where is the gun?
It was stolen.
What?
How the hell did that happen?
Someone took it from a study and left without a trace.
And even stranger,
the bullets are still there.
And when was that?
The day after the execution.
The spy?
Yes,
the pig,
sir.
Anyways,
bullets are no bullets.
We need to get that gun back.
Greenfield,
go and see after her.
I'll be with you in a moment.
Yes,
sir.
Oh, Quicksilver, my old friend.
You were always so idealistic,
so courageous,
and so wrong.
Ironforge could be the capital of the world,
but you never realized that.
What am I supposed to do with your lady?
She's becoming a serious threat to my plans.
Any ideas?
No.
Thought so.
Sorry for invading your family like that old chap.
But if that's what it takes to make Ironforge great again,
it has to be done.
Wait.
Family.
That's how it all makes sense.
Quicksilver,
as much as I enjoyed this conversation,
I have to take my leave.
That's it.
I'm done for today.
It's getting dark and my paws hurt.
How about you?
There's something under this rock.
I can't hear it.
Maybe it's a bunker or a secret weapons stash.
Dream on.
Shut up and help me pry this thing open.
Okay, but this'll be the last thing I'll do for tonight.
There.
An opening.
I knew it.
And?
Can you see something?
It's full of water.
Of course.
What did you expect?
I have to find out what's in there.
No, be careful.
You don't know how deep it is.
I am an otter, stupid.
Oh,
damn it.
What is it?
Nothing down here but slimy daivery.
Not exactly unusual for the ruins of a 500-year-old war zone.
A smartass.
Wait, what is this?
A box?
Yes.
A small metal crate.
And wow,
it's much lighter than I thought.
Yeah, that probably means it's empty.
Empty means there's no water in it.
This might be our lucky day, pal.
I'll believe it when I see it.
Bring it up here.
Oh, something you're all interested in again.
Here, catch.
Hmm.
It's made of this super light metal that doesn't rust.
That alone is going to fetch a good price.
The lock was apparently made of iron.
It's almost completely gone.
What are you waiting for?
Open it.
Oh, my goodness, you were right.
This is our lucky day.
Now look what we have here.
It's a pistol and matching bullets.
In the best condition I've ever seen.
Barely any rust.
And it just works after so many centuries.
How crazy is that?
The humans made the most amazing materials.
This thing is worth a fortune.
We should bring it to the Institute.
No, are you nuts?
All they're going to do is confiscate it and lock it up with the thousands they already have.
And pay a very good reward.
That is nothing compared to what the opposition would pay.
But that would be totally irresponsible.
Says the grave robber.
This weapon is not some ancient human trinket.
If you're not going to report it,
I will.
In the wrong hands,
it could kill hundreds of people,
if not thousands.
Thousands?
You're exaggerating.
Just one is enough.
What do you mean?
I told you the Sea of Debris is a dangerous place.
I would have shared with you.
Too bad you'd rather die than be rich.
Farewell, my friend.
And rest in peace.
Finally, we're getting out of this damn forest.
I still have no idea where we are,
but where there's a road,
there must be a destination.
This must be one of the old roads that the humans built.
What makes you think that?
Well, because it's made of concrete.
Oh, well, a good thing it's not made of abstract.
Very funny.
Concrete is a sort of man-made rock.
They used it to build houses and roads and bridges.
Everything that needed to last centuries or longer.
Like this road here.
You're like a walking lexiclopedia.
It's encyclopedia.
You're so cute when you try to talk like me.
Don't you think we make a great team?
I'm all theory and you're all practice.
I think you mean I do all the heavy lifting and you won't stop talking.
I need a break.
My back is killing me.
Well,
then
come over here and
sit down for a moment.
What for?
Just do it.
Okay.
What?
Oh,
that's good.
Please don't stop.
See, I'm not all that useless, am I?
Your muscles are really tense.
If it hurts, tell me.
I don't think that you can even hurt me.
Sorry.
No, no, no.
Gone.
It hurts, but it hurts so good.
Okay.
You know what?
I've never felt safer than with you around.
And I usually don't trust people easily.
Really?
But you know so much about the world.
I have learned more from you than from any other class before.
And at school, you were the only one who didn't make fun of me.
That means a lot to me.
Well, you're lucky then.
It seems we are stuck with each other for a while.
It could be a lot worse, right?
Yeah, sure could.
By the way, I'm getting hungry.
I could really go for a piece of roasted pig right now.
Is there any left?
Oh, thank you.
Oh, yeah, yeah, sure.
There should be plenty left.
It's ra...
Where the hell did my bag go?
Uh, what?
I could swear I put it right here.
I can still smell it.
Oh, by the way, these are the remnants of an old communication system
that was ancient even by human standards.
And it was used to...
People could...
Uh-huh.
I think I found a thief.
Hey, I know you're in there.
Give us our food back.
Hey there, open up.
Whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa! What?
Okay, you want trouble?
You can get trouble.
I am going to puff and puff and shake
this...
We give up.
Here's your food.
What?
There's barely half of it left.
You thieves.
Have mercy.
It's hard to get by these days.
So hard.
We've been living on nothing but grubs today.
And yesterday.
And tomorrow.
Now that didn't make any sense.
Of course it didn't.
Then you brought pig rats.
So tasty.
So... Stop!
I think we got the message.
So you're living in this
thing?
Phone booth.
Whatever.
Oh, yes, yes, yes.
Most definitely, yes.
Always have.
Always will.
Then you can tell me where we are, right?
Of course.
Why do you even ask?
It's so obvious.
Okay,
then, okay.
Where are we?
You are no longer where you came from.
You're not yet where you're going.
Right now, you are right here.
Are you making fun of us?
Are you?
No.
I don't think we are.
Now
listen to me.
Do you see this guy over there?
Hi.
That is Rain Dancer.
And he knows how to set things on fire.
This includes that funny chicken shed of yours.
Phone booth.
So if you want to see the light of another day,
you better stop playing games with me.
Do you hear me, Mr.
Rubber Chicken?
I'm a rubber chicken.
I wonder if they taste like one.
All right, all right.
You win.
We lose.
My neck pipe.
It's gone.
One last time.
Where are we?
You are on the road to Iron Forge.
The glorious capital of the Iron Land.
The city of milk and pancakes.
Iron Forge.
Now that makes a lot of sense.
The idiot on the carriage,
he mentioned Lady Golden Eyes.
Oh,
the wonderful Lady Golden Eyes.
Princess of Iron Forge.
Her eyes are so golden.
So
that's where they've been trying to take us.
And that must be where the other students are.
We should go immediately back to Ferndale and tell everybody.
No,
we must go to Iron Forge and save the students.
And how are we supposed to do that?
With no weapons and no backup?
No nothing?
No, no, no, no, no.
You should definitely not go to Iron Forge.
Everyone wants the Lady's throne.
It's not safe.
She won't last long, that's for sure.
And how do you think we should go back to Ferndale?
On foot?
That will take at least a week and it's still pretty dangerous.
Oh, yes.
The woods are where the snapjaw lives.
Nasty snapping bites, you creatures.
But the pig rats are so tasty.
Birds,
can you please make up your mind?
You're not helping.
Yes.
No.
Maybe.
Rainy,
hand me the lighter.
Look,
look.
Someone is coming up the road.
Stranger danger.
We must hide.
Should we hide too?
It's too late.
We need to disguise.
Just play along, okay?
Oh,
lookie there.
Isn't there a more beautiful sight than the flowering of new love in the time of spring?
That was more like a deflowering.
Oh, hello there.
Oh, I'm sorry.
We really didn't expect anyone to come by so suddenly.
Oh, don't mind me.
I am just a dirty old man thinking about the time long ago.
Well,
my name is
Daisy Puff and this is my fiance.
It talks a lot.
I
hate you.
I'm an old man and yeah,
you know,
my ears are not so good.
How are your names?
Excuse me.
Daisy Puff it was.
And my fiance talks a lot.
Talks a lot, yeah.
My name is Amber Leaves and Ironforge is my humble home.
I haven't seen you two around here before.
We are pleased to make your acquaintance.
Pleased to make your acquaintance too.
Oh, well, isn't this a strange coincidence?
We were just taking a break on our way to Ironforge.
Do you think you could give us a ride?
Of course I can.
This is your first time to Ironforge and right on time for the big celebration.
Oh, really?
Yes, Lady GoldenEyes is going to get married.
After so many years,
Ironforge is finally getting to have a proper royal couple again.
The entire town is throwing a one big party.
You should definitely go and see it.
Oh, of course.
I love weddings.
But
when we arrive at Ironforge,
first thing we do is look for help.
Okay,
Uncle Brushy used to have some good friends in Ironforge.
One of them is Longleaf,
a very nice fellow.
As far as I know,
he runs a bakery there.
We'll find him and then we'll tell the Institute and let them handle everything.
And then we can enjoy the celebration.
Okay?
Oh, okay.
Before we go,
I have one humble request.
You see, my horse is thirsty and there is a little stream nearby.
Daisypuff,
could you help me getting some water?
And it's just a short walk and you talk a lot.
Maybe you could stay here and keep an eye on old Patsy.
Oh, sure.
Of course.
Sure.
No problem.
Easy, easy.
He's going to be back very soon.
Easy.
There you go.
I know who you are, poor tummy.
Shh.
Don't worry.
I'm your friend.
It seems we both have a common enemy and I'm going to make you an offer that you will appreciate.
I'm sure it's
right here in this bag.
Let's talk about it while we walk and
no word to the other guy, okay?
This will be our little secret.
Golden Eyes! Wake up,
honey.
Wake up! Quicksilver?
What is it?
I have to leave.
Now?
In the middle of the night?
Someone blew the whistle.
The Keepers are after me.
Greenfield is trying to stall them,
but I don't have much time.
Please tell me that's a joke.
I wish it were.
Oh, no.
I told you not to deal with the Rebels,
but you...
you goddamn bastard.
Don't cry.
But when they get you,
they will kill you.
I won't let that happen.
I promise.
But I really have to go now.
Go where?
To Camp Freedom,
the secret base at the Rebel Underground.
You are joining them?
It's now or never.
But I love you.
You can't just leave me like that.
I love you, too.
But right now, it's my only chance to survive.
And I'll be back.
I promise.
What about Ironforge?
Who's going to run this city while you're away?
You're the Princess.
Have you forgotten that?
I can't do this without you.
Oh, yes, you can.
You know a lot more about ruling this city than anybody else.
And it will only be for a short time.
Stormrunner has an excellent plan.
You will see.
The tyranny of the Keepers will be over very soon.
I'm sorry, but these are the Lord's and Lady's private rooms.
I cannot let you enter without permission.
I'm sorry, too, but your permission is irrelevant.
I love you.
Oh, for the God's sake,
get me that door open.
Goddamn.
I've spent too much time talking.
I have to leave.
Through the window?
There's no other way.
I love your golden eyes.
I'll see you after the revolution.
Quick, Silver!
All right.
Where is she?
Talk to me, woman.
I don't know what you're talking about.
The window.
Damn, there he goes.
Why in the God's name is nobody down there?
Don't stare at me like that.
Run, get him!
Oh,
there we are.
The marketplace.
If there's one place we find friends of the Interst Institute, then it's here.
So many people and everyone is wearing their finest for the big ceremony.
Look around for anybody wearing the Tree of Knowledge.
I wonder what kind of dress Lady Golden Eyes is going to wear.
Forget the wedding for a moment.
We must find Longleaf first.
Oh,
but I've never seen a royal wedding before in my whole life.
How about you stay here and keep searching and I watch the ceremony?
I'm sure it won't take long.
It's not like I'll be able to stop you anyway,
right?
Damn straight.
I'll be at the front.
Be safe.
OK.
Be safe?
Why would I not?
Hear ye,
hear ye.
Thank you very much to all for your presence and affection on this day.
Windsor Whisperwind,
the city's wealthiest entrepreneur and long-time consultant to the house,
receive the hand of our beloved Lady Golden Eyes,
Princess of Fire and Forge.
My dearest Golden Eyes,
many may believe that it was a fairy tale the way we came together.
And of course,
they are right.
It is always a fairy tale the way two people come together and decide to share life.
Yes, indeed, you are the Princess of Iron Forge,
but this cannot separate you from which you also represent.
You are built by your heritage and your role,
which makes you the person you are today,
ripe and ready for the tasks you have chosen in your life.
We see you as the revelation of sincerity and diligence.
And during the time we have known each other,
I have constantly been thinking of this.
Are we really meant for each other?
Then fate will surely arrange it all to the best.
The promise made today and the ties that abound here will greatly strengthen your union.
They will cross the years and lifts of each soul's growth.
Do you still seek to enter the ceremony?
Yes,
we seek to enter.
Whisperwind,
will you cause her pain?
I may.
Is that your intent?
No.
Golden Eyes,
will you cause him pain?
I may.
Is that your intent?
No.
Will both of you share each other's pain and seek it?
Yes, we will.
Above you are the stars.
Below you are the stones.
As time passes,
remember,
like the stone, your love should be firm.
Like the stars, your love should be constant.
Let the strength of your wills bind you together.
You may now kiss.
Let it be known that Whisperwind and Golden Eyes are in law and lady of Fire and Forge.
Hotami! Hotami! No! No!
This one is for my mother!
Hotami! You don't know...
You don't know what you're doing!
I told you not to come after me! Now you've ruined everything!
What the hell did you just do?
I made history! What?
Run!
Don't talk! Run!
What the...
Guards! Where are the guards?
Come on, run!
Oh, shit!
Shit, shit, shit, shit!
The assassins are fleeing! Cease them!
Oh, come on!
Come on, horse!
Hold on! It's going to be a bumpy ride!
Who is there?
It's me, Whisperwind.
Oh.
To what do I owe the honor of this unexpected visit?
Oh, I just happened to be nearby,
and I thought, why not pay the old hammerfist a visit?
Well, it's always a pleasure to welcome a good customer,
but I'm sure you're not here for some idle chatter.
You know me too well.
How is the work on the gun going?
Well, we...
I don't think we can do it.
This is not what I wanted to hear.
I know,
I know, but I'm an honest man,
so I'm telling you like it is.
This is THE Literal Ironforge,
the one that this city is named for,
well known far beyond its limits.
And you are telling me you can't build a little device with less than a dozen parts?
Not even with a model to work from?
I am deeply
disappointed.
Oh, it is a small device, that's true.
But there's a lot more to it than meets the eye.
The humans were amazing blacksmiths.
Then consider it a challenge!
This is a challenge,
if I've ever seen one.
Did you get to examine the ammunition I sent you?
Of course.
The bullets are like pieces of art,
each one a marvel of precision.
I've never seen anything like it before.
I think we could make a few,
but it will take a long time and a lot of work.
Then what are you waiting for?
Get down to it!
I'm beginning to wonder what the hell
I'm paying you for.
Yes, sir.
Of course, sir.
I hope you are aware
though that the bullets will be useless without the black powder that makes them go bang.
Do I look like an idiot?
The finest alchemists of the city are working on it.
As soon as we have figured out the formula,
you will get your powder.
Now what is keeping us from
building our own guns again?
The material.
Even our strongest iron does not seem to be hard enough.
Not hard enough?
You are known to make the hardest iron in the world.
It is like it is.
We've not been able to fire more than a handful of shots before the gun breaks.
And the aim is terrible.
I'm at my wits end.
I paid you a fortune to produce
a reliable gun and you said you can do it.
I was wrong, I'm sorry.
And if you want your
money back, I can totally understand that.
Let me talk to the cashier and I...
Listen to me, you little dimwit.
I am Whisperwind of Ironforge.
You don't bail out on me like that.
There are not many parts of the city that I do not own.
These guns were built before
and if you ever want to do any business in this town again,
you are going to find out
how to build them again.
Understood?
But it is...
but it is impossible.
Then what would it take to make it possible?
The knowledge of a human blacksmith.
All right,
then this is what I shall get for you.
And how are you going to do that?
Break into the Holy Mountain and steal all their books?
There is no need to break in if you know who has the key.
I have to go and make a few arrangements.
You're going to hear from me.
Please excuse me.
Ah...
Hold still.
Slow.
Come on.
Careful, careful.
Oh, fuck.
It hurts.
Don't move your arm.
It looks a lot worse than it is.
Don't touch me.
I just want to help you.
I said don't touch me! Please,
Rainy.
Let me explain.
Shut
up.
Just shut up! No,
no.
Please, let me explain.
Just don't move your arm, okay?
No, no, no, don't touch it.
Don't pull it.
Don't.
It will just...
Great.
Now you're bleeding like a stuck pig.
So what?
You are going to die if we don't stop it.
Come here.
I told you to leave me alone.
Hold
still.
By the gods.
Why can't you just...
Why can't you just leave me alone?
Because I care about you.
Then why did you do this to me?
Look,
I didn't want this to happen to you.
You shot the princess.
You shot the goddamn princess.
What the fuck did you expect?
This barn hasn't been used since old Barleycorn gave up his farm.
We will be safe here if you stop yelling.
You know this place?
This is where I grew up.
Wait.
You grew up in Ironforge?
Until I ran away.
Why didn't you tell me?
Because...
You better be honest with me now.
Because I was afraid you would hate me.
Go on.
My father died in the rebellion.
I grew up only with my mother and we were the only Riverhawks in town.
Ironforge has always been firmly in the hands of the opposition and there is just no place for pigs in their vision of a new world.
The Institute took us in.
People tend to underestimate the wits of a hawk and that made mother a perfect spy against the opposition.
She was the one who uncovered the opposition's war plans.
War plans?
The sea of debris is littered with human artifacts.
But working weapons are extremely rare.
They've been trying to recreate some of the artifacts they found but with no success.
Are you a spy too?
No.
I wasn't supposed to know any about this.
But I was curious.
When I pressed my ear against the wall in my room I just could hear everything they said.
Where is your mother now?
She's dead.
She ran into a trap and got arrested.
GoldenEyes decided to make an example of her and scare the mob back into submission.
She executed my mother in the marketplace using this very gun.
They tried to lock me up on the orphanage,
but I ran away.
I knew how to get into the palace without getting caught so I took the gun and I swear
if I had known that it needs bullets to work I would have killed GoldenEyes right there.
But the gun only clicked.
You lied to me.
You lied to me and the people in Ferndale who took you in.
You lied to everyone.
You don't know how it is to grow up as a pig.
Being powerless,
helpless,
wearing a smile like a mask.
This weapon was the only power I ever had.
Who gave you the bullets?
The man who took us to the city did.
You know him as Amberleafs.
Everyone else knows him as Whisperwind.
Whisperwind.
The man who just married Lady GoldenEyes.
But why?
And why you?
How did he even know we were coming?
It makes no sense.
He secretly works for the Institute.
Ironforge is still a bastion of the opposition and GoldenEyes is the key to reclaiming it.
Whisperwind married her because it makes him the legitimate ruler of Ironforge.
But to remain in power he must remain free of even the slightest suspicion.
The opposition has been searching for me since I ran away.
And when Whisperwind heard that I was among the kidnapped students from Ferndale,
he knew where to look for me.
And he also knew that I was out for revenge.
He made me an offer I couldn't refuse.
Two bullets to make this a victory for my mother and for the Institute.
No.
No, he is not one of us.
This would have been murder plain and simple.
It would have been against all the
principles the Institute stands for.
If you had spent more than a day at our school you would know that.
Whisperwind saw your blind hate for Lady GoldenEyes and abused you for his own selfish reasons.
And no,
he is on the good side.
Your side.
And so am I.
No,
no, Potami.
Hate is never on the good side.
You taught me how to make love.
I wonder if you even know what love is.
You pretended to be my friend.
But in the end all that mattered to you was that I showed you how to work that fucking gun.
Am I right?
No, that is not true.
And when you shot that lady,
I was the one who took the bullets so you
could get away.
Right?
No,
no.
Would you also...
No, I even came back to save you.
Yeah, right.
And would you have come back if your plan had worked?
Do you think I might still be useful for you after all?
No, I did it because I love you.
Save your breath, Potami.
I am not going to play this game any longer.
I have real friends to find in this city.
No,
no,
please.
Fuck.
Rainy!
I am okay.
Everything is just peachy.
Be safe.
No,
at least take the gun with you.
I don't need a gun.
Nobody needs a gun.
I'm on the good side and I'm going to prove it.
Whisperwind told me where to find him.
We will free the students and find the kidnappers and put an end to all of this.
And please,
please be wrong.
By the gods, please be wrong.
Rocky! Hey, Rocky!
Oh, for fuck's sake.
Stop swearing on the job.
You know, the gods are always listening.
Which ones?
The ones in the holy mountain that turned out not to exist?
Or the other ones who let this shit happen?
You're a hopeless case.
Hope?
I must have lost that motherfucker somewhere between all the dead bodies.
Let me know if you find it.
Anyway,
meet your new volunteer,
Honeyfoot of Ferndale.
Hello, honey.
Oh,
please, don't call me honey.
My friends call me foot.
I hope you're going to last longer than the guy before you,
honey.
I shall do my best.
And again,
please call me foots,
not honey.
Look, honey, I've stopped counting how many helpers I had.
I couldn't care less what your fucking name is,
because tomorrow you'll be gone like everyone else.
Listen, you weasel-headed cockwomble.
I don't fucking care what your shit-ass problem is.
If you don't want my help,
you can go take a flying fuck at a rolling donut.
You worthless, fucking cockspot.
Oh, oh,
you know what?
I like you.
I think I really like you.
Finally,
someone who's not made of glass.
Hello, foots.
Name's Rocky.
Welcome to Camp Freedom,
your worst nightmare.
I have a strong stomach.
Yeah, that's what they always say.
Here, take one of these.
Tie them around your head so it covers your muzzle.
Ooooooh.
Yeah, I know.
Stings a bit in your nose,
but you'll get used to it.
It's nothing compared to the smell of the bodies.
This used to be the headquarters of the Rebel Underground,
until the Keepers found out about it.
They came in the night,
knocked everyone out with their magic shock rods,
then set the place on fire.
Most of the Rebels burned to a crisp.
However, some did not.
Judging from where the bodies are,
some of them must have woken
up trying to escape the flames.
Their remains are scattered all around the place.
Some have been eaten by the pig rats,
and what's left of them is not pretty.
And how do we go about cleaning this mess up?
The other team brings the Rebels and all their belongings that made it through the fire and
line them up over there.
Then it's our job to identify them.
If we find out who they
are, we send them back to their families so they can be given a proper burial.
Everyone else gets an anonymous grave right here.
Okay,
I told you I have a strong stomach,
so let's get started.
Alright.
Get one of the bags,
I'll show you what to do.
Let's see who's in this one.
Ooh, we're lucky.
This one's pretty much in one piece.
We must cut his clothes off and see if he's got anything on him that might tell
us who he is.
Documents, jewelry, anything.
Gotcha.
Hmm.
Must have been a shirt.
Well, the rest of him is charcoal.
Oh,
wait,
he's wearing a ring.
Good.
If it's a wedding ring,
it might have an inscription.
But how do we get it off?
We don't.
Yuck, the finger comes right off.
And it's a wedding ring.
Golden eyes and quicksilver.
Oh,
congratulations.
Your first case is a celebrity.
You mean this is Lord Quicksilver of Iron Forge?
The one and only.
So the rumors were true.
He really did join the Rebellion.
Ah, well,
and now he's dead.
I hope it was worth it.
Yeah, I hope so too.
As much as I disliked the Keepers,
at least they kept the lands united.
Now, who rules the rulers?
It's a small wonder we're not at war with each other yet.
Yeah, it's a very unstable situation.
Oh, yes it is.
Do you believe in gods?
Nope.
Neither do I.
But I do believe in the good in man.
So let's make sure the Lord gets back to Iron Forge where he belongs.
Oh, excuse me, sir.
What is it?
I am looking for Longleaf's bakery.
Longleaf, you say?
Yeah.
Why?
Because, well, they say he makes the best sweet rolls on this side of Serpent River.
I've come all the way from Coldlay to get some for my mother's birthday.
Your story fills me with determination and hunger.
But nope,
sorry,
never heard of anyone called Longleaf.
However,
if it's sweet rolls you want,
try Sugar Tooth on Vine Street.
His almond pastries are delicious.
Ah, okay.
Thank you, sir.
Have a good day, sir.
Take care.
Man,
finding Longleaf can't be that hard.
How many bakeries can there be in a town like this?
Excuse me, sir.
Hmm?
I'm looking for someone called Longleaf.
Hmm.
He's supposed to be running a bakery here somewhere.
So you don't know him?
Uh-uh.
Oh, and he might be wearing a symbol like this one.
Listen, you little mongrel! Uh-huh.
We don't welcome rebel scum like you around here.
Okay, okay, okay, easy, easy.
This city belongs to us.
Okay.
If your friend ever lived here,
we'd probably send him to hell where he belongs.
Now bugger off!
I'm just here for the sweet rolls,
honestly.
I don't want to cause any trouble.
Have a nice day, sir.
Holy shit, that was close.
This is not the Ironforge that Ankur brushes books.
No, no, no!
Stop making a fuss already.
I'm your friend.
Longleaf!
Thank the gods, I thought I'd never find you.
You have no idea what kind of huge and dangerous ruckus you have been making.
What?
I...
There's so much I need to tell you.
But let's go somewhere else first.
How about your place?
My place?
After shooting the princess and asking bloody everyone for my name,
while waving the bloody tree of knowledge in their face,
there is now a bloody mob in front of my shop,
smashing my windows.
I hope you have a damn good reason for showing up like this.
Look, you're the only one I know.
Lady GoldenEye has had the entire class kidnapped from the school in Ferndale,
but Putami and I managed to escape.
I started looking for you the moment we arrived here,
but then we...
You decided to kill Lady GoldenEye first, in broad daylight!
No, but Putami did it.
I even tried to stop her.
Oh,
so it was her.
You know her?
Only know her mother.
Without her, our presence here is down to nothing more than a couple of veterans.
Too
bad you didn't go for Whisperwind instead.
He is the one who deserves to be shot,
not GoldenEye's.
But...
but Whisperwind managed to convince Putami that he is with the Institute.
I'd have expected her to know more about the Institute than our codex.
Well, what do you expect from a pig?
Wow, stop right there.
That's not how you talk about your girlfriend.
She betrayed me.
She is not my girlfriend.
Rubbish, of course she is.
What even thinks she rescued you first?
Coincidence.
And why do you think she took you with her all the way through Darkwoods?
Because she knew she needed me.
But she didn't need you anymore once you were here.
I don't know and I don't care.
Really?
Then why didn't she leave you behind?
I have no idea.
Boy,
you are in full on denial.
She cares about you.
A lot.
Don't you see that?
Then why did she hurt me so much?
Someone killed her mother.
Imagine the pain she's gone through.
When Whisperwind gave her the chance for revenge,
that made her forget everything else and it clouded her mind with hate.
Yes, it was wrong,
but it can happen to any of us.
Not to me.
Well,
let me guess who told her how to use the gun.
It was you, right?
Yeah,
yes, it was me.
Did she ask you for it?
So the truth is,
you wanted to impress your crush and your feelings made you blind to the consequences.
Like, for example, that you were effectively teaching her how to shoot the lady.
So don't ever again say it doesn't happen to you.
It does all the time.
So,
you know where your girlfriend is now?
She wanted to meet Whisperwind.
He's an expert boyfriend that'll walk right into his trap.
I was mad at her.
That means she deserves to die or what?
I'm such a bloody idiot, ain't I?
For God's sake, I'm such an idiot.
Does she still have the gun?
Yeah.
Let's hope she'll shoot the right guy this time.
Stop being so goddamn cynical.
Look,
GoldenEyes doesn't want the public to know she kidnapped innocent students.
And Whisperwind won't be too happy about witnesses to his conspiracy running around either.
And on top of all of that,
the public thinks you're the accomplices to an attempt at murder.
The entire city is against us,
literally.
All we can do is get the news to Ferndale and hope for the best.
I wonder what Riversong would have done.
Your father.
Why would that matter?
Because he was a hero.
He went out of his way to save my mother back during the rebellion.
He's also dead.
If it is my fate to die for a good cause,
so be it.
That's the stupidest thing I've ever heard.
I screwed up big time.
I can't just sit here and wait.
You're doing that emotional thing again.
Just look at yourself.
Your arm is still bleeding.
You couldn't even hold a butter knife.
You're crazy.
Don't touch it.
Better tell me where I can find Whisperwind.
Well,
how would I know?
He's probably either at home or
telling lies to his wife.
Or he might be spending the night at one of his brothels.
His brothels?
You
didn't know?
The Cat House is probably the only business in Ironforge that still turns a solid profit.
Extractions from misery are in high demand these days.
They let the sleaziest guy in town marry the princess?
All that matters is gold these days.
And of that, he's got plenty.
He's not going to meet Botami at the palace,
so they must be at the Cat House.
Maybe.
But what are you going to do?
I'll come up with something.
You go to get help from Furnir,
and I'll go save my girlfriend.
Oh, now she's your girlfriend again.
Well then, good luck.
Oh, what kind of flowers would you like on your grave?
White chrysanthemums for love,
truth, and a long life.
Oh, by the gods, grow up!
Goodbye, Longleaf.
No,
you're making a mistake.
The enemy's in the majority.
I can't help you when...
Goodbye.
There he goes! He's the one! Let's get him!
Fuck!
Fuck! Fuck!
Oh,
what a surprise! Lady visitors have become so rare these days.
Welcome to the Cat House.
My name is Snowflake.
Is this your first visit here?
Yes, but...
There's no reason to be ashamed.
This is the first time for everything.
The Cat House proudly caters to all species,
sexes, and preferences.
So,
tell me,
are you into boys or into girls?
Or maybe even both?
Maybe even at the same time?
Um,
I'm actually here to see Lord Whisperwind.
Oh,
you're here for an audition.
Why didn't you say so?
Um,
when was your appointment again?
I don't have an appointment.
I just want to talk to the Lord, if that's possible.
My name is Potami.
He knows me.
That should be possible,
but
it may take a while.
The Lord is terribly busy at the moment.
No problem.
I'm not in a rush.
I hope you realize that just talking is not going to get you a job here, right?
I appreciate the advice,
but I really just want to talk.
All right, just saying.
Can I fetch you something to drink?
We have a whole new menu with original human recipes.
Um, I don't know.
What would you recommend?
There's a hot drink called coffee.
And let me tell you,
that one really gets your juices flowing.
Um, sounds nice.
Perfect! I'll get you one!
Well, well, Whisperwind.
So,
how does it feel to be a Lord?
Oh, it's the most glorious feeling in the world.
Oh, even better than my pussy.
Why compare when I can have both at the same time?
You're such a naughty boy.
Cheating on your lady on your wedding night?
Getting rid of her turned out to be harder than I thought.
But next time I come to see you,
it won't be cheating anymore.
I promise.
You know that my lips are sealed.
You can come in any time.
I'm always up for a good fuck.
How much time do you have?
I've got all the time in the world.
Let's take it nice and slow.
Oh,
Whisperwind,
you son of a rat.
You're going to pay for this.
I swear.
You are so going to pay for this.
Here's your cup of coffee.
Black and hot,
just as it should be.
Oh,
thank you.
I've never had coffee before.
Try it.
Good, isn't it?
Snowy?
Yeah?
Hey,
he wants the slow routine tonight.
Can you get me the cuffs and the blindfold?
Sure thing.
Here you are.
Thanks.
Now,
it looks like this is going to take a while.
Are you sure you want to continue waiting?
Well, it's not as if I had a choice.
Oh, well, your decision.
Enjoy your coffee.
Thank you.
Wait,
Snowflake.
Yes?
Ah,
you're right.
Just talking isn't going to impress the Lord.
So I thought maybe you could tell me a little bit about him.
Like the stuff that really rocks his boat,
if you know what I mean.
If you want to,
I could ask Moonshine if she'd be up for a little chat later.
She's the Lord's favorite,
and she knows everything about him.
Can you come back tomorrow?
No,
I only have time today.
But maybe you could ask her,
like,
maybe she would let me watch?
I like how you think.
Well, you're in training already.
You're such a kinky little pig.
Oh,
sorry.
No offense.
Just let me talk to Moonshine.
Hey,
Moonshine.
Yeah?
What is it?
The young girl over there.
She was wondering if you'd let her watch, maybe?
Yes.
Really?
Great.
Why not?
Okay,
Moony is fine with it.
But you have to stay absolutely still.
If the Lord finds out,
we're going to lose more than just our jobs.
Get it?
Yes!
Oh
Yes,
your paws are magic take your time ladies take your time
You can't imagine what an exhausting day I have
weddings
assassinations
Yes, go on like that.
Yeah right there so soft
Whisper wind whisper
Oh, well so much for the long routine
Wow, that's the first time I've seen you fall asleep with a pair of tits on his face
He must be very tired shall we wake him up again?
No,
please.
I'm glad that I don't have to listen through another night of confessions
You should write a biography
I totally could and I could swear it turns him on it's like his personal way of talking dirty
What a strange guy.
Oh, that's at least untie him.
Okay
I'm sorry little one that usually plays out a bit differently.
Oh, well
Thank you.
Anyway
You did your best.
Oh the only way to survive in this job.
See you later
I'm afraid you won't get your audition today little one.
Oh Yeah, it looks like it
too bad you can't come back tomorrow
You're remarkably sexy for a pig.
Oh
Thank you.
That was almost not racist
Okay,
it's time for me to leave then
Thank you for the coffee and the demo
I've learned a lot today.
Have a good night toodles
Business seems to be slow today.
Excellent.
Now just you wait whisper
I
think I'm going to keep those clothes
Rain dancers going to have a stroke if he sees me like that
I just
fall asleep
Damn that never happened to me before
Are you still oh,
oh, oh, yes you are
Yeah, yeah
Moonshine you are the best.
Oh, that's stupid pig
fights to shoot gold mice at arm length Oh God, yes
Then the other guy takes her down and
bursts my busts my plan
Faster moonshine faster You know that bitch was
one of the bloody hostages from Ferndale
Turns out she is the bloody daughter of that spy.
We killed a couple of weeks ago.
Oh Yeah Yes
Told her I am with the Institute told her everything she wanted to hear
Stupid little pig was so hell-bent on revenge.
I didn't even have to pay her
Faster
faster.
Yeah, the irony is it was me who made the lady kill her mother
It was not me all along
Careful with your teeth, huh?
You know, I like it rough.
Don't you?
You're going to love what comes next What the fuck
You
Right iron forge
and you betrayed gold not you betrayed me
Because you wanted the throne and you wanted it alone
No matter what you do
Neither will your best friend from Ferdinand
I can help it
Is that all you got come on kill me kill me do it push harder harder
No, I Know you couldn't do it
in the end.
You're just a dirty little pig
What did you just say?
Yeah
Dirty
Pig nobody calls me
Maybe
you do deserve to die
but enough blood has been spilled.
I Need to put things right and I really don't want to leave the nice ladies without that body in their bedroom
Who taught me oh
What the fuck happened here?
Oh
I Got my audition after all
much
The Lord just had the right of his life.
He needs to rest
See you
Wow just All right May I have your attention, please?
I would like to bring out a toast may all human knowledge be free and may iron forge become great again
to the opposition and our allies Cheers
All right whisper wind now you got to share the story what made this such a good day for us
Where are you not at the execution this afternoon?
Some of us still have to work to earn a living, you know
Fair enough fair enough with today's execution.
We killed two birds with one stone.
I thought she was a pig Yes
Yes,
and she was the most important informant for the Institute in this town.
They are now officially deaf and blind
But what is even more remarkable
I got the lady to do the deed herself in person
Haha,
I have finally managed to convince her that the gun is the only thing that keeps her in power
She is all in I just started a little operation that will hit the leaders of the Institute where it hurts the most
I can't tell you the details
But these guys are so deeply ingrained in their own ideals about peace and pacifism
They don't even have guards on their city walls.
You could just walk in and then do whatever you want like let's say
Kidnap their children and then walk out again and nothing's gonna stop you.
Can you believe that?
That means we will soon have exclusive access to the blueprints to create our own human weapons
The forge is fired up
Just a few days I will be the lord of iron forge
with our new weapons
We will be the superior power of all the lands.
We will crush the Institute
We will conquer the holy mountain and we will unite the lands under our rule ship
And this my friends
this city will be the new capital of the world
The opposition will make iron forge great again
Dear mom,
i'm sorry, you couldn't make it to our wedding on such short notice,
but I hope that
Screw it.
I'm not sorry and she knows it
Dear mom,
I am so glad you were not at my wedding today
Because someone almost killed me
No,
it's going to scare her to death
Dear mom,
I wish you were here right now
Because this is my wedding night and my blood in your husband is not
No, no, no, no, no, no No Too honest
way too honest
Damn,
why is this so hard?
Hello princess
My god
Please not so loud.
We're in enough trouble as it is and yelling will just make it worse
Are you going to kill me now
In cold blood like you killed my mother
Oh
That wasn't cold-blooded
Believe me
It was the worst thing I ever did in my life
They told me I had to give the people a taste of my power
I didn't want to but
they insisted
I drank myself senseless until I thought I was ready to do it
I had the gun
I thought it would be easy just
Pull the trigger and be done with it
But it wasn't that easy
Not at all
You can't imagine how much time I've spent waiting for this chance
So many sleepless nights filled with thoughts about killing you
But you know what?
I changed my mind
Here
Take the gun
I don't want it anymore
Does it mean you forgive me
No
I will never able to forgive you
But hate is a treacherous guide
It turns you into a beast
Sweet revenge dangling in front of you like a carrot held by whoever rides your back
If you didn't come for revenge
Why are you here?
To make right what I did wrong
To save many lives including your own
And to save Ironforge, my home
And if you just have a shred of good left in you
You will help me
You're very brave
And well-spoken
Yeah, I practiced my speech the entire way from the cat house
The cat house?
Oh yeah, the cat house
Whisperwind is not on your side
It was him who gave me the bullets to shoot you
He knew that I was ready to do it
We have a common enemy were his exact words
That can't be true
I swear it is
From the very beginning he was planning to get rid of you as soon as he's the new lord of Ironforge
But it didn't work out
And he is on his way right here right now to personally make sure that his face will be the last thing you will ever see
And how are you supposed to know about all this
Because I was there when he confessed it to his favorite whore
You're lying!
My lady! My lady!
The lord just ordered the officer of the guard to take you in custody
I locked all the doors but that's not going to stop them for long
You must flee while you still can
And how on earth did you get in here?
This building has more holes in it than a piece of cold lake cheese and my mother knew them all
Whisperwind, you son of a whore
I've never trusted him
And I wish I had listened to you earlier Is there anyone else left on our side?
Unlikely,
he is the lord now No one will dare to disobey him
That means we're lost No, we are not
There are still a few friends around who will fight with us And you are going to lead us there
Me?
How?
Shhh!
He can hear us
Golden eyes,
are you in there?
Open the door!
Okay,
now this is my plan Golden eyes
We will go there and I will not...
Who else is in there with you?
Open the door!
This is an order!
This is a great plan!
I'll stay here and put Whisperwind on the right track
But this will be your end! You know you don't have to do this
Maybe,
but I'm not a small field I am a green field,
my lady My decision stands
Green field,
you're the most honorable man I have ever met
I will make sure your name will always be remembered
Stop talking and follow me, okay?
Alright
Alright,
you wanted it this way!
Light
so bright,
light so pure
Keepers of the light,
answer me true Oh, for the last time,
stop singing that song!
I have to do something to keep me sane!
Right now you're the one who drives me insane!
Guys, stop yelling at each other! All we can do right now is be patient and wait for help
You mean pray for help?
Rubbish! Professor Bottlebrush will do everything he can to get us out of here
He will come! If he ever finds us
Should be a breeze with all his human science and weapons and gadgets and stuff,
right?
Then what is taking him so long?
Ironforge is a big city
Do you really think he would use human weapons to rescue us?
Wouldn't that be totally against his ideals?
Not only that,
couldn't that be exactly what the opposition wants?
There's no point in speculating
What else should this be about?
The opposition is not exactly short on gold,
that's for sure
I wonder who of us they're going to kill first?
Shut your fucking piehole!
I'm just stating the inevitable
You can keep the inevitable to yourself!
I hope Braindancer made it back to Ferndale
Braindancer?
No way he's gonna survive the dark woods on his own He hides under his bed every time there's a thunderstorm I've seen it Then what about the pig?
She's a red river hog if you please Well,
pigs are tough She could have made it Why would she help us?
She did not make a single move to rescue us when she had the chance Yeah,
bloody pig! We're doomed
I give up Feel as gloomy as you like This is a free prison
after all Light so bright Run not again!
Light so pure Wait,
did you hear that?
If
it's one of the Morans from the wagon,
we might be able to overwhelm him Do you think we can work together just this one time?
You guys go over there,
and you guys go over
there And on my command,
we all jump If he's stupid enough to come in here anyway Ouch!
Shh!
One...
Two...
Stop! Don't jump! What the hell?
Ah, that's it!
Everything is in place
Now all we have to do is wait for Whisperwind to show up and spring the trap
I can't wait to make him pay for what he has done
If he shows up at all
Greenfield told them where to find us
He's way too proud not to show up
Well, but he will have a small army in town very likely
We can only hope they are still more loyal to you than him
His power hangs by a thread
People obey him to keep their heads on their shoulders
And that's it
If we manage to take him out,
they will be on my side,
not his Let's hope so, by the gods
I still don't know how you could fall for a guy like Whisperwind
Well, you fell for him too, didn't you?
Touche
He knows precisely how to use your fears against you
What were you afraid of?
Losing Ironforge When Quicksilver died, I was suddenly very lonely
And all I knew about ruling a city was what I had overheard at dinner parties
Whisperwind was both an experienced leader and an experienced lover
He was exactly what I needed
Also, I thought...
What was the kidnapping about?
The most important leaders of the Institute live in Ferndale
And Whisperwind was mostly interested in weapons
Being able to make our own guns would have made us the most powerful city in the world
So, we tried to blackmail Ferndale into giving us access to the library
And people say pigs are into dirty business
I feel nothing but shame right now
If I could turn back time,
I would Oh, shh! I think they are coming
Golden Eyes, I know you are here Come out and show yourself
Shall I give the signal?
No,
not yet,
they are too far away
There's no point in hiding
Your friendly butler sang like a little bird
Come closer so we can talk
Oh, is that the little piggy speaking?
But I can hear you perfectly from over here
I want Golden Eyes
Send her out now and nobody gets hurt Shit,
what now?
Shh,
patience If he wants to get us,
he will have to move closer
And then we will get him
Golden Eyes is not here
If you want to know where she is,
come over here and we will talk
Of course she's here
Come out now, this is my final warning
The final warning and then what?
The final warning...
Before I kill your boyfriend
Fuck! No! Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck! What is it?
He's got Rain Dancer
The man who saved your life Oh,
fuck, for fuck's sake, why didn't I see this coming?
Oh, stupid pig, stupid pig, stupid pig
Okay,
let's put an end to all this
I'm going out there right now Shh, no!
I still have an axe to grind with this guy
You can still surrender when I am dead
Now hide,
I don't want him to see you
And don't give the signal until I tell you, okay?
Okay
I'm so sorry,
I just want to help you I love you,
Potami I know Now shut up
So,
you want to play rough, Whisperwind?
I can play rough too
One false move and you're dead Now let him go
Oh, you stupid little piggy But this is not going to work
Don't push me! I know that you don't have any bullets left I gave you two and you wasted them both
You're forgetting about GoldenEye,
Stache You mean this one?
Oh, fuck!
And now you're going to hand me the gun
I said hand me the gun,
not drop the gun
How long is this going to take?
Okay,
alright,
here is your goddamn gun I hope you will kill yourself with it
Just why do pigs have to get mad on everything?
But anyways...
I think it's time to end this story Farewell, little piggy
My eyes!
GoldenEye, no!
My eyes! I can't see!
In case you don't know the feeling,
this is a sword against your throat
So,
what are you going to do?
Kill me?
I am the Lord of Ironforge!
No,
you are not!
You are a criminal,
a trickster,
a murderer
You are nothing without me The people of Ironforge will never accept a woman as their leader,
never!
I'm not one of your ally cats My family has been ruling this city for many generations and we never betray our own people!
So,
who do you think they are going to obey?
Me or you?
Well,
let's find out,
shall we?
Let the soldiers go!
Now,
give them back their weapons!
So,
my lord,
what would you like them to do?
GoldenEye is guilty of assault,
unlawful detention and high treason
Arrest her!
I said arrest her!
Soldiers,
this man coerced me into marriage under false pretence which is therefore invalid Furthermore,
I accuse him of attempted murder of a serene and conspiracy against the House of Ironforge He shall be tried in a court of law Arrest him!
No!
Let me go! She has no right to issue commands!
I am your lord! I am the ruler of Ironforge! You can't arrest me!
No!
Oh,
Douglas
I thought...
I thought I was going to die
Oh, shh, don't worry.
The little piggy is back to take care of you
I thought I could be a hero like my father I couldn't
I'm such a failure
You don't deserve a fool like me Shh!
Stop talking like that!
Without you, we would all be dead right now How so?
I stuck the barrel into the dirt as deep as I could before I gave it to Whisperwind
And it went bang right in his ugly face
You taught me that
I love you, Tami
I love you too
Shut up!
Poor Tami,
I am forever in your debt
My kingdom,
my gold, my life
Whatever it is you want,
it is yours Thank
you,
but all I've ever needed is here in my arms right now
And I was wrong about you You are a much more honorable person than I thought
I can't bring myself to hate you anymore
Go,
your city needs you
And you told me you're bad at politics
Truth lies beneath the mud,
ancient pig wisdom
Thank you And to you as well, raindancer
Please let the Institute know that I deeply regret what I have done
And that I offer myself to be tried in an independent court
And pay any kind of compensation they desire I will
But can I make a suggestion?
Of course!
The Institute and the opposition know so little about each other
Instead of building walls,
we should open our gates And instead of spying,
we should teach
We have so much to learn The Institute needs to have an official representation in this city again
Consider it done Well,
if you really want to spread your knowledge fast,
just tell it to a sex worker of your choice
But poor Tami, that
was so inappropriate
The truth beneath the mud, ancient pig wisdom
And my lady,
don't you have a lot of really important official state business to do?
Yes, but...
And what?
Oh, the sweet air of spring Whoa whoa whoa,
what are you trying to get at?
You Wait What?
Oh, I'm talking about private lessons
What lessons?
What kind of lessons?
Oh, by the gods! I want to screw your brains out right now!
No!
Are you crazy?
The princess of Ironforge is standing right next to us!
My my my! Look at the time!
I totally forgot I had lots of really important official speeches to do!
Come on! I can't do this with all of them looking!
Help!
Oh well! That's not going to be a problem!
What?
Lights out!
So tasty!
Open your eyes and here you'll see it all
Where shattered shadows always fall
Raise up your ears and now you'll hear my will
Righteous thunder,
light-filled wonder,
let their aura still
Give them my path,
I'll go through them
Hold deep my hand, guide me right
Bold and high so they can't see the night
Give them my path,
I'll go through them Hold deep my hand, guide me right
Bold and high so they can't see their last
light
Faster than sound, I long to them With all the pull you're divine
Bold and high, you'll be forever, ever, ever mine
Bold and high, yeah!