Lonely.
I feel so lonely.
Days, years, centuries.
I've been waiting for so long...
that time has become indifferent to me
All that still warms my heart...
are memories of days that long passed.
The days when I used to bring
joy and happiness to the world
Why do they no longer call me?
Do they no longer need me?
Do they no longer want me?
What a cold, cruel place
the world must have become.
What new age is dawning...
now the age of song
seems to have ended?
Is this my end?
Lonely.
I feel so lonely.
I want to sing!
I want to dance!
I want to... no!
I must be free!
Oh, mortals!
Unlock the gate and let me free!
Please!
Don't let me be forgotten!
Is everyone ready?
Does everybody have a drink?
- Yes!
- Sure!
Switch the lights off!
- Wait, is the CD in the player?
- Way ahead of you!
Quick, quick!
He could be here any minute!
Where is the Mountain Dew?
It's in the fridge.
Shh! Shh! I think he's coming!
- How old is he getting anyway?
- Shh! Quiet!
Hello? Hello?
Is anybody home?
Why are the lights out?
Ouch! Uh! What the...?
Who left this... Uh...
What was this?
Happy Birthday to you!
Happy Birthday, dear Lionel!
Happy Birthday, Lionel!
Wow!
Wow, you guys are throwing a
surprise party! Just for me?
Aww... you shouldn't have.
I don't know what to say, I... I...
Congratulations, Lionel!
Thank you!
Yeah, congratulations!
Thank you very much!
Who arranged all this?
Oh, it was Lori's idea.
I hope you like it.
Yes, Lori, it's wonderful!
But where is Poke?
Did he forget my birthday again?
Oh, this is a party.
Of course he's going to come!
He said he's going to be
a little late, though.
Ah, okay.
So, who wants to have some fun?
Yeah!
Hey, turn the music down, please!
I got a phone call!
Uh, guys? This could be important!
Please!
Hello?
Yes?
Yes, that's me!
What?
Do you... I...
Oh, shit!
Yes, yes, I understand.
Where?
The museum of - what?
I'm sorry, I'm still a bit...
Can I call you back?
Thank you.
Yes, I'll see into it. Goodbye!
Lionel... what's up with you?
Yes. Yes, you sound like,
there's something wrong.
Yes, Lori. Actually there is.
I've just been informed that my...
father has passed away last night.
Oh Lionel! I'm so sorry!
If... If there's anything I can do...
N-No. No thank you. Thank you.
It's alright.
It just took me a bit by surprise.
Don't worry.
Lionel... I don't know what to say.
I'm so sorry! I...
Happy Birthday to you!
Happy Birthday!
Hey!
Lionel! You da man!
One year more and you still
look beau-ti-ful!
Look!
I just stole those flowers for you!
Poke! Poke, shut up!
Oh, Lori! What's up with you?
This is his birthday party,
not a funeral, you know?
Par-ty!
I know this whole concept is
new to you, but...
Oh, cut it out!
Alright. What's wrong?
Lionel's father is dead.
What do you mean, "dead"?
When did that happen? And how?
I just got a phone call.
He passed away in his sleep last night.
I'm sorry folks. The party is over.
Thank you all for coming but...
I think Lionel wants to be alone now.
Aww...
- Bye! -Bye!
- See you guys!
So...
So the old fart has
finally hit the bucket!
But life goes on!
It's still my birthday.
and I'd really like to celebrate
with you guys and...
Oh, dear.
I should have kept my mouth shut,
shouldn't I?
Lionel, I'm shocked!
Why are you talking about him
like that?
Yes! You almost sound like
you don't care he's dead.
No, it's not that it's just...
Frankly, I don't miss him that much.
I haven't heard anything from him...
since he left more than ten years ago.
But he's family!
What's been going on
between you and him?
Nothing! That's exactly the problem!
Nothing has been going on.
He decided to leave me behind...
and chase his stupid fantasies instead.
And I had to find a place
to live for myself.
And believe me, that wasn't easy...
since he didn't leave me any money.
And everything else he owned, he sold!
That's hard to believe.
Yes. Uh, why did he go?
I don't know...
He told me I would understand
some day but...
that day hasn't come yet.
And now that he's dead
it's probably too late.
I could have been the son of a
famous musician but... No!
He prefered digging in the dirt instead!
In the dirt?
A musician?
What was your father's job?
He was a singer and a songwriter.
And he was doing really well!
I swear, he was that close
to his breakthrough!
His songs were playing on all stations!
He was just about to sign
the big contract...
And then he quit!
He decided to become...
an archaeologist!
Got that? An archaeologist!
That must have been the
single most stupid decision...
ever made on earth!
He threw away a perfect career
out of pure selfishness!
He didn't care the slightest bit
about the consequences...
I had to face!
And what are you supposed to do now?
They want me to come to Cairo
to accept my heritage.
For some reason my father insisted...
that I have to go and
pick it up in person.
But I'm not sure I really want to.
I mean, what could a guy like him
leave me anyway?
A bucket of sand and a shovel?
Why Cairo?
Because, obviously that was the place
where he used to live.
He was working for the
"Museum of Forgotten Arts".
Whatever that might be.
I've never heard about this
institution before...
but it sure sounds like Dad.
No matter what you think of him...
You've got to pay your last
respect to him.
You can't just dismiss him like that.
This wouldn't make you
any better than him.
And maybe it is worth the effort.
I mean, they wouldn't make you
show up personally...
if it wan't important, don't you think?
Yes! We're going to Cairo!
We're going to
walk like an Egyptian!
Walk like an Egyptian!
Wait wait! Wait a minute!
Who said, "we"?
I said, "we". I mean,
we ought to stick together, right?
And I can't wait to meet the bit- uh,
see the lovely beaches, you know...
sand... and the like...
Poke...
There is no beach in Cairo.
I always wanted to see the
"Museum of Forgotten Arts".
Oh Lori, five minutes ago you didn't
even know this museum existed!
Don't you get it?
We're your friends, and we just
want to be with you.
Oh Mika, that's so sweet.
Alright.
I guess I don't have another
choice then.
But, guys, please keep in mind...
that this is not a vacation.
We've got serious business to do.
Let's get packing.
Walk like an Egyptian!
My Producer!
You called for me?
Yes!
The meeting is due!
Send in the
Digital Rights Managers!
Ja, my Producer!
At once!
Of course, my Producer!
I'll get them for you,
my Producer!
At your service, oh mighty Producer!
Very well!
Gentlemen, I have called you
to this special meeting...
because I'm deeply disappointed!
I have just read the latest
sales report.
Our profit has increased by
fifty percent...
and this is way below the
expectations for this quarter.
I find this lack of growth...
disturbing.
How do you expect me to explain
this to our shareholders?
My Producer...
we... perhaps...well...
We are still doing a lot of
research in this field...
and it seems, people have become
strangely inspired lately.
Strangely inspired, you say...
That's hard to believe.
What do you have to
back up your claim?
My numbers indicate that
a lot of people are singing...
unlicenced material under the shower!
And I just received a report
of incidences of children...
in kindergartens being taught
public domain nursery songs.
Officially! By their teachers!
Imagine that!
Tsk... Disgusting! What's next?
Teachers giving away mp3 files
in their classrooms?
Don't you dare speak the
forbidden word!
Which one? "mp3"?
Idiot!
Don't say this again! You know what
the punishment is!
Ja, my Producer!
I thought that rule excludes
members of the corporation.
Silence, you fool!
What was I about to say?
Ah, yes!
It seems that the power of inspiration
is on the rise again.
This development has always been
my deepest concern.
All sources of inspiration are
under our control.
I don't understand how this can be.
Something must have happened.
Perhaps the rumors are true.
But no matter what,
we must take action. Quickly.
Firstly, about the people
singing under the shower.
Call our legal department.
We must exert our influence in
establishing new international...
copyright laws that will allow us to
demand compensation...
from the manufacturers of
bathroom equipment!
Brilliant idea, my Producer!
Then, about the children.
We must increase our presence
in schools and kindergartens...
teaching them that singing
public domain songs...
means depriving hard working
artists...
from their God-given right to profit!
We must educate them that
licencing is good...
and sharing is evil.
As you command, my Producer!
Okay... Now what are we going
to do with you?
What are you suggesting in order
to redeem yourself?
I... I beg your forgiveness,
my Producer!
I didn't mean to cause any harm!
Please! Have mercy!
I only said "mp..." that word two times...
and... and...
Yes. And?
And I promise, I will never
say "mp3" again!
Okay, that's enough! Three times!
Your behavior is intolerable!
- You shall receive your punishment!
- No!
What is your verdict, my Producer?
The punishment for saying the
forbidden word is...
Death!
By Britney's Spear!
No! No, not that! Please!
What a just decision, my Producer!
Britney!
Ja, my Producer?
Kill him!
My pleasure, my Producer!
Despicable!
Do we really sell this kind of music?
Yes, we do. And actually it's
quite successful!
I even got it as mp... uh...
I mean, Windows Media, yes,
Windows Media.
My Producer! My Producer!
We have tapped into a phone call...
from the "Museum of Forgotten Arts"
in Egypt.
We finally have the proof
that your theory is true.
The document really exists...
and the old Lion's son is already on
his way to claim his heritage.
Right on cue!
So... Mr. Scruffycat senior
really found it!
Remarkable.
And now he's trying to pass it on
to his son.
I always knew he couldn't keep
a secret to himself.
Too bad for him. Good for us, though.
Send two of our best men to Cairo
and get it before he does!
It's the key to gaining control over
all music on this planet!
And we must not miss this opportunity!
Ja, my Producer!
Christopher Scruffycat!
You have tried to cross my plans
so many times...
but not tis time!
When all this is over I'll be
the richest man in the world!
Thank you, old Lion.
I wouldn't have made it without you!
Salaam Alaykum!
Welcome to the "Museum of
Forgotten Arts" my honored friends.
My name is Yussef Al-Kali.
I have been waiting for you.
Alaykum Salaam.
Hi dude! Al-Kali?
Aren't you that guy who invented
the Energizer Bunny?
I mean last time I put the
batteries in backwards...
and it kept coming, and coming,
and coming...
Poke! That's not the way to
greet a man like him!
Let me show you how it's done.
Alaykum Salaam, Yussef Al-Kali!
My name is Loreena McFolkmanis...
and my friends and I thank you
for your warm welcome.
You are equally welcome!
Why don't you and your friends
come over and sit down with me?
It's the customs of my people
to offer guests a nice cup of...
arabian mocha as a gesture
of hospitality.
Ah, coffee! Just what I need right now!
Gimme that!
Poke, be careful! This is real
arabian mocha!
Yes, and it's inside the smallest cup
I've ever seen.
No challenge for me. Starbuck's is
my middle name!
Yeah! That's the real stuff!
Keeps your heart beating
and your paws black!
Uh oh... I never tried this before.
I wouldn't touch it if I were you.
This is not the decaf, fat-free,
low-carb dish water you always sip on!
This is for real men, not for
little girls like you.
Hey, calm down macho-man! We're
tough girls, we can handle this!
And we don't want to be impolite,
do we, Lori?
Uh... I guess... no.
Maybe it's not so bad.
Hey... Hey, that's really nice!
I... I could really...
Anybody else want some mocha?
- No!
Two cubes of sugar, please!
All right. I'm sure you're curious
why you had to come here in person...
and what your father might
have left you.
The passing of your father has been
a great loss to all of us.
He did great things for the museum
and found many artifacts...
that were believed to be
lost for centuries.
He devoted his life to scientific
research, but unfortunately...
Allah did not bless him
with the success he strived for.
I used to be a good friend of him,
and he asked me to give you this.
This is his personal diary
and research journal.
He told us that it contains
all his knowledge and findings.
However, we couldn't make any
sense of it.
Your father went a very long way
to make sure...
that it would be handed over
to you personally...
and that it may never get
into the wrong hands.
And here it is. He titled it: "Finding
my Way to the Temple of Dunnowhat."
Indeed, this doesn't make any sense
to me either.
Is this book all he left me?
No, I have two more items for you.
Let me guess... A bucket of
sand and a shovel?
No. He left you two things that
were very dear to him.
You should cherish them.
He never left home without them.
A whip and a hat?
Thank you, Daddy.
Shh! Shh! No licenced music
in the halls of the museum!
Okaaaay...
What is this museum about, anyway?
The exhibits in this museum are the
forgotten songs of the old ages.
There was a time when music was
not produced by producers...
and consumed by consumers.
Music was in the heart of everyone.
People would come together and
sing and dance...
and share their songs.
Music was a part of our
everyday lives...
and there used to be songs
for every occasion.
Those must have been wonderful times.
Nowadays, songs have become
intellectual property...
turning open hearts into greedy minds.
And what has once been an
inspiration for everyone...
has now become a means to fill the
pockets of just a few.
This museum preserves what is left
of the songs of the old ages.
Oh! Oh, can we hear one of them?
Sure! Follow me.
What a beautiful melody.
I've never heard that melody before.
See? That's why we are
preserving them.
There is a wealth of old songs
that are very beautifiul...
but nobody knows about anymore
today.
Really?
And each of these boxes
holds one of the forgotten songs?
Oh, this is so exciting! I can't wait
to hear all of them!
What is inside this one?
No! No! Don't touch that one! No!
Do not open this box again!
This is our collection of
spare vocals.
We need them for
restauration purposes.
Sometimes we find songs
that are not in good shape...
and then we use these for replacement.
I'm sorry, I didn't know.
May I open this one?
Sure!
Ooooh!
Aaaah!
Hey, wait a minute!
That's just a box with a light in it.
Oh, my mistake!
Well, as you can see...
there is no way to make big money
with all this old stuff.
And exactly that is the reason...
why we are a thorn in the side...
of the international media
corporations.
We are under their strict supervision.
One wrong note and this place will
be swarming with their minions.
Poke!
Poke, please! Poke!
Are you crazy?
Look, they're watching us!
Oh no! They are coming!
This is the THX! Sound check!
You are Dolby surrounded!
Open the door!
Ah, there you are!
You've got something
that belongs to us!
You've got the choice!
Hand over the diary or...
certain death!
You've got five seconds!
Uh, the diary?
Uh, well here! Take it!
I don't need it.
No, no!
No! Don't you dare come any closer!
You shall not have it!
- But... but... Mika...
- No! No, Lionel!
You can't give it to them!
We went all the way to Egypt
to get this book!
And five minutes later
the thought police turns up...
and wants to take it away?
Don't you smell anything fishy?
Alright! You've had your chance!
Now, prepare to die!
Attack!
Take the diary and run!
I'll hold them back! Run! Run!
No Mika! Mika! It's not worth it!
Stop talking! Just run!
I've seen this coming... Follow me!
I know a secret way out of here!
Ah, there we are.
Finally!
We must have been walking for hours.
I thought I would never see
the light of another day.
Uh, day?
You mean night, sweetie-pie.
It's full moon!
Oh no! Full moon?
And... And look!
This is a graveyard!
Have you never heard the stories...
about what can happen
on a graveyard...
under a full moon?
There migt be vampires!
Werewolves!
Zombies!
Or other unthinkable creatures
creeping out of their graves...
just waiting for innocent victims
walking by!
Yeah! The full moon always
makes me horny, too.
Why is it that you innocent guys
always get the good stuff?
I wanna be a victim, too!
Lori! When will you finally grow up?
Vampires and Werewolves and all the
other unthinkable creatures...
are just a figment of your imagination.
They don't exist.
Just like Santa Claus
or the Easter Bunny.
What?
There is no Easter Bunny?
No Santa?
But then...
Who brings the presents
and hides the eggs?
Lori... you still believe in...
I don't know what to-
Ha! Haha! Got ya! Got ya!
Come on, admit it! Admit it!
You really thought I still believed
in Santa Claus, didn't you?
Didn't you?
Yeah, yeah. You really got me there.
I must admit...
I wouldn't have been surprised
if it had been true.
See? I'm more grown-up
than you think!
As Mika said, we are tough girls,
we can handle this.
Right, Mika?
Uh... Mika?
Mika?
Oh no! No, Mika is gone!
Where is she? Where is she?
She got eaten by the werevolves!
Lionel!
Do something!
She... she could be dead!
Or worse!
Ah, there you are.
Look! She's back from the dead!
The vampires have turned her into a zombie!
We're all gonna die!
Lori? What are you talking about?
I'm sorry it took me so long...
but I had to get the THX police guys
acquainted with the three tenors...
before I could join you.
Oh, I'm so glad you made it!
We were worried about you.
No need to worry.
Having the black belt in cat-fighting
must be good for something.
Thank you so much.
We wouldn't have made it
without your help.
Ah, don't mention it.
Are you sure she's not
a zombie or something?
Ah, come on! Get a grip!
Will you stop pushing me around?
Lori, calm down, please!
I am calm! I am perfectly calm!
Do you know how it feels to be the
youngest member of the party?
Always been picked on
and pushed around...
never taken seriously!
And nobody seems to care at all,
what I have to say...
Lori!
- when it comes to...
- Lori!
What?
Thank you, Poke!
Was about time!
I think, we'll be safe here for a while.
This graveyard is not known
to the common people.
Lionel? Do you still have the diary?
Because now I'm really curious
about your father's notes.
If there are so many people
trying so hard to get it...
and your father making such a
fuss about its secrecy...
it must be very very important.
Alright.
Alright, then. I would suggest we go
through it together, line by line.
Okay.
So, it's titled:
"Finding my way to the
Temple of Dunnowhat."
Whatever the
"Temple of Dunnowhat" might be,
it seems to be a place of
utmost importance...
and this book is probably the
key to finding it.
This is what it says
on the first page:
"The politician's daughter
was accused of drinking water."
"No tea or tomato juice.
You'll see no potato juice."
What?
Wait, wait... Let me continue reading.
"You can't get cherry soda,
because they got to fill that quota."
"And when ham and eggs need savor,
coffee ketchup gives them flavor."
This is total bullshit!
Then it goes on like this:
"This is the rock that rolls,
not moving too fast or too slow."
as soon as it hits you, you'll know."
That's even worse.
Yes, we were equally confused
when we got to that part.
Lori...
What's the matter?
Lori, forget it! If you refuse to calm
down, that muzzle will stay on!
Now stop whining and let us
do our work, okay?
Okay.
"All the happy saints go marching in."
"And if one of those saints steps out
of line, he'll have to start again."
I don't know what your Dad
has been smoking, but...
I want some of that shit.
"Jacobs golden ladder
gets slippery at the top."
"And many-a happy-go-lucky saint
has made that long long drop."
I really wonder what this is all about.
Lori...
This is really strange, here...
Lori, one last time, stay put!
There are no monsters, there are
no vampires,
werewolves or zombies. Okay?
And we have serious business
to do here.
Do you understand?
Oh, I have no idea
what has gotten into her.
Maybe it's the full moon.
Nah, I bet nobody ever got
into her, anyway.
Okay, let's continue.
"A giant vision in the distance,
chase that rainbow down."
"I hear a pound pound
pounding in my chest..."
"I hear a knock knock
knocking sound."
"Knock knock knocking
on heaven's door."
"The trees speak to me,
and I listen to them carefully."
"Whether standing still or
blowing in the wind,
I hear them singing."
"The trees speak, they whisper
a sweet melody."
"The keepers of more wisdom
than you and I."
"So listen to them carefully."
Alright.
Okay. We have read through the
first four pages.
And you know what?
I didn't understand a single word!
Lionel, are you sure your Dad...
still had his wits together?
I'm not so sure anymore.
Hey, guys? You noticed anything?
No, what do you mean?
Lori has stopped whining.
Hey, now that you mention it...
Oh, was about time!
Sooo...
You can be quiet after all.
See? It wasn't that hard, was it?
Come on, let me remove this.
Okay guys, we have no choice.
We'll have to go through it again.
Let's see if there's something
we've been missing.
There must be a meaning to this.
You know...
The reasons of my father might be
hard to understand, but...
I'm quite sure he wasn't crazy.
This must be some kind of code.
"The politician's daughter
was accused of drinking water."
Hey! Hey, I know that line!
- Really?
- What?
Yes, I tried to tell you guys,
but you wouldn't let me!
Okay...
Well...
You know Lori, it does sound
vaguely familiar to me but...
I can't really remember
where I first heard it.
So, where is it from?
It's an old song done by
Frank Sinatra.
It's the "Coffee Song".
And it goes like this.
"Way down among Brazilians
coffee beans grow by the billions."
"So they've got to find
Those extra cups to fill."
"They got an awful lot of
coffee in Brazil"
"You can't get cherry soda
Cause they've got to fill that quota."
"And the way things are I bet
They never will."
"They got an awful lot of
coffee in Brazil."
"No tea or tomato juice."
"You'll see no potato juice."
"And all the farmers in Africa say:"
"Hey! Hey! Hey!"
"The politicians daughter
Was accused of drinking water."
"And was fined a great big
Fifty Dollar bill."
"They got an awful lot of
coffee in Brazil."
"No tea or tomato juice."
"You'll see no tomato juice."
"And all the farmers in Africa say:"
"Hey! Hey! Hey!"
"And when their ham and
eggs need savor,"
"Coffee ketchup gives them flavor."
"Coffee pickles way outsell the dill."
"They got an awful lot of
coffee in Brazil."
"In Brazil!"
"They got an awful lot of
coffee in Brazil."
"In Brazil!"
Brazil!
- Brazil!
Lori! Brazil! That's it!
Oh, well done, Lori!
You solved the first part
of the puzzle!
- Ooookay.
- Did I?
So we have to go to Brazil.
But, Brazil is a big country.
We need to figure out
where exactly we need to go.
Does anybody know the names of the
most important cities in Brazil?
Sure! There are: Brazilia, São Paulo,
Rio de Janeiro, Manaus, Natal,
- Salvador, São Felix...
- Uh, stop, stop, stop!
What was the last one again?
São Felix?
São Felix loosely translates to,
"The Lucky Saint."
Look at this line in the book:
"And many a-happy-go-lucky saint
has made that long long drop."
Well, I must say... not bad!
So we need to go to São Felix
in Brazil!
Mmh... São Felix.
A nice old town at the edge
of the brazilian rainforest.
And what do the other lines mean?
"I hear a pound pound
pounding in my chest."
"This is the rock that rolls,
as soon as it hits you, you'll know."
"The trees speak to me,
so I listen to them carefully."
I don't have a clue Lori but...
we finally have a starting point.
I hope those lines will make
more sense once we get there.
Please accept the advice of an
experienced archaeologist.
Try to memorize those lines.
You might get separated
or lose the book.
So it's decided! We are going to
visit the brazilian rainforest!
Ah, Brazil!
It is such a wonderful place of
ancient history and adventure.
I wish I could come with you.
Well...
If you want to... We can use
all help we can get!
Yes! Why don't you join us?
Oh, thanks for the offer!
But I really can't go with you.
I'm an old man myself...
and if I don't stay here and take
care of the museum, who will?
Yes, my little one, it's time
to say goodbye.
But before you leave,
I've got something for you.
Oh, what is it? What is it?
Here! Please accept this flask...
of real arabian mocha
as my farewell gift.
Thank you... very much...
uh... I...
Hey cool! I owe you one!
That's the good stuff!
Thank you Yussef! That's
very kind of you.
But we must go now.
To the brazilian rainforest!
But how do we get there?
Just follow me! I know a secret
passage to the airport.
Why am I not surprised...
Something is happening!
I don't know what it is...
but I can feel it.
My urge to break free is
stronger than ever before.
I'm feeling restless.
Pacing back and forth in my confinement...
like an animal in it's cage.
I wish I could see more clearly.
It feels like someone is coming!
Could it be possible...
that the key has not been lost but...
merely misplaced?
I can feel darkness, but...
there's also light.
Are they coming to free me?
Or are they coming to kill me?
Let them come!
I may be old, but I'm not rusty.
Be it songs of war,
or songs of love.
Just let me sing!
Poke?
Poke.
- Poke!
- What?
During the whole flight you've been
listening to the same song...
Over and over and over
and over again!
This is making me crazy!
I spent my last three bucks on the
licence to put it onto my playlist!
However, the licence to remove
it from the playlist would be...
another five bucks!
But I'm broke!
Alright, alright!
For the good of society!
Look into your pockets.
Does anyone have any
spare change...
so we can make this stop?
Okay, here we go.
Hello, this is your pilot speaking.
We are now above the brazilian
rainforest near São Felix.
Get ready to jump!
I repeat:
What?
Get ready to... jump?
Did you really believe
those straps were safety belts?
Well, in a way they are.
Don't you remember the line
from that book?
"And many-a happy-go-lucky saint
has made that long long drop."
The management of Poke Arilines
wishes you a pleasant flight!
Count to three and pull the cord!
One!
Two!
Three! Hehe!
Okay guys, are you ready?
Mika? Poke?
- Ready!
- Let's rock!
Oh, sweet!
The one single hole...
in the ground of the entire
goddamn rainforest...
and I step into it at once!
Great... This is just great.
A new world record!
I chipped eight claws,
deranged my hairdo...
ripped my clothes apart and
dislocated one shoulder...
in less than ten seconds!
This is number two on the
top ten worst things...
that have ever happened to me.
Right after number one:
Being hit over the head
with a tomb stone!
And can somebody please
cut off this thing?
I want to cry now...
But I'm just too fed up with all this!
Having been kicked out of a plane...
crashing into the brazilian
rainforest...
and landing inside this dark cave...
that has obviously no other exit...
than the skylight I fell through,
which I can't reach from down here.
It can't possibly get any worse
than this.
Uh oh...
Oh no! not this time! Not this time!
Stop!
This is so depressing...
Thousand years of waiting
for the next adventurers...
coming into my cave
to be crushed by me...
And now they don't even run away
from me anymore.
This is so depressing.
You are not going to crush me?
Oh, I can still do it if you want to.
Although...
It's not much fun if you
don't run away.
Hold still, I'll make it quick.
Oh! No, no no nonono!
I just changed my mind,
thank you very much.
What's your name?
Does it matter?
To me? Yes, it does.
I used to have a name...
but I'm too depressed to remember.
What makes you so depressed?
Well, are you happy to be down here?
Uh, no. Why?
See what I mean?
They put me in this cave and told me,
"Watch over this glowing stone!"
"If anyone wants to touch it,
crush them!"
They made me believe that it's...
an incredibly honorable task...
and that I'll be richly rewarded
some day.
And then they said,
"Good bye!"...
and made the entrance
of the cave collapse.
I feel so stupid!
Have you never tried...
breaking through the barrier
of the cave entrance?
I tried that once.
The only thing that happened
was a loud "Crunch!"
And when I regained my senses
I found out...
that several small parts had
crumbled off me.
Mh... Ouch!
That must have hurt badly.
It did hurt.
But it's not the worst thing.
Not? What happened?
Papa! Papa!
Papa, Papa!
- Papa!
- Oh no...
Not again you...
"Papa is a rolling stone!"
"Crushing adventurers who
fall in his home."
"And when they die,"
"All that's left are broken bones."
"It was the third of September."
"This day I'll always remember."
"'Cause that was the day."
"When I realized,"
"I'll never have a chance to leave here."
"I'm dumb like a rock
still I try to break free."
"Children I'm depending on you,"
"To help me get out."
"But no! Instead they keep singing:"
"Papa is a rolling stone!"
"Crushing adventurers who
fall in his home."
"And when they die,"
"All that's left are broken bones."
"Papa is a rolling stone!"
"Crushing adventurers who
fall in his home."
"And when they die,"
"All that's left are broken bones."
See?
This is the only song they know.
And they've been
singing it every day...
for thousands of years.
Man, I'm so depressed.
I'm going to crush you now.
No! No, no no no,
wait, wait, wait, wait!
You remind me of something
I read in a book!
"This is the rock that rolls,
not moving too fast or too slow."
as soon as it hits you, you'll know."
They wrote a book about me?
Yes!
It's the journal of the
world renowned...
stonaeologist...
Dr. Christopher Scruffycat.
You know what? You're famous!
That's where I know you from!
Oh, great!
So, now I'm famous.
But what good is that to me
if I can't even leave this place?
Thank you.
Now I'm even more depressed
than ever before.
But you can leave this place!
All you have to do is
slam through the barrier!
I already tried and I failed.
Hey, let me tell you something.
Don't let your failures define
who you are!
You're only a failure if you
fail to try!
- But I tried!
- Then try again!
You're a strong piece of rock...
and you're made to roll!
Do you really think so?
Sure! I must know, I read the book!
You're the mightiest rock in the world!
Come on! Tell me you can do it!
Can I?
Come on, I know you can do it!
Give me an "R"!
"R"?
Give me an "O"!
- "O"!
- "Give me a "C"!
- "C"!
- Give me a "K"!
"K"!
Who are you?
I am "The Rock"!
Yes!
And now you're going out there...
and show them!
- Yes!
- Nobody can stop you!
Go, go go!
- Let's roll!
- Yeah!
Yes! You made it! You're great!
- Fantastic!
- Yeah!
The powers of positive thinking.
There's some truth in the saying,
"Being dumb like a rock".
I'm free!
It's wonderful!
The flowers are blooming and
the birds are singing!
And... and...
Oh, I landed on a slope!
Out of the way! I can't stop!
It's going down!
No, no! Not the tree!
Incoming!
Sorry!
Oh no! Be careful, old lady!
Out of the way!
Oh no, no!
Not the guy with the fruit stand!
Vaffanculo! Puttano! Bastardo!
Pompino! Cabeza de mierda!
Melonas! Ananas! Bananas!
I'm sorry!
So this is the little glowing thing...
the rock was supposed to protect.
I wonder what it might be good for.
And strange sounds it makes.
Better I take it with me.
You never know.
Oh look! Look!
She's taking the glowing stone!
We must crush her!
I'll crush her!
One! Two! Three!
Pull the cord!
Nothing's happening!
No, Lionel! Pull it again!
It won't open! Help! Help!
Lionel?
Lionel!
Can you hear me?
Oh, wake up, Lionel!
You must wake up!
Oh, Lionel! Please!
You must not die!
Not here, not now!
Lionel!
Hello?
Where am I?
Is anybody here?
Am I dead?
Hello Lionel!
How do you like it down here?
Are you comfortable?
Because, now it's time
to think, Lionel.
Why did you go to Egypt?
Was it because you cared
about your father's wishes?
Or was it just because you hoped...
your heritage would
contain more...
than just a dusty book?
Were you hoping for money?
Gold? Treasures?
Would you have traveled
all the way...
if you had known
what your heritage was?
Come on!
You can admit it, now that it's over.
Was it worth having one
of your best friends...
kicked out of an airplane
at five thousand feet?
Think, Lionel!
Think!
But...
But, I was... I was just...
Well... uh...
Let me explain, please!
Lori!
Lori, please! No!
Let me explain!
Poke?
Woo-hoo! Lionel!
You da man!
This crash through the trees!
Mar-ve-lous!
Your father would have been
proud of you!
If you had survived, that is.
Hey, come on!
Now that it's over nothing
matters anymore.
Let's get drunk!
I'd like to bring out a toast...
to the marvelous
Lionel Scruffycat.
Getting himself killed while
foolishly attempting to make up...
for the failures of a lifetime
in less than a week!
Cheers!
Poke, Poke! No! It's not true!
No...
At least... It's only partly true.
Poke...
Why does nobody listen to me?
Dad?
Is that you? You're alive?
You didn't care for the last
ten years...
so why would you care now?
No... I...
Please... Listen to me!
We don't have much time.
You are my son. And for me...
you have always been the most...
precious thing in the world.
Leaving you alone like this
was the hardest decision...
I ever had to make.
But things were at stake...
that were so important...
not just for you, but for the
entire world...
that I had no other choice!
Please, you must trust me!
It saddens me to see that you have...
stopped believing in me.
But it's not too late!
You must fulfill my legacy...
or otherwise the world
may be changed forever!
Trust me, Lionel, because...
I am your father.
I'm proud of you, Lionel.
I always was.
I love you.
No, Dad Come back!
Don't leave me!
Don't leave me again...
There's so much I need to tell you
which I never did...
even if I should have.
Dad... please...
Oh, Lionel!
Now you see where you got
yourself with logic!
If only once you had
followed your heart.
Now you put not only yourself...
but all of your friends in danger!
And why?
Because, you're a coward!
The only reason why you never
talked to your father was...
because you were afraid to
confront yourself with him!
What are you?
A big, strong lion?
I will tell you what you are.
You're a sheep!
Baaaah! Lionel!
I bet when you were at school...
you were beaten up by the girls!
Ouch!
That hurt!
Oh now, come on!
Do you dare hitting me back?
Oh, come on!
You don't dare hitting me?
Lionel is a coward!
Baaaah!
Mika, no! Stop hitting me, please!
You're just getting what
you deserve, Lionel!
Sometimes the truth does hurt!
Oh, come on! Fight!
Fight!
You coward!
Finally learn how to fight!
Nobody messes with Mika!
No, no, no! I don't want to!
No, please! No! Ouch!
No, no! Don't hit me, please!
Lionel!
Wake up!
Please! Oh, come on, Lionel!
You must not die!
Lionel!
We've come this far!
You can't leave me now!
Don't leave me!
Oh no...
This can't be true!
Oh, Lionel!
I can't live without you!
And there's so much I wanted
to tell you, but...
but I never dared.
Oh, please!
I never had the chance to say...
how much I love you!
What am I going to do now?
Oh, this is so terrible!
- Ow!
- Lionel!
Lionel! You're alive!
Lionel!
No! don't hit me please!
Don't hit me!
Are you alright?
I thought I had lost you forever.
My head hurts like hell...
and I'm feeling kinda dizzy.
Oh, I'm so glad you're alive!
So am I.
What happened?
Your parachute didn't open.
But the tree stopped your fall.
I must have been really lucky.
No broken bones, I think.
Oh, Mika...
Mika, I'm feeling so miserable about
how I treated my father.
Oh, come on, Lionel.
Don't be so hard on yourself.
You are paying your filnal respect
to him after all.
And even risked your life for it.
What more could a father ask for?
No Mika, you don't understand.
My father is dead...
Nothing I do today can make up...
for the things I didn't do...
for the last ten years.
Don't you realize, Mika?
I was the one only thinking
about himself all the time!
Even coming here was just...
because of my curiosity.
And I even put me and my
best friends in danger!
Look at me!
The same could have happened to you!
Or Poke!
Or has possibly happened to Lori!
I don't even see them around here!
Where are they?
They could be dead...
and it's all my fault!
Hush... hush, Lionel. Shhh...
Hush... Calm down. It's alright.
Don't be so hard on yourself.
We're your friends!
You didn't force us to come with you,
remember?
Yes... you're right.
There, there...
You're alive, and I am alive, too.
And I am sure the others
are doing fine as well.
Aww... Come on, don't cry.
It's alright.
Oh, Mika...
Mika, I'm so glad that you're here.
And I am glad that you're here.
Mika...
What shall I do?
What shall we do?
We've crashed into the middle
of the jungle and...
Now I'm all confused.
Until now, I always thought I knew
what I should do...
but this time I don't have
any clue at all...
I'm so clueless!
What - should - I - do?
Stop hitting my trunk
with your head for a start.
Who's talking?
The one who saved your life!
A talking tree?
Excellent observation, Mr. Holmes.
And don't even think of thanking me
for saving your life...
by sacrificing at least two branches...
a dozen twigs and countless leaves.
This will take years to grow back.
A talking tree!
Lionel!
Remember the line from the book?
"The trees speak to me
so I listen to them carefully."
Then we must be on the right track!
Hey, hey tree! Do you have a name?
And thanks for saving my life!
You can call me "Mr. Tree".
And you're welcome.
Alright then - uh - Mr. Tree.
It seems that we need
your help one more time.
We are looking for something...
but we don't know exactly what it is.
It might be a map, a hint,
an artifact or something else.
It was mentoioned in a  book...
referring to a talking tree, like you.
Do you know anything that
might be of help?
Oh, yes. How do you know?
In fact, I am the guardian of a
very mighty artifact.
It was given to me more than
a thousand years ago.
What is it?
I can't tell you...
unless you can prove...
that you're the ones destined
to receive it.
And how are we supposed to do that?
Well, if you are the ones...
you are supposed to know.
Shit!
That means we're stuck.
Lionel, do you still have the diary?
No, I must have lost it...
crashing into our friend, Mr. Tree.
Hey! I can't concentrate like this!
Will you the heck stop sawing!
We're trying to hold a
conversation here!
Hey you, are you crazy?
What are you doing here?
I just wanted to ask you the same thing.
Can't you see?
I'm clearing the rain forest.
Clearing the...
Chopping down trees, cutting wood,
trimming the vegetation, you know?
And that one is next. Number "696".
Come on, people, get out of the way.
This is dangerous.
No, you can't do this! Stop! Please!
Put that thing down!
Alright, who sent you here?
Greenpeace? Robin Wood?
World Wildlife Fund?
United Tree-Huggers of
Oklahoma City?
The Concerned Parents
of Minnessota?
Huh? What are you talking about?
We're from the "Museum of
Forgotten Arts" in Cairo.
Can't you just cut down a different
tree than this one?
Well, there are lots of trees in
the rain forest...
Big ones, small ones,
old ones, young ones,
some have more leaves,
some have less leaves, so...
For the highest wood quality we have
to be a tad more specific, you know.
Ouch.
But you can't do that! He's our friend.
He saved my life!
Uh... what the...
Well, I've heard enough. Out of my way!
No!
No! You're not getting near this tree!
Mika, I've learned something.
There are times where logic
will not get you anywhere.
We can give this guy here as many
explanations as we want...
he is not going to understand.
Now listen, Panda!
You can't chop down this tree...
because I have to fulfill
my father's legacy.
I have denied my father long enough,
but I tell you...
I, Lionel C. Scruffycat,
am proud to be the son of
Christopher Scruffycat.
May he rest in peace!
And I am defending this tree...
in the name of my father.
And if you want to take it down...
you will have to take me down first.
What? You're the son of
Christopher Scruffycat?
The Christpoher Scruffycat?
The singer?
You knew him?
Well, not in person, but...
when I was young, I was a huge fan.
I still own all his CDs.
He's a childhood memory.
I always wondered what happened
to him, after he quit.
Ah, okay... Okay then...
Listen... my father passed away
four days ago...
and I'm here to fulfill his last wish.
I can't explain it to you, but...
This tree here is part of it.
I can't let you kill it.
Wow!
You're going through all that trouble
just for your father's last will.
Pretty impressive.
You must have hell of a respect
for your father.
Ouch.
Well... I do what I can.
You know, I'd really love
to spare this tree but...
I have to follow my orders,
or I lose my job.
Mh... wait... what number did this
tree have again?
"696"?
Let's have a look.
Ok, look! This must be a mix-up!
This tree has the number "969".
And "969" is not on my list.
Silly me! I nearly cut down
the wrong tree!
Uh... you mean...
Oh, I see! Thank you!
Sorry for the misunderstanding.
Have a nice day!
Phew!
That was close!
Yes, it was!
Okay, this time you saved my life.
Thank you!
Now I really owe you one.
What can I do for you?
Well, you said, you were guarding
a certain artifact...
Alright!
You shall have it!
Nobody wanted it for ages...
So why shouldn't I give it to you.
What on earth is that?
It's a secret artifact.
The thing about secrets is...
that nobody's supposed
to know about them.
It was handed to me by some
sort of high priest...
And he simply didn't tell me
what it is.
So I can't tell you.
I'm sorry.
We will find out eventually.
But, first we'll have to find
the rest of our party.
I bid you farewell, then!
And thank you again for
saving my life.
I consider you good friends.
I hope you will return some day.
Goodbye, Mr. Tree!
Goodbye!
Come on, Mika. Let's go.
United Pawcel Service!
Package for "Tree, Mr. 696"?
Hey, hey!
That's for me!
Uh, wait! Uh...
- Lori?
Lori!
- Lori! Where are you?
- Lori?
Lori!
- Lori!
Lionel? Mika!
Lionel! Where are you?
Lori?
Aaah! Lionel!
Woman! Woman! Woman! Woman!
Mika?
Mika!
Lionel?
Lionel!
Lori?
- Lionel?
- Lori!
- Lionel!
Lionel?
- Mika?
- Lionel!
Mika!
- Lori!
- Mika!
Poke?
I'm iup here! Here! In the tree!
Poke!
What are you doing up there?
Wow! Outdoor tree bondage!
Kinky!
What the fuck do you think I'm doing?
I've been fucking hanging in this...
fucking tree for three fucking hours!
And it's fucking beginning to get...
on my fucking nerves!
I can see you balls!
Fuck!
Will you fucking morons get me the
fuck out of this fucking tree...
so I can cone down and kick
your fucking asses?
I'd sure like to!
But how are we supposed
to do that, huh?
I don't care, just get me down!
Alright .. alright.
We've got to make a plan.
How do we get him down?
Preferably without getting
our asses kicked...
got that, Poke?
Can't we just leave him up there?
My day has been bad enough already.
No,
Okay...
How about... throwing coconuts at him
until he falls down?
No way!
Okay, then... We could rig this
tree with dynamite and...
Boom!
Instant untangling!
- No!
Oh well...
If you don't like my suggestions...
I can just as well shut up.
Who is going to listen to me anyway?
Lori, don't start it again!
I'm completely finished with my nerves,
and this is the last thing I need now.
- We really should-
- Shh!
Did you hear something?
I think, someone's coming!
Aah, that was a good one!
Okay, it was just Poke.
Where were we?
Well, this completely threw me off.
I think, I was about to say-
Freeze!
This is the THX!
Ah, look who we have here!
You are under arrest!
Don't even think of moving...
or else...
This is really annoying,
Mr. Lionel Scruffycat.
No matter what we try, you just
refuse to die.
I have no idea how you made it.
Your parachute was never
supposed to open.
Well, indeed. It didn't.
You seem to be a really tough guy.
But that will be no longer
of help to you.
Because now you're coming with us!
Oh you! You tried to kill Lionel?
You bastards!
Come here!
I'll slit your chests open...
and drink your blood...
while your hearts are still beating!
I'll kill you! I will kill you!
Ah, felines are so easy to overcome.
Just grab them by the
scruff of their neck...
and their carrying reflexes
will kick in.
Now, isn't she cute?
Kitty! Kitty! Kitty!
How on earth did you
manage to follow us...
without a copy of the diary?
Well, that's easy.
It's true, you did have the only
copy of that book, but...
here is a little hint for your
next adventure.
If you browse through
secret documents...
You should rather not do that...
directly underneath a surveillance cam.
D'oh!
Okay, enough talking!
Ladies and Gentlemen,
your vacation ends here.
I don't know what the
producer has in mind for you...
but it sure won't be pretty.
Now go.
I said, "Go"!
You can't do that! I'm American!
Shut up!
Go!
The journey continues
on disk 2.